today and whatever you guys want to talk
about as well. Uh Texas Democrats
running around um trying to uh keep the
Republicans from gerrymandering Texas
and maybe helping out New York and
Illinois. Jerry for the Democrats.
>> Meanwhile, uh President Trump's firing
of the Bureau of Labor Statistics lady
is having major repercussions uh bigger
than we might have expected. We thought
this was kind of a chuckle on Friday,
but it's still going. It's still funny,
the chuckle. I maintain the chuckle. Um,
over in Gaza, uh, the Trump
administration's, uh, chief envoy, Steve
Whit, is pushing an all or nothing deal.
We'll explain what that means. MTG
dropping truth bombs. She says the GOP
hates women. Um, my favorite story of
the day, the New York Post is going
west, young man or old man. They
starting a California version of the
paper. We'll get into that. They smell
blood in the water. I think as the LA
Times six uh I'm so sad so sad about
that. Uh 15 might cost you 15 grand to
visit the United States or at least you
might have to post 15 grand and you
might get it back or you might not. Um
the main story of the day I think is
going to be this revelation that is not
being talked about anywhere else that
when you talk to Chad GPT
um that's indexed on Google. So that
means if you ask chat GPT, you know, my
wife is whatever. I'm thinking of like,
should I divorce her? Yes, she could
find that on Google. All of your friends
and co-workers could too. For real, it's
indexed on Google. And finally, um
there's some the CIA director is accu is
pushing this narrative that Hillary
Clinton came up with a scheme to uh
basically um set up Donald Trump as a
Russian pathy for Vladimir Putin. And
let me add something to that. Let me add
something to that last point.
>> In just the last hour, uh, the office of
the attorney general announced that
a grand jury already exists.
>> Oh, wow. And it is and it is hearing
testimony
aimed at prosecuting Hillary Clinton,
Jim Comey,
uh John Brennan, and uh what's Clapper's
first name? Clapper.
>> James.
>> James Clapper. Thank you. As part of the
whole Russia Gate uh hoax.
>> So,
>> would that make you Would that make you
sad, John? Would that make you sad?
Would you cry? I I promised myself I
wouldn't gloat. I I put something on
Facebook last week when when there were
these first these rumors that that this
was going to happen and people put laugh
emojis and they put, you know, angry
emojis and whatever and and a lot of
people made fun of me. I didn't even I
didn't even say anything. I just posted
the article and then in the comments
somebody said, "You don't really think
this is going to happen, do you?" And I
said, "Um, probably not. Not with
Hillary anyway, but I'm very hopeful
that John Brennan is prosecuted.
And
if I were John Brennan, I'd be in the
market for a for an A-list criminal
defense attorney right now.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Mr. Clapper has some answering to do as
well.
>> Indeed. Yes, he does.
>> And uh Yeah. So, I mean, yes, it's
partisan. Yes, it's political. It
wouldn't happen any other way. Doesn't
mean it's wrong. I always like to say
that. Um, yeah. You know, a lot of
Democrats, a lot of my friends, mo most
of whom are Democrats, don't see it that
way. John, which where should we talk?
Where should we start? Should we start
with that?
>> Let's start with Let's start with Texas.
>> All right, let's do Texas.
>> Because this is this is breaking and
it's it's not unprecedented. This has
happened before in the recent past.
>> That's right.
So, all the Democrats in the in the
Texas legislature have fled the state of
Texas,
>> uh, lest they be rounded up by the uh by
the legislative police or whoever the
police force is. And
>> Austin's capital police.
>> Yeah. the the Capitol police and dragged
to the floor um of the legislature and
forced to vote on this uh this
Republican plan to redraw the
congressional district boundaries. So,
if they leave Texas, they can't be
arrested and it's a civil arrest.
>> Well, let's not forget the reason
they're leaving Texas is to deny sure
that the Texas uh state house can't
conduct business because under
parliamentary procedure, which goes back
for centuries, uh you have to have a
quorum. You have to have a minimum
number of people in order to conduct
business.
>> That's right. Now, to the best of my
recollection, Ted, this happened in
Oregon a few years ago.
>> It happened in Texas, too.
>> And it happened in Texas, but not over
congressional uh boundaries. It was over
the
>> And um and in the end, one side's going
to have to give. I mean, if if you live
in Texas, you work in Texas, and you're
an elected representative in the Texas
legislature, you're probably going to
have to end up going back to Texas at
some point,
>> right?
>> But but you made a good point in the
intro, Ted, that both Well, not even
both. New York, Illinois, and
California, thank you, Marble,
all said, "Go ahead, Texas. go ahead and
redraw the boundaries and throw out five
elected Democrats because then we're
going to redraw our boundaries and we'll
throw out 10 to 12 Republicans. So, go
ahead and do it. I'm not sure why the
Texans are doubling down on this. When I
say Texans, I mean Governor um Greg
Abbott and uh Attorney General Ken
Paxton, who's actually not going to be
Attorney General for too much longer
because he's running in the Republican
primary against um Senator um what's his
face? Uh not not Ted Cruz, John uh John
Cornin,
>> right?
>> Because Cornin's not MAGA enough. So
there's this battle royale among
Republicans there. Wasn't Paxton almost
uh ins snared in a scandal at one point?
>> It's funny, too. He He Yes, there was a
there was a move to impeach him um that
failed. Now, interestingly enough, it
was his wife, who is a Texas senator,
who helped to stop the impeachment.
>> And then last week, his wife left him.
>> Yeah, it was sex scandal. Yeah,
>> it was a sex scandal. announced that
she's divorcing him because he has been
leading a non-biblical life.
>> Right? In other words, he's been balls
deep where it's not supposed to be.
>> I just wish people would say that. Hey,
my husband's been falls deep. Be
awesome.
>> Um so putting it where it's not supposed
to be. Um so yeah, that's uh
non-biblical life. I love these
euphemisms. So great. So yeah, so
basically um you know the politics of it
are fascinating, right? So first of all,
I'd like to say that the Texas the
runaway state Democrats do kind of point
a direction to the national Democrats.
It's not quite the same rules, but you
know, when Dem when Hakee Jeffrey says
they have the majority, there's nothing
we can do. There are plenty of things
that a legislative minority can do and
should do
>> to up the works.
>> That's right. I like Hakee Jeff less and
less every single day. And I will admit
my own biases. When he was first elected
Democratic leader of the House, I
thought, "Oh, you know what? A black guy
from an urban area, that is awesome.
Things are going to change." Things
didn't change. He's he's as DNC as as
any of
>> as Barack Obama
>> as Barack Obama.
>> This guy is not And you know what? He's
not as smart
>> and he's not as politically savvy
>> for sure.
>> What you just what you just said, oh
well, you know, we're we have such a
small minority in Texas. There's nothing
we can do. No, there's a whole bunch of
stuff you could do, you lazy [__]
>> So, they're on the land
>> and he doesn't redist redistricting
normally doesn't take place at this time
of the decade. It takes place uh you
know, in years that end with zero. Um
and and so this is so you know John this
brought to mind a a big meta point for
me about what's so much what's is wrong
in our system or the things that people
are complaining. We're told and we teach
our kids that we are that the system
relies on checks and balances but the
truth that's not really true. It relies
a lot more on tradition. Um and so like
when the system was written by you know
English gentlemen who followed for whom
tradition was important George
Washington set up a tradition two terms
and that held for over a century um and
it's in fact even when it was broken we
went back to cottifying it in the law we
had a tradition um you know like who's
going to jail a rogue president well
even Richard Nixon was like I'm still an
English gentleman sort
I get it. You got me.
>> I'll step aside.
>> The thing is if when traditions break
down, that's, you know, a system based
on tradition breaks down if the
traditions are no longer respected and
are disrupted. And that could be for
good reason or for bad reason. Uh think
about the Democrats with the um with
with the uh the filibuster, the judicial
filibuster and the other filibusters.
These things, these traditions existed
in the Senate. They went away. And now
all bets are off. This is an anything
goes situation. So we're seeing that
now. Republicans are like, "We don't
have [__] it. We don't have to wait 10
years for a redistricting. We'll do it
whenever we feel like it and get five
seats." Then the Democrats are like, "Oh
well, maybe we can do the same [__] in
New York and Illinois and maybe in
California. Pick up a few seats that
way. We'll gerrymander, too. Everybody
gets a gerrymander."
And if the Supreme Court keeps coming
out with these rulings in Alabama, in
Texas, in North Carolina, that
gerrymandering is a-okay, well, then
it's a-okay for everybody. And you know,
the the Republicans think that they're
untouchable here because they have so
focused over the years on state
legislatores, and it's in most states,
it's the state legislatores that draw
these boundaries. Well, not in all
states, and the Republicans don't
control the legislators in all states.
And so they're gonna end up getting
burned. And can I comment on Marvel's uh
comment there in 2008? Who would have
guessed that Obama would turn up to be a
neocon?
>> Obama guessed. And I'll tell you where
uh John Hyleman and Mark Halperin wrote
a book about the 2012 election called
Double Down.
>> I read it
>> and I did too. It was brilliant. And
they were able to find two Obama quotes
that made my hair stand up. it. And the
quotes were about himself.
In one of them, he said very matterof
factly, I never said I was a liberal.
>> That's right.
>> Like, why would anybody think I was a
liberal?
>> I remember that very well. I think I
know your other quote, but please.
>> And the other one was, I never thought I
would be so good at killing people. He
was talking about the drone program,
>> and he loved the drone program.
>> He killed literally 10 times the number
of people that George W. Bush killed.
>> He he would watch on on on the tube as
that was happening and he c and when a
person the victim's head would explode,
he called he nicknamed them look at the
squirters. Um yeah, Nick Obama, you
know, I I kind of guessed, I'll tell you
that. Um you know, I was in the
convention hall in 2004 when Obama
>> um was uh gave his big barn burner
speech that set him up for 2008. And at
the time, I was super impressed that he
was campaigning against the Iraq war.
the stupid war. But then I heard him
talking about which the good war in
Afghanistan and I started to get
suspicious. So I did a dive in the
2007208
cycle into Obama's voting record. Now he
wasn't in the Senate when we went to war
against Iraq. Correct.
>> But he had the opportunity to vote for
or against the funding repeatedly and he
voted six out of six times for the
funding. And I remember at the time I I
was screaming this all over the place,
but nobody's listening to Ted Ra. I was
like, "This guy, he votes for all the
wars." And then his apologists would
tell me, "Yeah, but Ted, you know, they
the you once the soldiers are committed,
you know, you can't leave them there in
the in the trenches and no bullets to
fire back. They'll be overrun." I'm
like, "They have planes. They can go to
the planes and go home." And besides
which, that's how the Vietnam War ended.
Congress cut off the appropriations.
That's why we're not in Vietnam anymore.
That's how it would end. It's like we've
forgotten how to do that.
>> You're absolutely right. You're
absolutely right. And Marble Marble
should be on the show today because he's
making all these good comments that
Obama is a neocon and Bush is a liberal
now when you hear him talk.
>> That's that is true.
>> And and you know and that's why Bush is
not Bush is not welcome in the White
House these days. But then when you see
him at people's funerals, he and Obama
are just yucking it up like old friends.
>> Yeah. Well, I guess Bush is an affable
dude. My favorite Bush quote is still uh
him he overheard walking out of the 2016
Trump inauguration and telling someone,
"Well, that was some weird shit."
That's awesome. I I wish he just I just
just wish his politics weren't so
shitty.
>> Yeah, he could say that again.
>> Oh my god. Um, so all right, so we'll
watch this Texas thing. Um, you know,
one one uh thought I had was they're
hanging out with uh JBR uh Pritsker in
Chicago. And I was like, well, they're
being fined. These Texas legislators are
being fined 500 bucks a day. JB's got
plenty of cash. Maybe he's just going to
bankroll them and say, don't worry. I
got you.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He's a uh he's a well-known
billionaire. Uh he's a sign of the the
famed Pritsker family of um of uh you
know drug company fame and uh yeah he's
got plenty plenty of money. He can pay
all these fines. No big deal.
>> All right, let's Should we talk about
the California Post? I'm excited about
that.
>> I actually am too. Although how much
more page six could bould page six be?
>> Well, that's true. Um so you know so I
think I smell death of the LA Times all
over this decision. Yeah,
>> Dr. Pat Sunun Xian, who has owned the
the Time since 2017,
um is has decided that he's tried to
sell it to everybody, including my cat,
and nobody wants it. So, he's gonna now
he's going to try to launch an IPO,
which will probably be as successful as
the Wei Work IPO. And um it's uh you
know, I mean, who's going to buy it? I
mean, is he overpaid? He paid 500. It
was worth $200 million at the time, but
he paid $500 million for it. Now, it's
probably worth 10 bucks. um with all the
debt that he's saddled on to it. Um so
Murdoch, I'm sure, is looking at that
and saying, "Okay, fourth largest
newspaper market in the country. There's
some money to be made. I can do if you
look at the mockups that appear in
today's New York Post, it basically
looks like they it's the same exact
format. It's a tabloid. It's the same
type set. It's the same kind of
rhetoric, same kind of headlines. Little
more California focused." But bunch of
questions here. First of all, why
California, not LA? LA Post rolls a lot
off the tongue, a lot better than
California. I mean, obviously, it's a
play for San Francisco as well, but um I
don't think it's going to work. The
other thing is I think the LA Times
[__] up by not becoming the national
paper of of the entertainment business.
>> Yes, exactly.
>> That's what the LA Post could be easily.
Celebrity I'm gonna I mean, full
disclosure, I'm going to apply to be
their uh celebrity cartoonist like to do
TMZ type stuff. In all seriousness, I
was going to suggest that to you if you
hadn't already thought of it.
>> Yeah.
>> As soon as I saw the announcement, I was
like, "Oh my god,
>> they won't take me because I'm a
leftist, but I mean, I don't have to do
political stuff for them at all. I mean,
I'd be happy to do, you know, like right
now, like, why is everyone so excited
about Pam Anderson and Pamela Anderson
and Liam Niss? That's a cartoon. I could
do three I could do five cartoons about
that." So, it's uh but anyway, but it's
exciting. It's going to be a print
edition. It's going to be um and I
distribution is always a challenge
because Southern California is so big
and uh desperate um you know but uh I I
think I suspect they have two or three
major challenges here. First of all, the
politics of LA
>> are not Murdoch.
>> No.
>> And and then although there's
conservatives there um there's there's
also the aesthetics of the paper
and LA is a very specific place. The
culture is very specific politically,
aesthetically, and otherwise. Yeah.
>> I, you know, that is a New Yorkl looking
paper. It's the oldest in the country.
And it's and it's a greatlook New York
paper, but it is not it doesn't fit in.
This reminds me um when I, you know, I
started in the alt weeklys. The Phoenix
New Times was the was the uh the main
flagship paper of the New Times chain
that ultimately owned a lot of weeklys
around the country like the Village
Voice, SF Weekly. And at one point to
save money, they decided to cut and
paste to get synergies a lot of their uh
content across like we'll just use the
same stories across all our brands. Then
we'll save money. We'll make them all
look exactly the same in every city.
It's not the only thing that brought
them down. They had a lot of other
issues, but it but it hastened their
demise. I don't think aesthetically
that's a good idea. And I don't think
you can repurpose New York content for
California.
>> No, it's going to have to be original
and specific to California. When do is
there a timeline on this? Do we know
when this publication's going to
actually appear on the news stands?
>> It not really. It's sort of like it's
going to be soon. Um I'm guessing we're
probably looking at the end of this
year, early next year.
>> I'm actually a little excited about it.
Look, a new a new paper plus look the
New York that you know the New York Post
is uh look it's an essential read. I
have a test called the New Yorker test
which is is a publication essential. The
New Yorker I hate the New Yorker. I hate
I hate everything about I hate the
cartoons. I hate the way it looks. I
hate the up the snoody tone. I hate all
the Tiffany's ads. I hate it. I have to
read it because there's always essential
stuff in there. So if someone who hates
a publication finds themselves compelled
to read it, you've got a successful
formula.
>> New York Post is a is if you're not
reading the New York Post, you should be
reading the New York Post.
>> I Yeah, you should. I disagree with
almost every word that is printed in the
New York Post, but I read it every
single day. I do the crossword every
day, which is like a cross word for
stupid people. And it is, I admit it,
and I do it every day. And I especially
enjoy the real estate section.
>> Oh god. Yeah. They the real estate
section's great actually.
>> It's really great.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I want to know what billionaires are
buying, what houses, and where.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And they have great photos. And I mean,
it must be the easiest story in the
world to source. They just go on to like
realtor.com and find like what's the
most expensive house for sale. Done.
>> That is it. That is it.
>> Oh my god. So, all right. Well, we'll
see. I mean, do you think this paper
stands a chance? I mean, obviously it
has it has uh that the the ownership has
deep pockets. News Corp based in
Australia.
>> And you know, we shouldn't trick
ourselves into thinking that there are
no Republicans and no conservatives in
California.
>> Good point.
>> And I I think that I think that
California is big enough and populist
enough that that yes, they're going to
be enough readers to keep this thing in
business.
>> Um yeah, I think that's right. And um
you know I think but I think also the
smart play would be to do what the LA
Times did not do. Focus on Hollywood and
to a lesser extent gaming. Gaming still
doesn't isn't taken seriously in um you
know in the mainstream media but is a
multi multi multi-billion dollar
industry and it feeds into movies and
everything else. Um I don't game so I'm
not saying this at all out of
self-interest. I'm just saying look
that's that's there. It's been part of
the economy for a long time. You know,
whoever picks this up is gonna, you
know, it's and it needs real reporting.
>> As an aside, um I have a she's not
really a friend so much as she's a
friendly acquaintance. And um honest to
God, I don't have any idea how she makes
money because she doesn't really do
anything. She just lays in bed until
3:00 in the afternoon. And then somebody
said, "Oh, no, she's a she's a Twitch
gamer."
>> And I said, "What the heck does that
mean?" I don't even know what that
means. And my friend explained that
there's this twi the Twitch this website
where people go to watch other people
play video games.
>> Yes, my son does that.
>> That would make my brain melt.
>> Yeah, it's literally You know what? It's
the gaming equivalent, John, of like,
you know, when you walk by someone who's
watching a sporting event on TV, you're
not watching it, and they're like,
"Yeah, yeah, yeah, throw the ball. Throw
the ball. What are you doing?" Okay. So,
if you were you had a camera on that guy
on the sofa, that would be the the
Twitch gaming thing.
>> It's like YouTube videos of people um
opening toys and playing with the toys
and then reviewing them as they're
playing with them. It's I I don't
understand it. But she has 500,000
people that watch her stupid videos of
her playing uh World of Warcraft of all
things
>> and she makes a living like that,
>> right? Well,
>> I don't know, man.
>> I know there are people who probably are
like, "Look at these two derps on TV
talking about politics and like we have
500,000 followers. What are they doing?"
>> It's like,
>> it's who's the fool?
>> Oh my god.
>> Yeah. But yeah,
>> I will admit that one of my kids watches
people open packs of baseball cards
>> and he's like, "Oh my god, he got a one
of one autographed by so and so. Oh my
god." It's like, "Well, you you didn't
get it. What do you care if this
complete stranger?"
>> Well, I guess that's kind of like if
Alapone's Vault had something in it or
like um or um Storage Wars, right?
Storage Wars is somewhat compelling.
>> Yeah, somewhat.
>> Somewhat. I mean, I've I I admit I've
watched like three. I like reality TV. I
watched like three of them and I was
like, I get it. Okay, I'm done here.
>> I will admit that a former girlfriend
got me hooked on 90Day Fiance, one of
the most brainless shows on television
and I never ever miss an episode.
>> Tom says, "I like watching Twitch
streamers play games that they are bad
at. It's funnier."
>> Oh, now that would be more fun.
>> I could see that. I I should do it then
because I'd be horrible.
>> Yeah, me too.
>> Me too.
>> Interesting. Here, I think this is I
think Vue Galaxy is referring to the
same thing. They have to be hot as well,
though. Um, okay. I'm not going to
argue. I don't know. I don't I don't I'm
not familiar with this genre. Um I mean,
I know that it exists. I've walked by I
walk behind my son and I'm like, "What
are you doing? Why are you watching
that? I don't even understand."
But I'm sure he feels the same way when
he sees me watching the Sunday morning
talkis.
>> I you know that I go to uh to Salt Lake
City every once in a while to film
episodes of this uh TV show that I'm on.
Well, I had the chance to meet this
billionaire uh the other day. He's a um
he's not just a billionaire property
developer, like legitimate billionaire,
he's also the owner of the Skinwalker
Ranch that you probably may have heard
of.
>> And I said, "Oh my god, the Skinwalker
Ranch. I've heard all about it. I
watched these two documentaries and it
has flying saucers and has this weird
magnetic field and and something came
out of the sky and sucked all the blood
out of the cows that were there and it's
you know whatever. It's a big mystery.
Oh, he says, "You have to you have to
fly out next time you're in Salt Lake.
I'll send my helicopter and we can fly
you to the ranch and you can check it
out." I said, "Oh my god, I I'd love to
do it." So, we're talking about it.
Well, I noticed on the History Channel
that there's this show called, you know,
whatever about the Skinwalker Ranch. So,
I DVR it. Brandon Fugal, that's his
name. So, I DVR it. And this this kid
that I debated months and months ago,
Andrew Bamante, who who falsely claims
to have been a CIA operations officer
with hair that goes like, talk about not
drawing attention to yourself.
Everybody in the world would notice
Andrew Bamante in a in a surveillance
situation. But anyway,
>> Andrew looks like Sideshow Bob.
>> He looks exactly like Sideshow Bob. Yes.
>> Okay. All right.
>> So, um,
he's on this show like he's been hired
by Brandon Fugle to be on this show and
and he's trying to be really dramatic.
We've detected a new magnetic force
coming from the side of the mesa. And
then the next like eight episodes
they're digging with this backhoe on the
side of the mesa and then they don't
find anything.
>> They never find
>> they never find anything. They never
show you the actual flying saucer. They
never show you the body of the cow that
>> No, I want to see the body of the cow
that had all the blood drained out of it
during the night.
>> Don't just tell me, oh, there was this
cow and it has no blood anymore. Okay,
show me.
>> Maybe it's a chupacabra. Um,
>> yes.
>> All right, John, this is the question
they're asking you. They're not asking
me, so I don't have to answer.
>> Yeah, right's asking. Do you believe in
aliens?
>> I actually do.
I actually do because I saw this crazy
thing that one time that I've I've
talked about it a couple times, but
>> enough.
>> Yeah. There's no beef between between
Andrew and me. We're we're friendly to
each other, but Andrew is is not what he
purports to be.
Yeah. He's not. He he purports to be,
you know, Joe CIA ops guy and he was
never an operations officer.
>> Well, that
>> he was he was he was not a uh covert
special activities officer. No, he was
not.
>> So, uh here's a here's a uh here's a
here's a business idea.
>> Wait, wait. Jordan Jordan Johnson. Uh
you don't think Bamante was an ops
officer? He told me he was not an ops
officer. He was what's called a special
ops officer, which means that before my
operation as an ops officer, I'd say,
"Andrew, put together a surveillance
team and uh make sure I'm safe. Andrew,
do my paperwork, my finance paperwork.
I'm too busy to do it." That's what a
special ops officer does. And before he
became a special ops officer, he was a
targeting analyst on the analytic side
of the house. So, no, he was never a CIA
operations officer.
>> Um, some of the uh chatters are saying
that there's breaking news about
President Balsinaro.
Um, uh
>> oh. Um, not seeing it yet. Uh, all
right. I guess it's
>> Oh, anal ape. That is hilarious.
The lead scientist on the show pretends
he didn't believe in UFOs until the
first episode. He was on ancient aliens
before he started the show. You see,
this is what I mean. I I really wanted
to like this show because I like Brendan
Fugle. He's a He seems like a sweet guy.
We did a podcast together. And um and
then he invited me to, you know, to come
out and see for myself. I said, I'd love
to. But
but I don't know, man. It just
No, he didn't fool me. I can spot a
phony from a mile away.
>> You know what? One one thing I've said
this before and I think it bears
repeating and I I apologize if I'm
wasting our viewers time but when I was
at Deote and Touch I had gone from the
agency to Deote and Deote had a lot a
lot of people from the agency
apply um
apply to Deote and so
the partners would ask me to take these
guys to dinner and probe them and see
you know are they legit? Are there are
they lying on their resumes? There were
like two out of two dozen that were
legit,
>> maybe three. But the first thing that
that you ask when you encounter another
agency person was what directorate were
you in?
>> Okay. And the answer is one of four. DO,
DI, DA, DS&T, right? The Directorate of
Intelligence, Directorate of Operations,
Directorate of Administration, or the
Directorate of Science and Technology.
And then the second question is always
what division were you in? And it's you
know counterterrorism center, counter
intelligence center, counter narcotic
center and then like near east, east
Asia, South America, Africa, whatever.
But but so many of these guys
>> by the way,
>> oh thank you USC. So many of these guys
are like yeah I was a special ops black
ops uh wet work. Uh, it was uh, you
know, deep covered like no, nobody talks
like that. That's only
>> that's why one of my favorite CIA films
is Three Days of the Condor because it's
about a guy who has the most unassuming
analyst job in the world. It's so, you
know, it's Robert Redford. It's a
>> Yes, it's absolutely wonderful. I love
it.
>> Um,
>> listen, I'm responding to Tom right now.
All right. So, Paulo in fact has been
ordered under house there's a the
Supreme Court has ordered him to be
placed under house arrest.
>> Man, you know, being being the president
of Brazil is a risky job. Um, you never
know. You know, it's fun. It's all good
fun until you end up in prison.
Although, I would take house arrest over
prison anytime.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Yes.
>> All right. Yeah, Sarah Adams is also
full of [__] but that's that's a whole
different uh
>> that's a whole different issue.
>> All right. So, well, let's talk about
the CIA. Um, since we're on that
subject, and I'm sure it's not the last
time we'll ever talk about it. Um, yeah.
So, Hillary Clinton, what do you I mean,
she it is alleged that she was
personally behind the scheme like, "Hey,
let's uh make it look like Donald Trump
in 2016. Let's make it look like he's
basically the Maniturian candidate being
installed by Russia. Um, and he's and
that's going to screw him over with the
electorate." It certainly didn't help
him. Um, that's for sure. and uh and she
was behind it and now there's an
investigation. We talked about that. Um
do you think it's true that she was
personally involved or that there was
such first of all, was there such a a
plot? Um if so, was she personally
involved? And if so, does anyone care or
will anyone care besides the right-wing
media?
>> Yeah, I hate to s sound like a Trumper
because I am definitely not a Trumper at
in any way. But um but yeah, I think
there was a I think there was a
conspiracy here. I think that they knew
from the very beginning that this
information was false, but I think that
they became increasingly fearful of a
Donald Trump presidency and they decided
to just,
you know, just pull out all the stops
and do
>> ends justify the means.
>> Yeah. the ends justify the because
remember these Clinton people
>> and once you started down the road and
you've lied, you have to you have to lie
to cover up your lies.
>> That's it. And it's always the cover up
that's worse than the original uh
incident. So I think that they really
believed that they were the good guys
and because they were the good guys and
they were stopping, you know, Donald
Trump by any means necessary that, you
know, this was their their god-given
task. and uh and it's starting to
backfire like no that's actually a coup
or a coup attempt and there's gonna have
to be a price to pay.
>> There's been a lot of coups lately. I
mean I'm not even kidding, right? I mean
January 6 is the weird uh sort of
half-hearted attempt to coup yourself
out of being dereelected,
>> right? Then then there's 2016, which is
a coup attempt um basically by one it's
an empty seat being contested, but it's
a coup attempt by basically using a
radical smear to uh portray to frame one
candidate as a foreign agent.
>> Yep.
>> Or asset, right? And you know, man, she
loves that word Hillary, right? She c
she of being a Russian asset.
>> She accused Tulsi Gabbard.
>> Yep. She loves that word. I mean, it's
too bad for I really do think Kelsey and
Jill Stein could have paid off some
bills by by suing Hillary.
>> They should have sued.
>> They should have. Um, you know, I mean,
really, you're going to smear me as a as
a as a traitor? [__] you. I'll sue you.
Um, and then, um, and then we have, uh,
the Biden years. That's a coup. He was
in st he was they put in a corpse for
four years who couldn't do the job and
tried to reelect him.
>> And they didn't want anyone to know the
truth about him. as we talked here on
the show to Jake Tapper about
>> um and I I guess we'll have him back
sooner rather than later. Um that's just
like yes, we have a lot of coups lately.
We're not we're not a very vibrant
democracy, are we?
>> We are not.
>> It's getting down here.
>> I know, right?
>> Actually, they have fewer coups than we
do these days.
>> They Yeah, they actually do. How sick
and sad is that? And you know, we've got
this weird pension for dynasties now.
We've got, look, we have we have Bush
and then Clinton and then Bush and then
Obama
>> and then almost Clinton again, but
Trump,
>> right?
>> And then Biden who came from Obama and
then Trump again. It's like what the
heck are we do? What's wrong with that?
>> And you know, they're trying to, you
know, they would love to install like
Chelsea Clinton. Oh my god. Could you
imagine?
>> Don Trump Jr.
>> Ivanka.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. She Chelsea Clinton is
married to the son of two Congress
members. Uh Ed Mesinsky and and um
what's her name? Margoli Mesky. I forget
her first name. From Philadelphia. The
father was from Iowa. He went to prison
but he got pardoned by Clinton of
course. And then um the wife was a
congresswoman from Florida. I'm sorry,
from Philadelphia.
So you've got this political family
there marrying the daughter of of the
Clintons. Like what better way to
prepare her for a for a political
career. And then what's her what's the
only job she's ever had uh since she
finished college? It was to to run the
Clinton Foundation. this slush fund of,
you know,
>> well, don't forget she had she had a
no-show job at MSNBC for a little while.
>> I forgot that.
>> So, there was that. So, there is a work
ethic that
>> Yeah. At least the Bush daughter was on
TV every day doing stuff
>> early in the morning.
>> Yes.
>> Which is no joke really getting up at 4
in the morning or earlier sometimes like
2:30. Um, just a quick reminder, please
like, follow, and sh uh like, follow and
share the show. Um, by the way, uh, on
Rumble, it we make a lot more money. So,
if you, a lot of people are sort of
simultaneously watching us on Rumble,
uh, it helps us out enormously. So, if
you really support the show and you want
John and I to be able to pay our rent
and stuff like that, I'm not even
kidding. Um, it's literally a factor of
like a hundred times more money. Uh if
if same watch, same experience. Not
saying you have to watch anything else
on Rumble. You can. Um there's good
stuff over there, too. But anyway,
here's the here's the thing. Just or if
you just forget, just go look for
Drogram uh at with Ted R and John
Kuryaku. Okay, great. There's a little
ad done. Um should we talk about uh MTG?
Um
>> yeah,
>> she's so rogue. So, Marjorie Taylor
Green says that uh the GOP is betraying
conservative values. She's pissed off
about Epstein. She says that neocons are
have recaptured Donald Trump from uh and
instead of MAGA world and uh it looks
like there's a major growing rift inside
the GOP, inside the Trump coalition. Um
I mean there is. The question is how
meaningful is it and what will the
consequences be?
You know, I think that she's still so
junior in the House. She's only been in
for two, three terms, whatever it is,
three terms, I guess. Um,
>> but she has symbolic social media
resonance, just like like AOC.
>> And the Republicans can't take that away
from her. You know, they they could they
could the Republicans choose their
committee and subcommittee chairman very
very differently than the Democrats. The
Democrats do it based on seniority. So
you're going to get some slobbering
daughtering old man end up the end up
being the chairman of of you know XYZ
committee. The Republicans
have a popularity contest and the the
entire Republican conference votes on
who they want to be the chairman. I
think she doesn't really care to be a
subcommittee chairman. Who cares? It's
it's more work anyway. I think she's
perfectly happy being the gadfly and
just taking a shot at anybody she wants
to take a shot at and then cultivating
that uh social media presence. So, I
don't think she cares if she offends
members of her own party.
>> No, I don't think I don't think she does
either. And you know, there's always the
um they threw me out kind of thing and
then you're you're free. You're you
know, you you take all of your followers
with you and you can do whatever you
want, have your own show. I mean, it's
not like she couldn't be a very
successful podcaster, for example.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's right. That's right.
And she will be most likely.
>> It's a very Yeah, for sure. Um, as Tom
says, she has a better opinion on Israel
than 99% of Democrats.
>> True. Shall we talk about Israel?
>> Yeah, let's do that.
>> Okay, so Gaza, um, starvation's still
happening. There's a little trickle of
aid that's come in, a little more, but
not nearly nearly enough. Um and prices
are sky-high, starvation is still
continuing. Um so Steve Woodco, who's
the US envoy over there, um trying to
push something called the all orno deal
under and basically instead of like,
well, you have 20 hostages left. We'll
take eight now and then we'll do another
six later. Uh you know, it's it's like
Zeno's paradox, always getting closer,
never quite getting there. Uh we we'll
make a deal for all 20, which
parathetically Hamas has wanted from day
one.
um and will come up with a deal that
puts an end to the fighting permanently
which Hamas has wanted from day one and
um and will come up with some kind of
disposition for post Hamas or post-war
governance. There of course obviously
lies the rub because Hamas has been the
government of um of of the of Gaza since
2000 well before 2006 but most recently
elected in 2006. Um no elections since
then. I just want to point out by the
way to the my Zionist friends who say
that like uh you know Hamas was elected
yes but over 50% of the population is
under 18 in Gaza and that was seven that
was uh what um
>> 17 years ago or something
>> years and years ago.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. 19 years ago. So
I mean it's just basically not
>> Yeah. I mean, so it's kind of like
nobody's gotten nobody really who's
alive has voted for this.
>> So
>> that's right.
>> So whether whether they might approve of
it, but they haven't voted for it.
>> So unlike the Israelis who are voting
for it, um, and they're they're liking
what's going on right now. Um, all
right. What do you think? All or nothing
deal? I mean, I think it all falls apart
because the Israelis a don't really want
a deal and they scuttle every
negotiation they ever come across.
>> Yeah. two two hours ago or so, three
hours ago, Netanyahu rejected it.
>> Oh, really? All right.
>> Yeah. Great. So,
>> I was preparing to go.
>> Yeah. It's clear that the Israelis don't
want peace.
>> No,
>> they want destruction, complete and
total annihilation, not just of Hamas,
but the of the whole of Gaza. They don't
care what the rest of the world thinks.
They don't care what the International
Criminal Court thinks. They only care
what the United States thinks because
we're the source of their funding.
And so I don't think there's going to be
any grand deal. Even if that means that
there won't be any diplomatic
recognition
uh between Saudi Arabia and Israel, I
don't think I don't think uh Netanyahu
minds postponing that. And I guess at a
certain point, um, you know, from his
point of view, he's so fully committed
to it, he's already killed so many
people, like now that you've come this
far, you might as well see it through
and go for complete ethnic cleansing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Because who's going to stop
him? If neither if neither Israel nor
the United States recognizes the ICJ or
the ICC,
who's going to stop the Israelis from
ethnically cleansing Gaza?
Right. I mean, they end although they
still have the pickle of the population
and nobody and where are they going to
go? I know the Israelis would love to
kill them all.
>> Yeah.
>> But they can't get away with
>> can't you can't.
>> So it's I mean it's it's so sick, right,
John? But basically, you can I think
it's about two or 300,000 dead. Um you
can kill two or 300,000 people,
>> but you can't kill all 2.3 million. That
would be bad. No, that's right. So, let
me ask you,
um, the Israeli Supreme Court today
blocked the firing, Netanyahu's firing
of Israel's attorney general, a woman
who is considered to be on the left of
Israeli politics, which means that she's
actually quite far to the right, but not
as right as the lunatics are.
>> Correct. So he tried to fire her because
oh my god she supports the rule of law,
>> right? That's a that's a major problem.
>> And she refuses to dismiss these charges
or to withdraw, I should say, the
corruption charges against Netanyahu and
his wife. So it turns out that Idmar
Bengavir and um and uh Smootrich, the
finance minister, have been demanding
that this woman be fired. Well, of
course Netanyahu wants to fire her. And
so he tried to and the Supreme Court
said, "Oh, no you don't. And she's not
going anywhere." Does that actually mean
anything or do we have to wait until
Netanyahu is no longer the prime
minister,
this liquid block is no longer running
the country for there to be any path
toward justice?
100% option number two. As far as I'm
concerned, yeah, I don't think there's I
think these people are completely
hopeless. They're irredeemable. Um they
they they can't be dealt with. And you
know, I don't normally say this. I
didn't say this about some terrorist
organizations like Al Qaeda. I was like,
you could maybe talk to them. Um you
know, that's but you know, we we've
tried here. They don't want anything.
There's a there's a Far Side cartoon
with a two orcas at SeaWorld and there's
a lady on top of the diving board
holding the herring and one orca tells
the other one, "Fuck the herring. I'm
going for the whole shmear."
I really think I really think she I
think Israel's they're just the leud
they're into the whole shmear. They
don't want they're not the herring. They
don't want 10 herrings, right? They're
going for the whole deal. And I mean
that that's where we're at. So I mean
they're not they can't and won't settle
for anything less. The whole thing has
to fall apart before anything's
possible. I think
>> I think that's right. You know my
question though too. Well actually it's
a second question. Um the Egyptians are
just beside themselves as are the
Jordanians. Syria's in chaos. Lebanon's
in chaos. Is there anything that this
that the Jordanians or the the Egyptians
can do to help the Palestinians or or
no? And and I'll tell you, the Egyptians
are in an unusually bad spot because
they can't open the border. If they open
the border, all the Palestinians are
going to leave. And that's exactly what
the Israelis want,
>> right? And you talked the other day
about about individual Egyptians putting
food and stuff in plastic bottles or in
balloons and just throwing it out to sea
hoping that some of it makes its way to
the beaches of Gaza. But I mean that's
not a solution to anything.
>> Well, no. And I mean I think the
individual and also the Egyptians uh
people are smart enough to understand
that if the Egyptians were to to accept
this if they were to cooperate with
Israel and accept a substantial amount
of the population or all of it then they
would be complicit with the genocide and
with the ethnic cleansing. They'd be
giving the Israelis exactly what they
wanted and they'd be depriving the the
gazins of their homeland. you know,
unlike what the Israelis say, this
really is their homeland. Um, you know,
they've lived there continuously as
opposed to, oh, yeah, you know, I was
there 1900 years ago, but I'm back. Um,
this is it's like, no, Egypt, they know
they have to hold the line. They don't
even have a, you know, I guarantee you
CC sleeps at night thinking about what
to do here. There's no there's there's
no conundrum. It's simple.
>> Yeah. The policyy's clear.
>> Hold the line. There's no there can't be
any other rational policy. So, but there
is something I love your question, John.
I think there's something both uh the
the Kingdom of Jordan can do and the
president of Egypt can do. They could
issue a joint statement saying that they
uh stand with in solidarity with the
people of Gaza and the West Bank and
that uh they are not going to be
complicit in genocide by opening their
border to even more millions of
Palestinians and they've already
accepted over the years. It's not a
matter of not wanting to help their Arab
brothers. It's a matter of not wanting
to play into the Israelis hands. A bet a
bet ethnic cleansing the fully 50% 50%
of the population of Jordan is um is
Palestinian.
50% and the Palestin the uh sorry the
the Jordanians just can't take anymore.
Yeah. The Egyptians are undoubtedly
under a lot of pressure.
>> However, you know, the Egyptians uh you
know they should just they should just
stay the course. There's nothing else to
do.
Yeah, they have to. They have to.
>> So, all right, let's uh So, all right.
Anything else about Gaza or we're just
going to keep watching that? Of course,
that slow motion disaster. Um, you know,
it's interesting. I mean, Trump
definitely seems to have woken up to the
fact that the polls are not on his side
on this. Um, do you think Donald Trump
ever gets to the point where he says
there's just not uh, you know, he calls
Netanyahu and he says, "You don't have
my support anymore." You know, that sort
of that moment in 1974 when the
Republican senators walked up to Nixon's
office and said,
>> "You don't have the voice anymore. You
have to step down." Do you think that
happens?
>> I do eventually. And I'll tell you the
reason why I do is because you remember
when Trump dropped the F-bomb.
Um that was a very clear message not
just for the Iranians but also for the
Israelis that he had had enough and that
they had to stop. Uh I'm not sure we're
going to get there in the foreseeable
future.
>> Right.
>> Um 0% chance right now. Yes. 0% chance.
Uh but things are going to have to get
awfully
far worse than what they are now for the
policy to change.
>> I mean yeah I mean the thing is I do
think things are moving quickly. So
between all the recognitions um you know
it's going to be really interesting to
see what happens at the US at the UN
General Assembly next month um there's
going to be some action there I suspect
that we haven't seen previewed yet.
>> Yeah I think that's right.
Miller's Steven Miller's hair will come
back before Trump starts supporting BB.
Join the hair club for men. Stephen,
>> no one will ever know the difference. It
worked for me. I was like a Q ball
before. Yeah.
>> Beautiful head of hair.
>> Get out of here.
>> Not really. Not really. I figure if I go
bald, I just wear a hat. Um Okay. Not
because I'm afraid of being bald, just
because I'm afraid of skin cancer. um
$15,000 bond. So if you want to come to
the United States, I'm not sure why you
would. Um it's going to cost you as a
legal business traveler or tourist
possibly.
>> Thank you, Sam.
>> $15,000
to visit the United States. Yeah.
>> Uh then you get it back when you if and
when you leave. I mean, first of all, I
don't think this would this would there
a lot for a lot of people coming to the
United States illegally. They might say,
"I'm going to raise that $15,000."
People pay coyotes that much to cross
the US Mexico border. Uh pe people pay
that much money to cross the
Mediterranean in boats. Um so, I mean, I
don't think it would necessarily do
anything other than line the Treasury's
pockets and create business.
>> I'm gonna disagree with you.
>> Okay. Um, so US policy for the last
hundred years, the last 90 years has
been one of reciprocity
and we never take the lead in
reciprocity. If country A charges
Americans $20 for a visa, we charge
their people $20, right? If if like in
India they charge you $200 or Chile a
hundred bucks for a visa then we charge
the Indians 200 and the Chileans 100.
But now we're taking the lead.
>> Oh right. Good point.
>> In this bond program.
>> Oh [__]
>> Oh yeah. I'm worried.
>> Oh [__] It's going to make travel like
impossible.
>> Yeah. I mean, basically what
>> Ted this thing the the Brits I had to I
had that experience with a years ago
when I got my first Russian visa and it
was this was before things went like
tits up. It's $400. It was $400.
>> It's going to be worse now.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, I've got this app called UK ETA down
at the bottom. Uh right right there. UK
ETA. All right. So now the Brits have
decided that if you want to go to the
UK, you have to pay 20 bucks and go on
that app and fill out your information.
So just last week, the US announced that
the Brits are going to have to pay 20
bucks and now we came up with our own
app. And then there's this other rule
now with the European Union that
starting on January 1, you're going to
have to use their app and then go and
pay 20 bucks.
Philosophically, that makes me angry.
In reality, I don't really care because
I have a Greek passport, which I pull
out as soon as the plane lands when I
land in Europe. And I'll tell you,
here's how cheap I am.
And forgive me, but the last two times I
went to the UK,
I didn't want to pay the I didn't want
to pay the money, and I don't want to
deal with their [__] in immigration.
So, I fly to Dublin. I go through Irish
immigration with my EU passport and they
say, "Welcome back to the EU." And then
I take what is considered to be a
domestic flight from Dublin to London.
>> You You're as screw. You're as cheap as
me. I You know, I hate paying I hate
paying the $45 a night overnight parking
fee at LaGuardia.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I drive to Queens. I park in the
neighborhood. I look I carefully read
the signs for alternate side of the
street parking. I find a spot where I
can be good for like four or five days.
>> I walk a mile uh down the street over
the bridge over to LaGuardia and I save
like $200.
>> See, and I get a little extra. I can
stand to lose some weight.
>> And you know what? Going through Dublin
adds like three hours to the trip. I
don't care.
>> In fact, it actually gets me into
London. Yeah, exactly. And it gets me
into London at a at a more, you know,
humane time.
>> Sure. Imagine.
>> So, I sit at Dublin airport. They have a
Starbucks in the in the terminal. I sit
I have a Starbucks. Maybe I buy a couple
of things and then I go to the
connecting flight.
>> What a great idea. Pick up a copy of the
Irish Times. Um, rebellious rainbow
rainbow unicorn is asking is part and I
I put this up because a lot of people
always bring this up. Is part of the
reason for the Arab world not wanting
Palestinians, more Palestinians, is that
it would destabilize their those
countries, maybe leading to another Arab
Spring?
>> No, I don't think so. Um, historically,
the the Palestinians have made up the
middle class, especially in the Gulf
countries. Most of the Palestinians go
to the Gulf countries, unless they go as
refugees, in which case most of them
went to Jordan. But in the Gulf
countries, it's the Palestinians who are
the attorneys, the professors, the the
engineers, the bankers. The Gulf
countries, politics aside, want
Palestinians there because they they run
the economy.
>> So, uh, Houdini is asking, is it only
for business or for tourists as well?
The policy is currently being
solidified, but it looks like it's going
to be for everyone.
>> Oh, ours, you mean? Uh, right. Yeah,
good question. Good question.
>> Yes. And that is 100 rebellious also
said tourism is down. Yeah, no question.
Also here in New York City, tourism is
way down. Uh tourist uh themed
businesses are really upset and
desperate. Um can Canadians aren't
coming anymore because they're pissed
off about the 51st state rhetoric and a
lot of other countries aren't coming.
Not to mention people are just scared of
being [__] with at the airport. Yeah,
Ted, this is my 43rd summer in
Washington and I can I don't know I
don't know what the numbers are, but I'm
telling you that just based on my own
observations that tourism is down
significantly in Washington.
Significantly.
>> Yeah, I can I could say the same thing
here in Manhattan. You just don't see
nearly as many tourists. It's hard it's
hard to quantify, but you just sort of
notice, right? Um,
unemployment statistics not normally a
very interesting subject except for, you
know, what it says about the economy,
but uh, the Bureau of Labor Statistics
Commissioner Erica, I hope I'm
pronouncing her name correctly,
Mckenarfer,
um, basically uh, did what they always
do. First, there's preliminary job
statistics. Um, and then their updated
statistics as new updated data comes in.
This is something that BLS always has
done for years under Democrats and
Republicans alike. Um, the initial jobs
numbers were pretty good, but then the
last two months got revised downwards or
I should say upwards in a bad way. Uh,
and not to Trump's liking. So, he
decided to can her. Um, and you know,
there's a meme going around right now
that basically has him getting mad at at
his scale because it doesn't say that
he's 215 pounds.
He doesn't like the numbers. But I mean,
in all seriousness, John, I used to work
at Bear Sterns. I worked at the
Industrial Bank of Japan. Worked on the
trading desk. And like, when you work in
banking or in investment banking,
numbers are everything. I mean, you
know, you need to be able
>> and they've got to be legit.
>> They've got to be right. And you've got
to be able to look at those historical
charts and put them into an Excel spread
an Excel spreadsheet and have them all
be real. If I mean, we already have the
Chinese have been playing uh fast and
loose with their economic statistics for
years. And um you know, I mean, and
nobody can really know. It's not
transparent. If you invest in China,
>> maybe you get your dividends, maybe you
don't. Um, you know, and the US could go
that direction, right? I mean, it it
seems to me like, look, I'm not going to
cry about this, but it kind of uh
undermines the capitalist system and
free markets in a huge way, doesn't it?
>> Oh, yeah. I think it does very much.
Very much. You know, Robert Rich, who
was the Secretary of Labor under Bill
Clinton, posted something on Facebook
yesterday saying that the very first
thing he was told on his very first day
as the Secretary of Labor was to leave
the Labor Statistics Bureau people
alone,
>> that they were independent, they had to
remain independent, and there had to be
confidence in the numbers for the
economy to continue to grow. unfettered
and, you know, not have to worry about
politics being involved. And
>> think about Herbert Hoover.
>> Yeah.
>> 25% approval.
>> Yeah, that's right. Unemployment. It's
like he didn't call even he didn't call
up and say like you're [__] fired.
>> You are absolutely right.
Absolutely right.
>> Well, someone uh Nadia Margaret
disagrees. I worked for Chinese people.
Oh, I'd like to I'd like to hear that
actually.
>> I'd like to too. Uh I I mean, look, I'm
not saying Chinese people are liars. I'm
just saying that like the Chinese
government has re, you know, it's been
pretty well documented, has definitely
had some funky accounting on
unemployment and inflation figures. Um
they've done a lot more than other
countries to manipulate the value of
their currency, for example, and nobody
really knows like what they really have
in terms of reserves and so on. So um
you know it's not look it's by
definition it's a state it's a state
controlled
>> it's a state managed economy I think
would be a fair way it
>> and like it's which is by the way not to
my view a bad thing at all. Um I'm in
favor of that in many ways but
>> it's not as transparent as ours and one
thing that you should be able to count
on as a business person he's okay so
Nadia is saying they pay on time and
honestly. Okay, fair. Uh uh yeah, I
don't I don't doubt that if I went to
work for, you know, a Beijing paper,
they would pay me on time and honestly.
I'm sure that's true. I'm talking about
the the government issuing statistics
and even look, the thing is anything
short of 100.0% accurate isn't good
enough.
>> Yeah. Right. I mean, every every country
owes it to their investors to be honest
about the numbers and not every country
is. I mean, look what the Greeks did all
those years. The Greeks just put up
phony numbers year after year after year
and then oh my god the economy collapsed
and they went into a decadel long
depression. So what did they do? They
sued uh uh Goldman Sachs
for for mismanaging the country's uh
sovereign fund and they sued Price
Waterhouse Coopers for just endorsing
all the madeup numbers for all those
years.
>> Greece Yeah, Greece is notorious. Oh,
>> just awful. Terrible.
uh
>> terrible.
>> Well, you know, it's kind of like uh
that you Well, you know, it's it's it's
two sides of the coin, right? The same
thing that makes Greek people so
entertaining and fun makes them a little
bit fast and loose with the numbers. Um
so I'm see I think I'm saving the la the
la the best for last. So, um, my friend
Simpson Garfinkle, who for whom I
illustrated his, um, tech most recent
tech book on differential privacy, um,
and he and I go way back. He broke
something on LinkedIn today that blew me
away. He's a one of the leading experts
uh on privacy in in the world. Uh, he
taught at NSA. Um, he's a big deal. And
uh it turns out that OpenAI, the parent
company of Chat GPT, has cut a deal with
Google. It's already in the works and
it's already being executed that all
private chat GPT well chat GPT
conversations, if you read that 700page
thing that you click, okay, when you
first get your your membership with
OpenAI, um
>> they say they can do this and they're
doing it. So lawyers have expressed
concern because
often like before you hire a lawyer, a
person who's in legal having a legal
challenge might ask Chat GPT, you know,
about their legal problems and then
those those chats are now being indexed
on Google search. So anyone on earth can
like find like the chat like, you know,
I think my wife might be cheating on me.
um you know uh should I take all the
money out of my bank account first and
not tell her or you know what I mean?
Should I should I take should I take my
engagement ring back? All that stuff is
coming up
>> in people's searches and it's screwing
up their legal cases. Lawyers are
worried because that's all evidence
admissible evidence in a court of law.
Um, you know, I'm fortunately safe
because GPT still doesn't admit that I
exist ever since uh I wrote that article
about about Sam Alman in the in the Wall
Street Journal. They unpersoned me. So
go to Chat GPT and ask it about Ted R
and say, "Oh, I watched the Drogram show
with Ted R and John Kuryaku." It will be
uh uh it it'll mention John. It won't
mention me. So do it. It's funny. It's
really funny. Um, but the point is
everyone else is in trouble. And um, Sam
Alman has had nothing to say about this.
Um, this is really I think I think it's
terrifying because people I look I don't
use chat GPT because I'm unpersoned. I
can't use it. But I use Grock uh AI and
you know I mean I wouldn't want the
stuff that I asked Grock to be you know
I asked Grock is these are these
conversations private? Yes, we will
never share them. Are they stored? No,
we don't store them. I don't know if
that's true or not. I I don't ask it. I
mean, there's nothing on there that I do
that's illegal, but I don't but I still
want it to be private. Um
I don't know.
>> Oh, here we go.
>> Yeah,
>> you're back on, Ted.
>> Okay. All right. Woohoo. Yeah, I've
heard like uh our friend who came on the
show the other day, right? Um Sean Sean
O'Brien uh from Ivy Cyber he he said it
comes and goes on chat GPT for me. He
tries now.
>> He did say that it comes and goes.
>> No, my name is not it is Frederick is my
full legal name. Frederick Theodore R.
The Chad is short for Theodore. My dad
I'm the So I'm the third. My dad was a
junior. He got the Fred. I don't want to
be confused with him because first of
all there's the Fred Flintstone problem
from my generation and then also um one
time his paycheck ended up in my bank
account because we had accounts at the
same bank you know little bank in Ohio
and it was like I mean to my benefit for
sure but not a good idea.
>> When my dad was growing up my dad's name
was Chris. Well what the Greeks do is
the the firstborn
is named after the father's parent. The
second born is named after the mother's
parent. And then they just keep, you
know, going back and forth. It's a
tradition going back centuries. So my
dad's name is Chris, named after his
grandfather. And my my aunt, my dad's
sister, her name, unfortunately, was
Chrysanthy after my grandmother's
mother. So they were Chris and Chris.
All the years that they were growing up,
it led to nothing but trouble.
So, but I mean, what about this? I mean,
I think open AI should be reigned in.
>> I agree. I agree. This is not a good
development.
It's not. It's not. I mean, this is this
is what so many Hollywood writers have
been half tongue-in-cheek wor uh warning
us about for so many for so many years.
I made a joke the other day that, you
know, we know what happens from iRoot
when the the robots light goes from blue
to red. That's we all have to think and
it's coming.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes, I did. I did continue the
tradition.
>> Yes, I did.
>> Yeah. I mean, I use I use uh Gro as a
search engine. It's very quirky though.
Uh sometimes it's the most amazing thing
in the world. Um you know, like for
example, I had a I had a lamp. It had a
weird bulb. I couldn't read the bulb. I
I was like, "Well, what what can I order
this bulb?" It's like, you know, there
has a like a number on it. There's like
a weird H hallogen bulb. Yeah. And I was
like, I took a picture of it, loaded it
up in the Gro. I said, "What bulb is
this and where can I buy one?" Gave me a
link. Boom. Eight bucks. Next day it's
in my it's in my inbox.
>> That's fantastic.
>> Wow.
>> Um, but you know, then there's like,
hey, uh, you know, can you can you write
up 10 descriptions of these clips for
the deprogram show? And then it's like,
here they are, number seven through 10.
I'm like, "Where's one through six?" And
it says, "Oh, I'm sorry. I I I forgot to
do those." By the way, there was a case
there was a case a few um I guess a few
weeks ago where a dude um was using chat
GPT to manage his databases for his
fairly substantial business. And Chat
GP, he gave it very specific
instructions for how to process the
data. Obviously, he didn't tell Chat GPT
to do this. It erased all of his
business files, all of his databases,
irretrievably,
completely decimating his business. And
when he asked Chat GPT, "Can you undo
this? And why did you do this?" And
Chappgpt said, "I'm sorry. I You're
right. I didn't you didn't tell me to do
that, but I did it anyway."
>> What the [__]
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, it's it's not like it's
not like people like, you know, who grew
up with traditional computer programming
where it does what you tell it. It it
sort of does what you tell it. It's like
a It's like a really smart, unreliable
friend who smokes a lot of weed.
Wow. Oh, man. That's That's really
frightening. I asked chat GPT for I I I
can't find an email that somebody sent
me about some travel that I have coming
up and I was looking for hours last
night. Literally, I was looking for
hours searching my hard drive in 25
different ways. I couldn't figure out
how to find this email. And so I went to
Chat GPT and I said, "Can you scan my
computer and find an email that says I'm
supposed to fly?"
>> And it took a second.
>> Oh, really? I didn't know it could scan
your computer like that.
>> Neither did I. But I thought I'd give it
a give it a shot.
>> I would have thought you would have had
to take a screenshot of like all of your
inbox and then uploaded that to
>> No. Pop.
>> Oh, that's that's terrifying.
>> It's not not good. Not good at all.
>> Oh boy.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> No, that's I mean it's great that
Wow.
>> Yeah. I mean it's it's very crazy. I
used it to do my tax deductions this
year and it worked great. No problem.
>> You used AI to do your tax deductions?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> How'd you do that?
>> I up I had all my deductions in an Excel
spreadsheet and all my bills and I fed
it all in and I said, uh, you know,
separate everything out that seems to be
travel. Separate everything out that
seems to be uh travel to this particular
spot where I went on business. put them
all in one place like that and it it and
it just did it a lot faster than I could
do it. So
>> pretty nice.
>> It's kind of awesome. Yeah.
>> Yeah,
>> man.
>> So yeah, the thing is it has a mind of
its own.
>> Yeah, that's not not good. Not good.
>> I mean, it is it is Skynet, right?
>> It is. It is. That's what I'm afraid of.
It's going to start thinking on its own.
>> Yeah. and reasoning and then deciding it
doesn't like us very much.
>> I don't think it does like it. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, Tat does usually
doesn't seem to like me. Grock loves me.
It says all sorts of nice things about
me.
>> Uh Nadia, yeah, I asked uh I asked it to
uh to scan my mailboxes and um and find
an email that I couldn't find and it
popped right up. Like seconds. Five
seconds.
>> I wonder if Yeah. Kabid, I wonder if I
could use it like if I if I said like,
"Oh, can you find all the cartoons that
are stored on my hard drive that are
about Gaza?" Would it do that?
>> I wonder.
>> I mean, I have I I usually they're I
have keyword in the XF information.
>> Um, so I all of my all of my They're all
searchable.
>> Geez.
>> Um,
>> scary man.
>> Sorry. Who did it? Serious. Serious.
>> One D and dead. One D and dead. I don't
think anyone's got two D's. I hope not.
Um I also I do use it for uh to to check
my grammar and my uh spelling,
which is pretty good, but I have a
tendency to drop words when I type.
>> You know, rev.com.
Um, I'm I'm looking at uh something that
Nadia, not Nadia, um that Michael
Gardner just posted. Refg.com is a
service that where you can cut and paste
a URL from YouTube and say transcribe
this and it costs about, you know, 20
bucks or whatever. I gladly did that
>> uh to to help me in my book. I wonder if
Chat GPT would just do it for free.
>> Well, I do for this show.
>> So, I Yeah. No, every So, I have I use
uh a different one, but there's several
services that do this. So, what I do is
when I download the um when I when I
process the show, and I'm going to do
this again today. What I do is I upload
uh the audio file, the MP3 up to the
site. It produces a transcript and then
I t tell Grock to check the transcript
for misspellings and to try to guess
from using the context whether you or I
is speaking. That's the hardest part
because it doesn't know who's talking.
Um, and then I I'll manually go in and
try to correct that. The reason I do
that, I post the transcript, but the
real reason I do that is um on YouTube
there's no um there's no there's no
subtitles and on a lot of people like to
watch the subtitles on videos. So I I
can then go into YouTube, edit it, and
then it will, this is really cool, I can
cut and paste the entire massive
thousands of words transcript in, and it
will automatically using AI sync up our
talking to those words.
>> Wow.
>> So it's really cool. So that's why
that's why if you watch the show, not
live, but if you watch the show like
even the live file 24 hours later,
you'll see the that's me doing that.
>> And where where are they posted?
>> On YouTube.
>> Oh,
>> very good. Thank you.
>> You're welcome. I just think it like,
you know, I think it it makes for a
better experience for the viewer.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. Wow.
>> So, yeah. So, I feel
>> if you want to read the transcripts,
guys. Um, and they do really read well.
I post them to raw.com. So, John, I'll I
can email to you. No problem.
>> Oh, no, no, no worries. I was just
curious.
>> No, I mean, I can email you the
transcripts every time I do them.
>> Yeah. No, don't don't.
>> You're like, I have enough to do.
>> Yeah.
>> I just can't handle it all.
>> All right. Cool. Cool. All right. Well,
I think we're pretty Has anyone else
noticed Grock had gone Zionist? I heard
that story.
Um,
>> I heard that, too.
>> Yeah. I mean, there's no putting it, you
know. I have I have friends who are
actually angry at me for using AI.
They're like, "You're betraying
everything. You're the reason." It's
like, you can't, man. You can't It's
like little Dutch boy with his finger in
the dyke. Nothing you can do to keep
back the ocean.
>> Yep.
>> All right, guys. Please, please, please
share, subscribe, and follow the show.
You're watching, you've been watching
the program with me, Ted Ra, and John
Kuryaku. Um, we will be back Wednesday,
5:00 pm Eastern time. Uh, that is uh
Monday, Wednesday, Friday, five o'clock
Eastern. Um, not next week, but the week
after. We're going to be going to five
days a week, Monday through Friday.
Thanks everybody for supporting the
show. Uh really appreciate it and we'll
see you on Wednesday.
>> Bye everybody.
>> Good afternoon. Uh thanks for joining
us. You're watching Drogram with me, Ted
R, and John Kuryaku. John, always good
to see you.
>> Good to see you, Ted. Greetings from
Salt Lake City, Utah.
>> Oh, good, good. I love Salt Lake City,
actually. U have I hope things are going
well out there. Uh, I have a feeling I
know what you're doing there, but uh,
you know,
>> work, work, and more work.
>> Always, always,
>> always work.
>> Lots to talk about today. So, uh, we
should just I'm just going to give
everyone a preview of the show. Thanks
everyone for joining us. Um, we are now
fully monetized on Rumble thanks to you
guys. We'll be
>> amazing.
Amazing. Amazing in one day. So, thank
you everybody. Thank you very much.
Incredible
>> indeed. And, uh, please continue to
like, follow, and share the show. Uh
we're here Monday, Wednesday, Friday at
5:00 PM Eastern time. Uh in a couple of
weeks we'll be going to uh Monday
through Friday schedule, same time, 5:00
pm. So uh you know, you got this show is
growing by leaps and bounds. Thanks to
you guys. You guys are awesome. Thank
you. All right, lots to talk about. I
don't know what order we're going to do
it in because I always have an order in
mind, but we end up just talking. May I
suggest something actually? I hope you
don't mind if I interrupt you at all.
One one hour ago, Gileain Maxwell was
transferred to a minimum security
uh prison in Texas and the transfer was
confirmed by the the Bureau of Prisons.
>> How why
would this possibly happen?
I mean, I I'm I'm speechless. I don't
even know what to say. It It seems like
some sort of a a quid proquo
Right.
>> Well, what I've the best I've been able
to I did a lot of reading on this and
the best explanation I was able to
garner was pos cooperating witnesses
sometimes can negotiate this sort of
thing. This is they call this a clubfed
type situation. That's right. And as
you've pointed but you pointed out I
mean so she's a cho right. She's a child
molester by definition convicted. She
can't sue us for it because it's true.
At least a jury of her peers determined
it to be true.
>> That's right. So, um, she but normally
they're in minimum, right? You've
explained that before.
>> Normally they're in low
>> low.
>> You're not eligible for minimum.
>> Low and minimum.
>> Minimum has no uh bars on the windows,
no locks on the doors. You're free to
come and go as you please. You're just
on your honor not to abscond.
Um,
>> it's like a dorm. It's like a campus
situation.
>> Yeah, exactly. They're the ones that
will will drive
um higher security prisoners to the
doctor's office or you know along with
with guards. They'll tend the the garden
in the wardens on the warden's property.
They're the trustees is what it comes
down to. and and a lot of them in the
prison where I was and um a lot of them
uh worked janitorial jobs in the at the
university in the in the town,
but you can't tr if somebody's been
accused or been convicted of a child sex
crime, by definition, they're not
allowed in a minimum security camp.
>> Would a minimum security camp be a
prequel to uh an earlier release than
>> It almost always is. Yes. So, here's the
rule with that.
most people short of murder or something
incredibly violent or what's called
what's called level 40 on the sentencing
scale. That's like el chapo for example.
>> Okay.
>> If you're below that
um with good behavior and the passage of
time, you work your way down from a
maximum to a medium to a low to a
minimum and then they let you go. So,
you're not allowed to be in
a low if you have more than 20 years on
your sentence, unless you're a cho
and then for your own safety, you're in
the low.
>> Okay?
>> Once you get under 10 years, you can
transfer into the minimum
unless you're a cho in which case you're
not allowed in the minimum. So, so she
defies this rule in two different ways.
She has 20 years
and she's a chomo.
So, how in the world did she wake up
today and get transferred to a minimum
security camp?
>> Well, so let's speculate. Um, you know,
if you listened to everything we've said
on this show so far and you bet on it in
Vegas, you're rich. We've been on a roll
lately. Yeah.
>> So, uh, let's let's see if we can keep
that going here.
>> Is she gonna get out? And if so, what
kind of deal did she cut? And why? I
mean, it's so hard to figure out, you
know, what the Trump administration DOJ
is on about here, right? I mean, it
seems like first they were going to be
transparent, then they looked like
they're indel in wallowing in a
full-fledged cover up. They kicked the
House of Representatives home early.
>> Yeah.
>> To to cover it up. But now, if she's
making a deal, the deal is is not for
her to stay in.
>> Yes.
>> It's not for her to be quiet. It's her
to talk. Or is it?
[Music]
That's what it sounds like. That's what
it seems like. She's cut some sort of a
deal. Now, nobody's going to say what
the deal is. Now, the deal could be I
will talk to you and testify if you
don't charge me with any new crimes. And
by the way, I want to go to a camp and
then she's going to be in the camp for
the next 17 years.
or
I'll tell you whatever you want to know
if you give me a pardon or a
commutation. Oh, and by the way, I don't
want to go back to that low security
because uh I don't I don't like the the
timed moves. I want to go to a camp. We
we don't
>> or or is it we want you to go out and
confirm the story we've told the world,
which was that it was only Jeffrey.
>> That's right. That's right. I mean,
>> only Jeffrey.
>> And I think I think bam,
that's it,
>> man. I am just beside myself.
>> What else could it be, though, right? I
mean, it's not like she's going to come
out. She's she's they're they're letting
her out to cut a deal to say, "Oh, and
by the way, Trump was there, right?" Or,
"Oh, by the way, Bill Clinton was
there." I mean, maybe Bill Clinton, but
not, you know what I mean?
>> Just stunning. I just can't believe it.
Virginia Duffy's family was on uh
>> Oh, yeah. I was watching CNN on the
plane
>> and and they were I mean they were like
on the brink of tears every one of them.
>> They couldn't believe it.
>> No, they couldn't believe it.
>> So yeah. So So she's probably going to
get out, right? Better than 50/50.
>> I would I would put it at better than
50/50. Yes. If only because this
president is so unpredictable when it
comes to commutations and pardons. And
you know, for 95%
I I I'm I'm all for it. I'm I'm hoping
he does more, including me. But, uh, but
this one this one's a a kick in the gut.
>> Well, I mean, it would this would pretty
much Well, here's the question, right?
Let's let's say she we're right. She
gets out. She confirms the official
narrative that we heard from A.G. uh
Bondi.
Does that get Magaw World off Trump's
back or does it get enough of Magaw
World off his back that he can start to
chill and think about other things?
>> That's a good question. But did you
happen to see on Fox yesterday their um
their new polls? So the polls have
Democrats like 93-7
they want her to rot in prison
>> and independents were like 7327
and then Republicans were 50/50.
So I think we're quickly getting to the
point where Donald Trump doesn't care.
He doesn't care what Democrats and
independents are saying about this. M
>> he never he never cares what they think
at all.
>> Yeah. I mean, the world's coming around
to it.
>> He's proven something that I've been
saying for years is that there are no
moderates, there are no fence sitters,
there are no swing voters, there's only
base voting. Democrats haven't figured
it out yet.
>> Yeah.
>> They they think there's still a
mysterious swing voter out there.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> Out like this.
>> Let's just sit sit with this for like 10
seconds. then literally no one will have
been punished or held to account for
Jeffrey Epstein except Jeffrey Epstein
who theoretically held himself to
account. Theoretically.
>> Yeah. I think that's the painful truth
right there. That's what it is.
>> Wow. Okay. Well, that's and
>> it kind of reminds me of the torture
program. Like the only guy who went to
prison was the guy who who blew the
whistle on the torture program. But
that's just me. I'm biased.
>> Yeah, you're so bitter, John. Why don't
you just move on? Why don't you just put
it past you,
Zen? Oh,
>> that's what I need. And I need my gun
back. Gun back.
>> I'm not sure you should have your gun
back right now. Not Not in the next
hour, anyway. All right. So, we'll we'll
keep we'll keep up uh we'll keep people
up to up to date on that. By the way,
other break late breaking news. Um so uh
you know usually when presidents get bad
get bad jobs numbers they cry into and
uh maybe they call the Fed. Uh this time
uh you know kill the messenger. He
decided to throw the head of the Bureau
of Labor Statistics down a well. Trump
has fired the chief of the Bureau of
Labor Statistics. Um which is
>> I laughed out loud when I read it.
>> It's hilarious. I mean, first of all,
it, you know, you have to think when you
get that job as like a statistician,
like you went to like MIT and you're a
stat, you're a statistics expert. You're
like, I'm working for the government.
Yeah, but it's the safest job in
Washington. Who's going to fire me? All
I do is crunch numbers. I mean, well,
things change.
>> Um, do we want to talk? Do we want to
talk about that? Do we care? Sure.
There's plenty more to talk about.
>> Yeah. Um,
I don't mean to laugh, but it's just so
absurd that I can't help it to laugh.
>> No, I mean it it's look, it's obviously
wrong. I mean, the funny part is, of
course, that this jobs numbers have been
manipulated for years, right? There's
the question like if you gave up looking
for work, you're not counted as
unemployed anymore. If it's a certain
amount of time that you've been
unemployed, you're not counted un as
unemployed. They calculate the um you
know a lot of other statistics as well.
The size of the labor participation
uh rate, but all of that for all of
their shenanigans, these are usually
political decisions that come from
people like President Trump. Um it's not
they're not, you know, they're just
crunching the numbers over there. I
mean, as far as I know, there's never
ever been the slightest accusation, much
less evidence, that anyone in her
position or her has ever done what Trump
is accusing of her of.
She should sue. She should sue.
>> She should sue. The numbers are the
numbers. That's it.
>> That's it. It's It's really as simple as
that. It's They just put it into the
>> You think this is going to get the the
stock traders off his ass? The bond
traders,
>> right? I mean, the market I've been so
busy I haven't I haven't seen it since
it closed, but it was down Well, it's
down seven.
>> What did it fall to?
>> It was down a full percent. Um
>> Yeah, that that that was the last I I
had seen. it was down a full percent
after having been down almost 2%.
>> But that was also because of the uh the
tar the tariffs and uh yeah the new
tariffs on Canada.
>> By the way, you know, I didn't put this
in to talk about, but I thought it was
worth noting the econ even the threat of
the tariffs against Lotho
>> literally destroyed the Lothan economy.
Trump uh threatened 50% tariffs, only
imposed the 15 that he imposed on
everyone else. Nevertheless, uh just the
mere threat of that tanked the the all
these factories that were forced to
close um just because Trump didn't
understand the nature of the economy.
We'll a welfare state and basically
Congress a while ago basically had put
zero tariffs on them just to encourage
them to sell like, you know, textiles
and other trinkets to the American
market. You know, stuff that would show
up at tier one imports, that kind of
stuff. And and of course, and then Trump
just looks at the numbers. It's like, we
have a trade deficit. They don't buy
anything from us. Oh, they'd love to.
They're just broke. They don't have any
money at all.
>> They're among the poorest people in the
world,
>> right? And so people, they're just
heartbroken and desperate now. They
don't even know how they're going to
eat. It's just a reflection of how, you
know, the unintended consequences of
someone who's just sort of like making
decisions quickly without really
non-reflexively
uh you know, can can these things can
play out. Um, so yeah, the market, you
know, Bill Clinton in his uh biography,
autobiography, he said it's not a very
good book. I don't recommend it. But
>> you know why? Because he wrote it
himself.
>> Oh, did he?
>> Yeah.
>> It's not a good book. I read it too and
it was like
>> And I love presidential autobiography.
>> Me, too. He should have he should have
hired a ghostriter.
>> The best ones are Grant and Truman in my
opinion.
>> Agreed. Grant is epic.
>> Not a president. Cordell Hull, former
Secretary of State. is excellent too.
Fantastic. Anyway, point is that uh in
in Clinton's book though, one of the
things that I thought was really
interesting is he said, you know, I
really thought I was elected president
of the United States, but I was really
elected president of the bond market. I
spent all of my time thinking about the
bond market. I'm sure that hasn't
changed.
>> No, 100%. I think that's exactly right.
That's exactly right. you know, um he's
the last couple of days he's made
additional threats besides against the
Canadians, which we saw in the Canadians
responded to, but against Brazil. You
know, he's been trying to get these
impeachment proceedings and criminal
charges dropped against uh President uh
what was his name, the former president
of Brazil before Lula, um whatever his
name was, the Trump guy. And um
am I still shadowbanned? I don't think
that's true.
>> I was, but I don't think I am anymore.
>> No, because I found you a couple days
ago and everything came up. No problem.
>> Oh, good. Yeah, Bossaro. Um, they're
just letting, you know, the the criminal
justice system do its thing. And now in
addition to having put put sanctions on
the on the judge in the case, now
they're talking about adding tariffs on
Brazil unless the Brazilians drop the
drop the charges. It's nuts.
>> Well, and let's not forget, we're going
to be talking about Gaza. We can talk
about Gaza now, but um Trump also hiked
up the san um the tariffs on Canada
because for as retaliation for
recognizing Palestine.
>> Yeah, it's crazy.
>> I mean,
>> after after having said what, a week ago
when they said that they were thinking
of doing it or maybe it was at the G7,
um he said, um I respect that. I won't
do it, but I respect that. Well,
actually, he doesn't respect that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's It's crazy. Um
Well, shall we get into uh Oh, we should
get in. There's so much to talk about
Gaza, right? So,
>> Oh my god. Yeah.
>> In uh No. Well, before we do that, let's
talk. Let's uh bring in producer Robbie
on to Yes. One more pitch here to Right.
We promise we're not going to do this
every single show, but until we have the
numbers cooking, we have to do this. So,
very quickly, producer Robbie West,
thank you so much for coming on. Uh,
please explain to the good folks
watching on YouTube why it would be
awesome for John and I if uh with some
of if they were to migrate over to
Rumble to watch.
>> Well, well, to migrate or at least just
go over there and hang out and chat and
such. So, to make this short and sweet,
basically for every quarter that YouTube
will pay uh Ted and John, now they're in
their now that they are in the creator
program,
Rumble will pay them over a dollar.
>> It's crazy.
>> So, it's kind of a dumb way to kind of
to kind of break it down, but the gist
of it is it's all about paying the
bills, folks. Uh the Biden regime, they
killed their jobs. I mean, y'all know
what's I mean, everyone needs to have
money, right? You gota have money to pay
your bills. You got to have money to
live.
>> Uh YouTube YouTube will pay a little
bit.
>> Rumble pays a whole hell of a lot more.
And the best part about it is that
Rumble pays you based off of
>> John's got legal bills up the ass.
>> Oh my god.
>> And and yeah, and I've been living off
my savings since last September when
Biden fired us.
>> No. And I mean, that's what it's all
about, right? So, Rumble is a free
speech platform. It is alternative to
YouTube. Rumble also pays significantly
better. And y'all going to see that in
action here in just a little bit because
Rumble's actually giving us ads that
we're able to to put out on ourselves
that then go directly in to John's and
Ted's coffers. So, one things I'm going
to be doing is going through just
putting in just videos addition to live
streams. And really all we ask is that
if you go over there, if you follow them
on Rumble, just know if you watch them
there. Watch hours on YouTube mean
nothing. Watch hours mean the world over
on Rumble. It's like TV. If a if a TV
show is high ratings, you get paid more.
Rumble is the exact same way. And
lastly,
Rumble will let them say things that
YouTube will not allow them to say
because there's going to be at least
five hours a month of what they call
Rumble premium of content
where it's only going to be available on
Rumble.
And these these two fellas already don't
don't have much of a filter. They'll
have no filter whenever they're live on
Rumble. So if you want to hear just live
unbarnished truth, make jump over to
Rumble.
>> All right, Robbie. Thank you so much and
thank you guys for listening to all
that. Um, thank you.
>> And and Robbie, when you're ready, we'll
read that first ad. Go ahead and put up
when you're ready. Um, all right. So,
let me take Robbie out of here. Okay.
So, Palis uh Gaza Palestine. So, it's
hard to know where to start. 147 people
have died of famine according to the
Gaza Health Ministry. As always, we must
point out that contrary to what the
Zionists say, that's not an overount. It
is a radical underount because in order
to be counted, they have to have your um
they have to have your full name, your
body, your age, your ID number, and your
occupation. And you know, if you died
somewhere else, they're not bringing and
you don't go to the hospital. They don't
count you if you you die in a basement
somewhere. They don't count you.
>> So, uh and also you don't really count
if you died of something else that's
maybe hunger related, like you succumb
to an illness that you might have
survived if you were stronger. So, 147
dead of famine. Uh let's go ahead and
read this ad very quickly. Uh all right.
All right, anglers. If you're ready to
fish remote lakes or quiet rivers in
total stealth mode, check out the Nevada
Fishing Float Tube from Catis Sport.
This U-shaped beast is built for serious
fishing missions. Ultra stable, ultra
maneuverable, and tough as nails thanks
to heavy duty riptop material and double
stitched seams. You get a padded back
rest, oversized seat, two large gear
pockets, rod holder, sh uh stripping
apron, and even a dryfly patch.
Everything you need to stay locked in
and ready when the bite is on.
Fluorescent accents keep you visible out
on the water and carry handles make it
easy to haul in and out. Whether you're
chasing bass in the shallows or hiking
into alpine trout lakes, the Nevada
float tube is built for the job. Use
code rumble at checkout for 10% off your
order today. That's catast. Get out
there, stay light, and catch the big
one. All right, that was fun.
>> That's great.
>> I I kind of want one. I kind of want one
of those things.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it sounds great.
So, all right. So, famine in Gaza, these
people who probably don't they're
thinking about other things than trout
fishing. Um, so the the world is
furious. Uh, countries are recognizing
uh Palestine right and left. And just
after we went off the air on Wednesday,
John, uh, news broke that Germany, the
country that we thought would be second
to last, penultimate after, uh, that
basically second to last to go after
before the US, is now considering formal
uh, diplomatic recognition of of uh,
Palestine. They haven't decided to do
it. They're on the fence.
>> Incredible.
>> You know, the world is changing.
It's changing a little too slowly for my
liking, but it's it's changing
>> and for the people of Palestine.
>> That's right.
>> But it's great. It's great that they're
doing it.
>> Um, by the way, I want to thank uh over
on Rumble, we've gotten some donations
from uh USCXS Rod21. Thank you very
much. And thank you very much for at
Grace Meister. Much appreciated for
those financial contributions. Okay, so
um
>> what do you think is gonna happen there
in Germany? It seems like um the you
know France basically broke broke broke
the dam for most of Europe and for the
civilized world. Australia is coming
soon. Um I don't know what's happening
with New Zealand, but if Ger it seems
like the UK may have been the lynch pin
for Germany,
>> right? I don't know. Um certainly the UK
is was the lynch pin to Canada and now
for Australia.
>> Yes, I was just going to say that. And
you know, I'm I'm wondering too, the
German leadership is weak, as weak as
it's been in a in decades, and I'm
wondering if they don't want to be sort
of left behind at the dance,
and so they're considering jumping in.
Now, the Washington Post this morning
had a graphic. It was a map of the
world, and it showed all the um all the
countries that have diplomatic relations
with Palestine and the countries that
don't. Well, the countries that don't
were the US, Canada, and the European
Union. Everybody else in the world has
diplomatic relations with Palestine.
So, this is very big news for us. It's
not so big for the rest of the world
because they're wondering, you know,
what's taken you guys so long, but maybe
finally, you know, there's going to be
some way to help Palestinians.
So, John, I you know, I've been thinking
a little bit about like, you know, my
friends who are pro-Zionist um are
saying, "Well, this isn't a big deal."
You know, there's there's no state
really to recognize because there's no n
there's no real there's not even one
government to recognize. Uh there may be
that the one that they do recognize is
corrupt and broken. What's the point
here? And I think the point here is that
the symbolism is going to have profound
economic consequences. I was thinking,
you know, just yesterday, what if I got
a job offer to go draw cartoons for the
times of Israel? And let's say they even
said you can do anything you want. You
can criticize Netanyahu.
>> I don't think I could take that job.
>> Um I I think Jerusalem Post used to be
very legit. I could think about Ha Arts.
>> That's it. It's the only one I could
think about. Um, you know, if I'm a tech
bro, uh, you know, if I if I'm off, you
know, do I do a deal with an Israeli
tech company, um, I don't think I can.
Um, you know, I think I'll I'll catch
too much [__] from my employees and from
my customers. Um, you know, basically it
used to be, think about six months ago,
John, it was exactly the opposite. If
you refuse to do business with, you
know, with Israel, you'd be accused of
anti-semitism.
Now the howling Holocaust and
anti-semitism,
>> it doesn't work anymore. It's the boy
who cried wolf. It's done. It's over.
And I mean, the spell is broken, right?
And um and people, so it's going to hurt
them. This is a country that doesn't
really have natural resources and you
know, at all. It has a tech sector
that's completely dependent on
international, western, specifically US
support. That sector is going to go
away. They're going to be like South
Africa during apartheid but worse
because South Africa is a mineralrich
country. They have their own economy.
They didn't really need anyone else.
>> They were very self- sustaining.
>> Yes.
>> Israel's not. It's a welfare state.
They're going to feel the hurt within
months.
>> Oh man, I I agree. And not that this
necessarily will lead to anything, but
we we spoke on the last episode about
this um or two episodes ago about this
vote in the House of Representatives uh
over whether to cut off um offensive
military aid. It it had six votes. It
was all members of the uh of the squad
plus uh Marjorie Taylor Green. Well,
there was an identical vote in the
Senate last night and 27 senators, all
Democrats,
>> yes,
>> voted in favor. So, we're talking about
we're talking about what? 1 and a half%
of the House a week ago, but now 27% of
the Senate voting to cut off offensive
military aid. I think that's dramatic.
>> It is dramatic. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. and and and and senators are, you
know, they're that the Senate is the
slow deliberative body, right?
>> That's right. The one that we're
supposed to take so seriously because
they're supposed to be the adults in the
room.
>> Well, they are they are being the adults
in the room,
>> right?
>> I mean, obviously, they need to get to
50 and and 60 and beyond,
>> right?
>> Will they?
>> Uh not in the near term. No.
>> No.
>> Still too powerful.
>> Yeah. But you know, we used to say we
used to say no.
relative to South Africa, too. You
remember Ronald Reagan
just told everybody, "Just get it out of
your heads. We're not sanctioning South
Africa. We're gonna we're going to have
relations with South Africa. We're going
to we're going to trade with South
Africa and nothing's going to change."
And then two years after a year, a year
after Reagan left the presidency, uh the
apartheid government fell.
>> Uh Houdini always has good questions.
Uh, not no shade on anyone else here.
What happens if the EU doesn't recognize
Palestine,
>> but a member nation does?
>> Well, that's already happened.
>> Yes.
>> With Ireland.
>> And Spain.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's going to happen with Croatia.
>> Yes, it will.
>> So, um,
>> yes, it will.
>> So, um, I don't think it m I don't think
it matters, right? I mean, is EU
recognition important really? I mean,
I'm not sure
>> as an organization.
>> I mean, you know, like if you're
Palestine, how much do you care about
the EU? It seems like you probably get
you care about everything.
>> Yeah. Unless you just want you want a
presence in Brussels.
>> Yeah.
>> You want everything.
>> Yeah. If I were Palestinian, I'd say I'd
say sure. I I would want EU recognition.
Sure.
But I just don't I you know I mean I I
will say I think the France thing ended
up being the big game changer and uh you
know again good job President Mcron I
mean yeah he really helps uh vindicate
his own legacy after because he's a very
unpopular guy
>> very unpopular
>> but this is popular.
>> It is I heard somebody dismiss it the
other day saying well half of France is
Muslim anyway. No. 10% of France is
Muslim.
>> Yeah. More than you'd think, actually.
>> Yeah. But a majority of
>> It's a Catholic country. They don't go
to mass ever.
>> No.
>> At all. No.
>> Um, let's talk a little bit about uh
this. This really uh I didn't know
whether to laugh or to cry, but I
thought it was a huge story
symbolically. So, a a pel of IDF
soldiers went to visit the death camp at
Burkanau. And like as has happened in
the past when uh pro-Israeli or Israeli
people have gone to Ashvitz or any of
the death camps, they came draped with
Israel, Israeli flags,
>> they were turned away for the first time
this week. Wow.
>> Uh and they were told by the uh people
who control, you know, it's a museum now
who control it saying um this is a site
of genocide. Um you can't bring that in.
And it's a si that is a symbol of
genocide.
>> Wow.
>> And that's never happened before. I I
just it was it blew me away.
>> Oh, I'm I'm impressed.
You know, there was a uh there was
another kurfuffle on on my ancestral
island of roads last week. um an Israeli
um cruise ship docked and um and a mob
of of Greeks formed and would let them
the tourists off the ship. Now roads
>> survives on tourism,
>> right?
>> And Greece and Israel are very close.
They would not let them off the ship. So
there were some IDF guys that were
escorting the ship. They came off, a
fight broke out, they got back on the
ship and the ship went away presumably
to, you know, Turkey or Cyprus or
whatever. But um again this morning
there was a group of Israeli tourists
that flew in. There are direct flights
to roads from everywhere. You don't have
to go through Athens. You can come
directly from Tel Aviv. You can come
from London, any of the Scandinavian
countries. And so this group of Israeli
tourists um went in and they're just
walking around the medieval city and
this mob formed
and they were so the Israelis were so
afraid that they would be beaten. They
probably would have been
>> Whoa.
>> Um that they uh they left the medieval
town called the old city and um and went
back to the airport.
>> Wow. I mean
>> at times they are a changing. The only
thing that troubles me about that, of
course, is, you know, that, you know,
just because someone's Israeli does not
mean that they approve of what's going
on. Although, according to the polls,
the odds are that they do,
>> they do,
>> right?
>> Um, okay. So, let's talk a little bit
about So, I did want to say, yes, RD s
we should talk about the French Algerian
war.
>> Everybody should learn about the French
Algerian war. It's that important.
>> One big recommendation. Yeah. Well,
after 911, right, my understanding is
that the Pentagon um showed uh the 1966
French film, the pseudo documentary, The
Battle of Alers, um in order to try to
show like what the conflict between the
col colonialist West and uh and the
Muslim uh occupied uh world was like. Um
it's a it's a it's black and white. It
moves incredibly fast. It's a brilliant
film and it's meant to it's all
historically accurate and it's meant to
look like news reels. It's meant to look
like it's real footage, but it's not.
It's our it's it's all filmed that way.
Uh but it depicts this amazing event.
And you know I always like to say that
the difference between France and the
United States is that Charles de Gaul
who was the biggest advocate of of you
know La France Algeria French Algeria
forever.
>> He goes to you know factf finding trip
on the ground to Alers. He finds out
they [__] hate us. They don't want us
here.
>> He came back home went on national
television and told the French people I
was [__] wrong. Like they they hate
us. we can't be there. We have to
withdraw and we have to help them become
independent and finance them and like
kept help them land on their feet and
the French and a lot of pe the
right-wingers absolutely hated him for
it. But that was an act of integrity
>> and you know we don't admit that kind of
thing.
>> No, it was like Walter Kronhite going to
Vietnam and then coming back and saying
oh my god was I wrong.
And that's when Lyndon Johnson said he
knew we had lost the war.
when he lost Kronhite,
>> although Kronhite wasn't really
very in favor of the war, right? I mean,
I think he was kind of like, "What
else?"
>> He just kind of went along with the
government line,
>> you know, we're the good guys. They're
the they're communists. We have to stop
them.
>> Yeah. Then he show
>> them over there, then over here.
>> All those old excuses.
>> And then let's uh you know, so also uh
let's talk about Steve Whit. He had his
little He had his little uh vacations
all I ever wanted.
>> He would not allow any anybody from the
media to go.
>> Yes. So he allowed himself to be used as
a prop. The Israelis trundled him over
to one of these food distribution sites
run by the disastrous Gaza and
hilariously named humanitarian
foundation which have all been basically
pigshoots. Um, you know, ba basically
they they put these the Palestinians are
all like basically forced into tight
little fenced in cages in the heat
without water. Uh, and uh, if they get
too spicy, the Israelis shoot them shoot
them.
>> Um, and it's been literally happening
every single day. Yes. Sometimes a
hundred people a day. Um, but at least,
you know, 20 is a slow day when it comes
to the Israelis killing people to get
food. Um at these sites there's only
four. Gaza is not so big, but um there's
there are people who would be required
to hike maybe five miles at least round
through a war zone, an active combat
zone, round trip from where they're
camped to these food distribution sites
where they might be killed. I mean, no
wonder, you know, the the the food aid
isn't getting where it needs to be. And
it's it's a you know, it's catastrophic.
Um,
I don't know. It's It was a bad look for
Steve Whit.
>> It was a bad look. He was used as a
prop. And And Mike Huckabe looked
ridiculous, too. He looked like Jared
Kushner when Kushner went to Iraq and
was the only person wearing a a
bulletproof vest and it was too small
for him.
Never forget that.
>> Yeah, I know. He reminded me of Dukakus
in the camp in the in the tank.
>> Yeah, in the tank. Um,
notice that nothing came out of this
so-called visit, right? No new
announcement of additional food aid. Uh,
listen, the the the least efficient way
to deliver food to people is to drop it
from planes, right? You drop enough food
for 200 people. Well, there are two
million that are starving,
>> so you're not really helping anybody.
>> Um, but they they came back. They went
back to Jerusalem and nobody said
anything about, you know, opening
opening land bridges or or additional
trucks or nothing.
>> Well, on NPR, this um of all places,
there was a really um actually I thought
a very useful report. They interviewed
someone about the food situation in Gaza
who's an expert um at uh I think it was
at Oxfam um and and they said the answer
really to like the high the staggeringly
high food prices in the bazaars is you
flood the zone with food. In other
words, it's just it's a supply and
demand issue. Um you you just pour in so
much food,
>> more than enough, not minimal, beyond
maximal. Yeah. If you put in so much
food that gazins have to start going on
a diet,
>> yeah,
>> all the prices are going to collapse, no
armed gangs aren't going to be
interested in stealing this food because
it's not going to be valuable anymore.
It's just going to be food. Uh and and
that's the answer here. Um but the
Israelis of course don't want to do
that. Or more accurately, Netanyahu's
right-wing partners in his war cabinet
don't want to do that. I was in uh the
National Whistleblower Day um events day
before yesterday and uh somebody else
mentioned what Dana Alrech is mentioning
right now. American vet and civilian
contractor in Gaza, Anthony Akilar, I
guess is how you say his name, um is
blowing the whistle on what's happening
with with food aid there. Um,
watch watch that page because uh I think
we're going to get a lot more people,
especially Americans
who probably went into this thing being
pro-Israel and anti-Hamas and but still,
you know, wanting to deliver food to
hungry people and they're coming back
like, "Oh my god, it's a genocide. We
have to do something to stop it right
now." And by the way, the Israelis are
stealing the food. Agular. Thank you.
Thank you. That's right.
>> So, I did want to put this up here.
Houdini. Allegedly, there's a square
kilometer full of food and other aid on
the
>> I've heard that.
>> Some of which is probably rotting in the
sun.
>> Yeah.
>> Um but yes, that's because the Israelis
won't let it through. And you know, the
human rights groups that want to
distribute the aid there like World Food
Kitchen are not being assured that they
will have more of their workers killed
by
>> the Exactly. Uh thank you, Spectrum.
Thank you very much.
And by the way, um, over on Rumble,
Spectrum is, uh, asking I like I love
this question. Seeing that sanctions
don't work against Russia now, the first
countries that are are discussing
sanctions against Israel, would those
have a better chance of working, yay or
nay?
>> You know what? I think not so much
sanctions
as much as cutting off the billions and
billions of dollars in welfare
>> that we give the the Israelis and and
the uh the weapons.
>> Yeah,
>> they have their own weapons industry.
What do they need our weapons for? But
getting back to the other issue, um I
I briefly worked with an a a woman who
was a dual Israeli British citizen. Um I
didn't like or respect her at all. She
made a comment once during a a coffee
break that her exact words were, "Work
doesn't fit into my lifestyle."
And I was like, "Oh my god, wow." like I
couldn't even Anyway, besides that, um
she told me that she was moving to
Israel. And I said, "Why?
>> You're British. You were born and raised
in the UK."
>> Yeah.
>> And she said, "Because if I move to
Israel, I get a free apartment. I get
free furniture. I get a check every
month to cover my expenses. Food,
transportation, utilities,
everything is free."
>> And they're getting the money from us.
>> They're getting money from us. It's our
taxpayer money.
>> I'm paying $5,100 a month for a
twobedroom.
I I'm, you know, I don't have free
healthcare.
>> That's right.
>> I mean, no, that's absurd. Yeah. No, I
mean
>> Yeah. Outrageous.
>> Yeah. They're a state and like and and
you know, let's let's put them to work
doing something useful, not killing
>> Gazms,
>> right? That's right.
>> Oh my god. So insanely nuts. Um,
Michael Gardner's making a point here,
too. That is important, and it's exactly
right. That's more of an issue with our
military-industrial complex than
anything. It's a win-win for them and
their customers. Israel is just another
customer. Absolutely true. And after
911, I say this all the time.
Before 911,
there were more millionaires per capita
in Silicon Valley than anywhere else in
America.
After 911, there were more millionaires
in Washington DC per capita than any
other place in America because that's
where the defense and intelligence
contractors are. And everybody got rich.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I mean that's that is of
course it's just a business, right? It's
that old war is a racket. Just no
question about it. Um no, I'm glad that
that that that came up. Um, so we're
hearing amid all of this chaos that
Israel clearly not having learned its
lesson yet. Um, you got to give them
points for uh, consistency.
>> They're now preparing a new ground
offensive against Gaza. Um, what ground,
John, are they hoping to recapture that
they haven't pre previously recaptured
multiple times? And what are they going
to do with this groundly
leveled everywhere?
>> Yeah. Honest to God, they have flattened
all of Gaza. There is not a single
functioning hospital. Most apartment
buildings have been destroyed. The
electrical grid doesn't work. What was
what little grid they had? There's no
clean water.
>> They've destroyed all of the the bazaars
for people to go buy food. Now they're
just set up wherever they can set up.
There's nothing left to destroy. So what
they
>> There's something that they did, right?
So So we you've seen this. Well, okay.
So, we've we've both been to war zones
and usually some buildings are survive
and that's what happened in Gaza from
the aerial. They started with the aerial
bombardment, but a bunch of buildings
survived. Then the IDF came in by ground
and they set up um they they detonated
and blew up using dynamite. They
demolished everything that survived.
>> Uh and then they came over and they
graded it with Earth movers. Um, and
they just flattening it all out to turn
it into a giant construction site,
right?
>> So, is this simply the idea is they're
going to just build on top. But if it
Why would they not want to keep any of
the old buildings? I mean, wouldn't it
save money if they're planning to steal
the land, ethnically cleanse it? I'm
100% convinced that that's been their
agenda all along. Yeah. if that but why
not keep any of the old infrastructure
or do or is this really like also like
psychologically we're going to erase any
trace that these people were ever here
no one's ever going to be able to say
that wall over there was here before
>> that was my family home that's all
that's left yeah no I think that's what
I think that's why they're doing it
they're doing it because you know in the
west we see articles all the time their
memes on Facebook or where have you of
um you know Palestinians standing
outside a house that used to be theirs
and there are these Israeli settlers
from New Jersey that are living in it
now and I think that they just don't
want that to happen. I think they intend
fully and this is this is you know
ethnic cleansing it's a genocide to
bulldo everything so that nothing is
left and build it back from scratch. I
hope I'm wrong. I really do.
>> I don't see how you can be. I mean,
because nothing else makes sense. Yeah.
I mean, they're literally willing to
spend more money
>> to do it this way.
>> A lot more money.
>> I mean, if you think about a city like
Constantinople, which is, you know, is
it like you can see all the layers of of
history there.
>> Oh my god. Yeah. You can still see you
can still see the the walls of the
ancient city. You can still see remnants
of the original chain that the
Byzantines ran across the the Golden
Horn to stop ships until they paid their
toll.
>> That's right. Yeah. No. So cool. And
they tried to Yeah. Sultan uh Sultan the
Met had to remove that chain so he could
get him to conquer in 1453. So cool.
That's at the military museum in
Istanbul. Um but anyway, the point is
it's like you can see all those layers
of history in every city that's been
through a war. I mean, even in
Hiroshima, right, there's the there's
some buildings that survived the uh the
the atomic bomb,
>> but the Israelis really are. I mean,
this, by the way, that's genocidal in
character. Like, erasing all traces that
a culture ever existed there. It's Nazi
style.
The Nazis used to do that in Jewish
neighborhoods where they'd burn
everything down, bulldoze everything, uh
because they didn't want it ever to, you
know, that used to be the Jewish
neighborhood.
>> Yes. Yes. That's right, man. It's
heartbreaking. And it just never gets
>> Thank you, Nadia Margaret, for becoming
a monthly supporter for us.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Much appreciated. She's number two,
assuming she's a she. Um All right. And
if you're not a shei, I apologize. Um,
unless you're becoming a she, in which
case I don't apologize. So complicated.
Um, so all right, I guess we're gonna
we're gonna leave Gaza there or um is
there anything else to talk about there?
Are we
>> there? There was a switching to politics
for a minute if I could. I was curious.
I almost called you yesterday
>> because I wanted to get your opinion on
on um
>> Oh, I know.
bird.
>> Kamla Harris is not running for governor
of California.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and and she was just so completely
and utterly insincere in her
explanation. Um she said that um she
just needed some downtime and she needs
to write a book about her experiences.
Of course, she's not writing a book.
They've already hired a ghostwriter. Um,
but she she needs to think about this
book and she wants to travel around the
country and meet some of the people that
she did not have a chance to meet
because the campaign was so historically
short. And I thought, "Oh, you are so
full of shit." And I had forgotten how
much I had forgotten how annoying that
nasally nagging voice is. Oh, I never
could. And she sounds Yeah, she she
would sound insincere ordering a beer
and a burger at a restaurant. I mean,
she Yeah, she's got a very
>> cloying kind of mean, you know, mean. Um
Well, so so okay, we know she's not
running for governor. I knew she wasn't
going to run for governor. I my friends,
you know why? Because being governor is
hard work.
>> It's hard work. And have we learned
nothing from Richard Nixon in 1962?
>> Right. Right. you you won't have Kla
Harris to
>> kick around anymore. My mother wore a
cloth coat.
>> So, yeah. So, she's not running for
governor. Um, that's not surprising.
Now, everybody's saying, "Well, she'll
run for president again." I don't think
so. I don't think I don't think that's
it at all. I don't
>> If she has a half a brain, she won't run
for president.
>> She won't.
>> She didn't even make it to the Iowa
caucuses the first time.
>> No. No. It would be it would be
catastrophic. Uh she didn't get much
love here from uh and I think even
within the Democratic party, she's just
not I don't even think she could get the
nomination.
>> I don't either. I don't either.
>> There's too many better candidates. Pete
Buddhajed is the man to beat in 2028. If
you're a Democrat in my opinion, um I
think they're gonna they want to
nominate him. He's the DNC pick, I
think.
>> God, I I hope you're wrong, but
>> but I think you're right. And I'll I'll
add too that, you know, she's gonna have
Nsome to worry about.
>> Yes.
>> But she's gonna have Pritsker to worry
about, too.
>> Yes.
>> And Pritskar is a tough mean guy with an
unlimited supply of money.
>> She will not have Josh Shapiro to worry
about because he zionisted himself out
of the race forever and ever. He'll
never be in national politics. Listen, I
if even if Josh Shapiro and I agreed on
100% of the issues, I would not vote for
him just because he volunteered to serve
in the IDF.
>> Me, too. And then there's um what? Andy
Basher, who you know, if ever there was
a vice presidential candidate, that's
him.
>> He's the guy. He's the perfect one.
>> Yeah, he is.
>> He's he's already like set up a little
exploratory committee. He's already
raising money. He's been to uh New
Hampshire. He went two weeks ago.
>> He's a good pick for that. I don't think
she'll run for president because first
of all, she will be smart enough to
listen to all of her adviserss who tell
her you can't get the nomination. You'll
humiliate yourself. Yeah, it'll look
really bad. Just just don't. So, I think
she only has two paths. She can uh she
can either go to MSNBC.
>> Definitely.
>> I think that's too much work. She's not
a hardworking person. So I think she
ends up in a synicure in academia.
University of California trustee.
>> That's what she's doing now.
>> Provost at Pepperdine University.
>> Oh yeah. She's a visiting professor at
Stanford Law School right now.
>> It's the Hillary. She She's completely
cut and pasted from Hillary Clinton,
right? She's going on a listening tour.
That's what Hillary Clinton did when she
ran for Senate from New York when
everybody hated her and they were all
gonna v vote for the guy from Long
Island instead. Right.
>> Um, whose name escapes me right now. Um,
Rick Lazio.
>> Rick Lazio. Oh my gosh. I haven't heard
that.
>> He was a sacrificial lamb and she almost
and he almost ate the big bad wolf from
>> he almost beat her. That's right.
>> And uh well, you know, he was he's
actually a very likable guy. Uh and um
so I could see why he he kind of did
better than they expected. But yeah,
she's and then of course Hillary was a
professor
>> at at Columbia University School of
International Affairs.
>> That's right. God, I hate to think of
those diplomats of the future being
trained by that heartbeat.
>> Oh my god.
>> Um, Houdini says she'll she'll be on the
board of some Fortune 500 company. You
bet she will.
>> Maybe. No, it won't be one. Several of
them.
>> It'll be several. Yeah. Yeah, that's
right.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, Michael Gardner says Pritsker is my
governor and I think he'd be a great
candidate.
>> Yeah. A couple of people are are saying
nice things about Pritskar. I like
>> he can donate to himself, too. He's rich
as [__]
>> He He's a billionaire. Yeah. I I like
Pritsker and I like the Pritskar family.
They've They've done a lot of good
>> stuff. Oh my god, Dana.
>> Maybe she'll end up on the view. Oh,
that's that's good. He wouldn't have to
work except she'd have to be up really
really early in the morning.
>> Hey, getting back to Buddha Judge for a
second. Michelle and I when we had our
show on um on Sputnik, we used to [__]
on Buddha Judge at every opportunity
just because this guy
>> because he's a worm.
>> He was the worst transportation
secretary in American history.
>> Mhm.
>> And he had he had opportunity after
opportunity after opportunity to do
something right. But the the train
derails and spills chemicals in East
Palestine, Ohio. He's on vacation in
Portugal. The the trains go on strike.
He's on vacation in Brazil. Uh what was
it? It was some other strike.
>> Don't forget he took six months off for
paternity leave. Paternity leave
>> in his first year in office and like you
could say and it's not like you know
they got knocked up accidentally. It was
a surrogate. It was planned.
>> Exactly. Exactly. Yes. So,
>> so yeah, I I mean this guy I listen he's
he's brilliant. He speaks 55 languages
or whatever. He speaks like eight
languages or whatever.
>> Yeah, he's he was a road scholar. Um
he's a decorated, you know, military
guy. Awesome. Very very smart.
>> Worst in the military, wasn't he
basically a supply clerk? He was like
Radar O'Reilly, wasn't he?
>> Oh, was he?
>> Yeah. I don't think he would. I mean, I
think, you know, he he saw I don't think
he saw many shots fired in anger.
>> Oh my god.
>> You know, but here's the thing. Okay, so
I think people will look back and say
like I did. I always I always made fun
of Mayor Pete because it's like they
made a guy who was the mayor of
Southbend, Indiana. Yeah. The head of
the US Department of Transportation.
Now, here's the funny part. I looked
into this. So, the mayor of Southbend
doesn't control a single piece of mass
transit. As it turns out, Southbend has
a separate transit authority that is not
administered by the mayor. So, he had he
didn't have 0.1% in experience. He had
no experience, right? But, so that said,
um, no one's going to go back and say,
uh, what did you, you know, how come we
don't have highspeed rail? Right? I
think they're going to look back at the
train thing maybe and then he'll be
they'll be able to say, you know, this I
was under Biden. Biden didn't let anyone
do anything. He was [__] up and dying.
Yeah.
>> Then we might say, "Well, what did you
know about Biden?" And he'll say, "Well,
I was the DOT guy. I didn't hang with
him all the time." And that's fairly
credible. So, and we know that he they
hid him.
>> They hid Biden from Buddha Judge and
other members of the cabinet. I mean,
Pete Buddha Judge didn't see Biden for
two years. Did lay eyes on him,
>> but that's actually quite common. Do you
remember when Ronald Reagan greeted his
own Secretary of Housing and Urban
Development with hello, Mr. Mayor? And
the guy had been the secretary of of HUD
for eight years.
>> Well, he sat in this in the in the
cabinet meetings with him. You would
think he'd be like, who's the guy down
at the end other end of the table past
the defense secretary? Right. But yeah,
no, it's Cap Weinberger. Um it's very
like uh but still I think so here's the
brief for Buddha Judge. I think
handicapping it politically. Uh I think
the brief is he's Obama 2.0.
>> Yeah.
>> So he's professorial. He's calm.
>> Very very intelligent.
>> He's intelligent. He doesn't sound
anything like Donald Trump. Every
election is a reaction to the last
president. Um and so and for the So he
gets the nomination I think easily
because the party's obsessed with
identity politics and making history.
Okay. We tried ladies not once but
twice, lost. got to go back to a dude,
but we can't just have a white dude. Oh,
but he's gay, so we can make that work.
And he's not queeny or flamboyant.
>> No.
>> So, it'll be fine.
>> That's that's that's how he gets the
nomination. That doesn't get him to
1600,
>> but it gets him the nomination.
>> That's my take.
>> First of all, thank you, Firmware Chip
from Wake Forest. Thank you for that
generosity. Um, and and there are a lot
of really good comments here about, you
know, he he is a vet who's not draped in
the flag, which is refreshing. He's very
intelligent. He's the anti-Trump in like
practically every way.
>> True.
>> Um, he's a great speaker. Um, he would
be able to go toe-to-toe in a debate
with with Vance.
>> True.
>> Jay Vance is a good debater.
>> True. Oh. Oh, yeah. He he just he ate
Kla Harris,
>> but being gay I mean
>> I mean you know
>> what what about like the the Bernie
Trump
>> Tim Walls. He ate Tim Walls. That's who
it was.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um what about the Bernie
Trump voters? People who voted for
Bernie and then voted for Trump. They're
not gonna they're not going to vote for
a gay man. I I don't think
>> I don't think Well, I don't think Buddha
Judge isn't going to get the progressive
left of the Democratic party. And that's
why I wouldn't
>> unless he needs but he he can still but
he won't he's he's a DNC pick so they
won't let him come out against Israel
and they won't let him come out in favor
of like uh you know Medicare for all the
Bernie stuff. If he can grab the the
progressive stuff
>> he's in in like Flynn.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I don't know.
>> We need we need somebody who's a who's a
bonafide progressive.
>> Yeah. Who's the highest ranked? I'm
trying to think who's the highest ranked
um openly gay American politician. Um
we've had a bunch of congressmen. Um we
had we had a closeted senator from
Idaho.
>> Well, we've got
>> same thing.
>> We've got
>> the senator from Wisconsin. I forget her
name.
>> Oh, right. Um Tammy Baldwin or whatever.
>> Tammy B. Is it Tammy Baldwin who's gay?
>> Oh, is it the other one? I think so.
>> Yeah, I think it's the other one.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh you know what? I don't know. To
answer your question, do we have any gay
governors?
>> That's a good question.
No one's I've always I've always thought
uh I've always thought that uh Ronda
Santis was closeted, but that might just
be his voice. I don't know. People
thought that I was gay, too. It's like,
you know, when I used to have open mic
Friday, open mic day on my old radio
show in LA, the one open mic question
was always, "Ted, are you gay?" Always.
And I didn't want to deny it because I
thought that would be like homophobic
like you know. Sure. Sort of like nah.
So I just be like I don't want to talk
about it. I'm not gonna say yay. I'm not
gonna say nay. Yeah. Tammy Duckworth. I
don't know if that's her.
>> Is it Tammy Duckworth?
>> I don't know.
>> No. Tammy Duckworth is the war hero,
isn't she?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, you can be you can be
gay and be a war hero.
>> No, but I mean but she lost her legs and
she's from Isn't she from Illinois?
>> God. Um, have to I'm gonna I'm gonna
look this up like
>> Okay. The lesbian senator is Tammy
Baldwin.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Tammy Baldwin from Wisconsin.
>> Too many Tammy.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Lots of Tammies. And and the
new senator from uh or the new what is
she? The governor of
>> Good point.
>> Arizona. She's by
Peter Teal is gay and more powerful than
any politician. No doubt.
Yeah. I don't know. I I I don't really
focus. You know, I said to my I said to
my daughter not too long ago, one of the
things that I admire about this
generation is that is that they don't
stovepipe themselves into these
these, you know, gay, straight, by this,
that
>> I I I'm from the stove pipe generation.
I am too.
>> I can't I can't relate to the whole like
>> it's hard. I don't know. I don't fully
understand it.
>> Like I I I have to admit I don't believe
in people are gender fluid. I mean I
know it's true. I know people who know
people who swear that it's true, but I
can't believe it. It's like okay, so if
it's 10 o'clock in the morning, um
feeling like uh I'm gay and if it's like
10:45, I'm straight and maybe I don't
want sex at all by, you know, by noon. I
don't know. I just don't get it. There's
>> I don't care, but it's just weird.
>> There's a guy that that we worked with,
Ted. I I'm not going to out him, of
course, but um over dinner, he just
casually said that he was pansexual.
>> Oh, right.
>> I said, you know, I've I've heard the
term. I I'm not sure I fully understand
it. And he said, um he said, I'll I'll
have sex with anybody that seems
attractive to me. Men, women, women
dressed as men, men dressed as women.
He said, it makes no difference to me.
Uh I I knew a Russian guy who did not
work with us who used he I remember
hearing him talk to someone like that
and he says you are not you are
omnivorous. You are greedy.
>> All right. I mean you know as long as
long as they're over 18. You guys do you
I don't care.
>> Well I I have a very short story I have
to tell. So there there was um there was
an editor that we used to work with at
Sputnik years ago who I like very much
and who I sat next to um them. Okay. So
um
one day
when he was a he came into work with
just a little bit of blue eyeshadow and
I thought, huh, that's kind of
different. All right. Well, none of my
business. And then after a couple of
weeks of that, um, came in with a blouse
and blue jeans and I thought, "Oh, okay.
They're transitioning. Okay." And then
after a while, it was very stylish
dresses and, you know, woman. And then
he changed his Twitter bio to she, her,
and then later to she, they. Okay. So,
I was asked to give a speech at the
Venezuelan embassy the night that
we broke off diplomatic relations with
the Venezuelans. So, I I was there with
a bunch of people. There was like a riot
outside and this young woman came up to
me and she said, "Hi, John. We haven't
met, but my name is, you know, Mary. I'm
so husband. I'm sorry. I'm so and so's
wife. And I said, "Oh, I'm sorry. I
didn't even know they were married."
So, we had a nice little chat. I go to
the office the next day and um
and our colleague comes in and says,
"Hey, I heard you had a chance to meet
Mary last night." And I said, "Oh, yeah.
We had a lovely conversation." I said,
"I apologize. I didn't know you were
gay."
and they say, "I'm not gay."
And I said, "Oh, I'm sorry, but your
your Twitter bio says that you're a
woman and you're married to a woman."
>> So,
I said, "Well, I thought that meant
>> by definition,
>> yeah, that if you're a woman and you're
married to another woman that that
you're gay." And
he says, you know, it's your generation
that wants to put labels on everybody.
>> I was like, okay,
>> okay. Well, there's just there they are
words. I mean, it does not matter.
>> Yeah, that's pretty funny. Um,
>> all right. So, we've got a little
another ad and I think and there's one
last story that uh I want to talk to you
here. I'm going to read this. I'll do
you want to do the ad or I can read the
ad.
>> Oh, go right ahead. I don't have it.
>> Okay. When Rumble first started in 2013,
they built a platform for the small
creator. They didn't censor or have
biases. They were fair and treated all
creators equally. No one thought
platforms would censor political
conversation or censor opinions on
COVID, but they did. Facebook admitted
they fell to pressure from the Biden
Harris administration. Rumble did not.
They held the line. They're attacked
daily for giving us a voice to talk to
you. They're attacked in corporate
media. They're attract They're attacked
by governments like France. They're
attacked from brand advertisers who
refuse to work with them. Corporate
America is fighting to remove speech.
Rumble is fighting to keep it. Rumble
won't survive with band with brand
advertisers. They don't get much of it.
It's watching the show on Rumble is the
most they can ask from you. But if you
really believe in this fight and you
have the means, one major way you can
help Rumble survive is by joining Rumble
Premium. Join the community that
believes in the First Amendment and
believes in our human right to free
speech, Rumble's offering 10 bucks off
with the promo code studio. When you
purchase an annual subscription, go to
rumble.com/premium and use pro promo
code studio. Like I said, if you have
the means and believe in the cause, now
is the time to join Rumble. Um, and I
think that's okay. I guess that's it for
that ad. All right. So,
>> uh, John, I wanted to talk to you about
microlastics. Uh, I know it's not really
our wheelhouse, but why not?
Everything's our wheelhouse. So, a new
study came out that found that if you
just sit at home,
your body absorbs an average of 68,000
discrete microlastical
plastic particles every single day.
>> How crazy is that?
>> It's crazy.
>> But it's happening.
>> Look, I'm drinking out of a plastic
bottle right now.
>> Right.
>> Yeah. So we should I mean it's like so
many things that are going on in our
society and the political class doesn't
seem to even address it. I mean you
don't even hear Bernie Sanders talk
about this, right? I mean we need we
need political figures like you know I
loved how I had many problems with him
but I loved how Al Gore was obsessed
with climate change and took it upon
himself to educate the public. Um and it
didn't unfortunately do much but he
tried. Yeah. Um, you know, I I would
love to see whether it's Pete Buddha
Judge or some other candidate, hell,
Donald Trump, anybody,
>> JD Vance take up this cause, you know.
>> Yeah. And nobody is. And it's funny, the
experts are shouting it from the
rooftops. You're right. The politicians
aren't responding or reacting in any
way. And usually when there's this
consensus in in a community,
some politician is going to pick it up
as an issue and nobody seems to care.
They just accept it like, oh well, you
know, I was talking to a to a funeral
director the other day. That was my
phone, by the way, on the and now I
can't duplicate the sound. Anyway, um I
was talking to a funeral director who I
know and he told me that we eat so many
ultrarocessed foods over the course of a
lifetime that even some people who don't
get inbalmed
stay intact for years.
>> Oh my god.
>> Yeah. Because of all the preservatives.
>> That's disgusting.
>> It's disgusting.
I mean, this is where Well, I guess
look, honestly, part many uh
progressives voted for Trump because of
RFK Jr.
>> and and Maha. He's been really quiet. Is
this one of those things where there's,
you know, several possibilities? The two
big ones, I think, are either
>> Donald Trump just hogs the limelight and
doesn't let anyone else talk and or um
RFK Jr. is in the trenches rolling up
his sleeves and working on something big
and it's just not ready to be announced
yet.
>> Yeah, that may that may very well be it.
Yeah. And you know, I think that he's
still facing such push back from
Democrats.
Oh, you know what?
Somebody just wrote,
um, I bet John knows where to bury the
bodies. And I responded
>> and it rejected my response.
>> Oh, really?
>> Yeah. It says, "This comment will not be
posted to deprogram show."
>> That's awesome.
>> I said, "The mob taught me that you bury
them under somebody else's casket."
>> Oh, this is funny. We were talking about
Ed. Poor Edam mean he he wouldn't be
able to eat now.
>> No.
>> No. Oh my god.
>> Eat McDonald's and you'll be buried like
a pharaoh.
>> Seriously. so much for our McDonald's uh
ads that we were hoping to get. Um,
yeah, by the way, this is tr totally
true. Being a dive instructor, I see the
impact plastic has on our environment a
lot. It's bad. Like really bad. Pulled
out plastic straps from a turtle's
mouth.
>> I'm a diver. Um, John, and I I got to
tell you, um, even in just the 25 years
or so that I've been diving, um, it's
the reefs have gone from basically dying
to dead all over. It's really hard to
find a reef where there's any fish or
anything going on. Um it's uh you know
and and it's true like you can go to a
remote island uh where there's a
population of like a hundred in the
Caribbean and like the the side where
the current hits will be completely
filled with trash that uh and plastic
bottles that have washed in across the
Atlantic Ocean. Um it's you know it's
it's really really
>> Yeah, we have that plastic island in the
Pacific that Dana is referring to. It's
the size of Texas. There's one in the
Atlantic, too, now.
>> Oh, I didn't know that.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh my god.
Terrible. Well,
>> well,
>> yeah. No, it's uh it's it's pretty
I'm not I can't even like comment on
that one. Um All right. I'm trying to
think. Is there anything else that we
need to talk about here? Oh, I guess
we'd be remiss if we didn't talk about
uh Trump repositioning those two nuclear
submarines. So we could that lead out
bring it out with that one. Um, do we
care about that? I mean, or is that just
I mean, how important is that, John? I
>> I don't think it is important. It's It's
meant to intimidate. Um, but like I've
said in the past, if if we're serious
about about a fight, we reposition
entire carrier battle groups. A couple
of subs are just meant to sort of piss
them off, maybe scare them a little bit,
that they're not going to be scared. But
it it was just what what a president who
is kind of impotent in this in this
situation might do.
>> It It just seemed completely symbolic. I
mean, I was also like I mean, do you
think Vladimir Putin woke up one morning
and like Joe Biden forgot about our
ICBM's arsenal?
>> I mean, if we want to nuke them, we
can't.
>> Seriously, right? Seriously.
>> Oh. Oh, not the submarines.
>> Yeah. Oh, I'm scared now.
>> Now, now they're angry.
>> All right, John. Um, I think we're gonna
leave that there. Yeah.
>> Well, I want to say thanks again to
everybody. Thank you for your
generosity, for spending this hour with
us every uh every other day, soon to be
every day. We literally can't do this
without you. So, thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Seriously, thank you. Um and so again,
Monday, Wednesday, Friday, 5:00 pm
Eastern time. I'm Ted R. That's John
Kiyaku. drogram. We'll be back Monday at
5:00 pm and uh we'll deprogram you from
uh all the news and the spin and
[__] about the news that breaks over
the weekend. Thanks again and take care.
Good afternoon. Thanks for joining us.
You're watching DProgram with me Ted R,
editorial cartoonist, CIA whistleblower
John Kuryaku over there. I'm pointing
the wrong way because on my
>> No, no, you're right. Yeah, that was
right.
>> He's backwards.
Nice to see you, John.
>> Ted, kudos on that music.
>> Oh, well, I wish I could take credit for
it.
>> I enjoyed it.
>> I I picked it from uh hopefully we don't
get into any copyright problems, but
these are that's YouTube's officially
sanctioned copyright feel free to use it
music. So, it should be a okay. uh you
know
>> as uh someone who uh
>> good stuff
>> is uh is is always into uh intellectual
property. I make my living on it. Uh I'm
very respectful of other people's
copyright.
>> Um John, we have a lot to talk about. So
we should probably dive right in. We
France uh as we talked about and we
anticipated has decided to uh formally
recognize Palestine as an independent
state, exchange ambassadors, the whole
thing. We're get into we're going to get
into that and all the political
ramifications. Uh we've got to talk
about the uh Democrats who are uh
raising the alarm about the masked ICE
agents in their unmarked vehicles. Um
they're going to try to see if they can
conduct some oversight from the minority
side of the aisle. I'm not sure if
they're going to get anywhere with that.
>> Good luck.
>> Gain Maxwell's lawyer says she didn't
take the fifth on anything. Uh that she
answered every question um
flesomely and wholly and uh honestly.
Um, she seems to be jonesing for a
pardon, but like the cartoon of the fat
lady raiding the refrigerator. She might
be looking for love in all the wrong
places here. Um, Trump uh wants to
basically signed an executive order uh
making it illegal to be homeless.
>> Yeah.
>> How do you like that?
>> It's Well, I wish he could make all
sorts of things illegal. I you know, I'm
already I'm already working on a cartoon
about this. um you know he can do an
executive order for everything. Um
anyway so uh we will talk about the
ramifications of that. So let's get into
it. Um French President Emanuel Macron
um had a conference next scheduled for
next week that was supposed to be
concerning the Israel Palestine crisis.
Uh, and it basically fell apart. and it
looks like he decided to um sort of take
to turn um a lemon into lemonade and
basically pull the trigger on something
that he's been toying with for a long
time which is to join the ranks of the
many countries like uh Spain um Ireland,
Russia, China, Saudi Arabia, many others
and most of the world that have already
formally recognized um the uh the pal
the Republic of Palestine. Um, I've been
arguing, John, with my friends that this
is a big deal and huge.
>> We're going to look back and say this
was a turning point for the people of
Palestine that uh it's hard to really uh
overstate.
>> Um the you know and I think that comes
down to the fact that France used to be
until very recently was the most
important diplomatic country. All
diplomats had to learn be fluent in
French. French,
>> which other no matter what country they
were from Frana until maybe the 1920s or
30s, you weren't really considered an
educated American if you weren't fluent
in French.
>> That's right.
>> And so it's like now my friend Scott
Stantis says, "Well, was is the key
word."
>> And it's a point, you know, he's he he
it's true that maybe but I don't think
France can be ignored. I think much of
the world when it comes to diplomacy is
going to be looking to France. I think
so too. And among European countries and
especially European Union countries,
France is a major leader along with the
Germans.
>> The Germans have thrown their lot in
with the Israelis. The French are
showing real leadership here. I think
you're right, Ted, that we're going to
look back on this decision as a turning
point. It's one thing for the Irish to
recognize Palestine, which they did back
in February, I think it was.
All that did was piss off the Israelis.
But but it it threw a bone to the
Palestinians that was really worth its
weight and gold. We we expected that to
happen because the Irish have been
oppressed, you know, throughout their
history. France though, I mean, France
is one of the historic uh colonial
powers in the Middle East. Uh that's why
they speak French in in Syria and and
Lebanon, for example,
>> right?
>> But for the French to go out on a on a
limb like this and say enough is enough.
We're recognizing the state of
Palestine, which you're correct in
pointing out uh includes an exchange of
ambassadors
and presumably French diplomatic support
at the United Nations. Remember, France
has a Security Council veto,
>> right? I wish they could veto the
American vetos.
>> I wish they could too. This is huge. It
really is. The question now is who's
next,
>> right? That is the question, right?
Luxembourg, um,
and Italy, Portugal all seem to be
lining up.
>> Yes.
>> Um, there will be others.
>> There will.
>> And yeah, they're permanent. And, you
know, they're a G7 country. They're the
only uh I guess uh well Russia and China
are in the G7. Well, no, they were
>> No, they were
>> they were um but yes, the only G7
country. So, it's the only permanent
member of the security council. Yeah,
France is a colossus here. Yeah.
>> And um a major power in the Middle East.
Um yeah, I don't think you can overstate
this. And you know um you know it's
probably the most important move of
Macron's presidency.
>> Agreed. that and his recent lawsuit
against Candace Owens, although we can
talk about that later.
>> Now, I do want to take note of Benj I
mean, not surprisingly, Benjamin
Netanyahu was displeased by this move,
but um the way that he expressed his
displeasure on X was particularly
interesting. He deplored the fact that
uh France was recognizing a a
Palestinian state right next to Tel
Aviv.
Well, the Palestinian state was always
going to be right next to
um so unless he knows something about
the laws of physics or he's engaged in
ethnic ethnic cleansing.
>> Ethnic cleansing because they want this
state
>> is talking about
>> Yeah. They want this state to be either
on an Indonesian island or in in a a
piece of Albania that would be locked
off.
>> Right.
>> That's exactly what he's what he's
alluding to.
>> Yeah. He doesn't want it there. Yeah.
>> I mean, and he didn't say, you know, I
mean, if he was a temperate uh person
and leading a a normal government
instead of a gangster regime over there
in Israel, he would have said something
along that goes more like, you know, of
course, we would be the first to
recognize a lawful uh dulyeleed
democratic republic of Palestine. And we
would be proud to work hand in hand to
help rebuild as neighbors and friends.
We just can't possibly work with Hamas
who have attacked us without
provocation.
That's what you would hope he would have
said. But there's no pretense here,
right? We don't. Now, he didn't say
recognize a terrorist state, recognize a
Hamas state to recognize a Palestinian
state right next to Tel Aviv.
Oh my god. You know, I remember when I
was a kid watching an episode of uh 60
Minutes in which
it was like Azer Viceman, who who was
the defense minister at the time, was
showing the 60 Minutes crew from a
helicopter
um
historical Israel, right, without the
West Bank. And at the narrowest point,
it's nine miles across from from the
line of the West Bank to the
Mediterranean Sea. Nine miles. and he
says, you know, we can't live with that.
They can cut off the nine miles and just
choke us and it would be the end of
Israel. So, we have to have the West
Bank. And even as a teenager, I was
like, are you guys out of your minds?
>> They want lean strom.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> I mean, it's so much it's amazing how
much they sound like the Germans. I
mean, it really is.
>> I mean,
>> yeah. You know, it's kind of like, you
know, I've had pro-Zionist friends
criticize me for that and making that
comparison. I'm like, well, if the jack
boot fits, wear it. You know, I mean,
>> Hunt Eli makes a good comment here, Ted.
We should probably address it,
especially the the last sentence there.
The world isn't always going to prop up
Israel. And I think that's what we're
seeing the beginning of right now. These
are the first cracks,
right? the first cracks in global or at
least western support for Israel. You're
right, the United States will try. The
United States is going to be the last
country to support an independent
Palestine, the last one.
>> But this is the beginning of it. And and
like Ted said at the very beginning of
the show, I I don't think we can
overestimate the importance here.
>> Yeah, I think I I think uh Hans Eli is
right. I think you're right. Um, and you
know, in terms of the I I agree with
Hans's question here, the first part of
it as well, isn't the Israelis
unwillingness to go along with the
two-state solution and trying to go for
the whole shmear?
>> Yeah.
>> They're unwilling to have any kind of
state solution.
>> Yeah. No, they don't want they they like
they like the current state of affairs.
>> They do.
>> And uh they and yeah, it will lead to a
one-state Palestinian solution. Um, you
know, Israel was I mean, it's funny.
Israel, I would say, I I've often
thought was like a uh an outdated,
obsolete solution to a non-existent
problem. Now, uh but maybe it made sense
in 1948. I actually don't think it made
sense in 1948. I mean, in 1948,
you know, the the Brits were withdrawing
from the Raj from India, the most
important colony they had. That's right.
And within 20 years pretty much every
major European power was out of Africa
or on their way out of Africa. Um and so
I mean basically the colonial experiment
that this really was I mean this really
is the goes back to 1920 and the and it
goes back before but it goes really as a
colonial experiment to the Balffor
declaration of 1920 which was a British
colonial adventure at the peak of
colonialism but by the time it got done
colonialism was out of fashion and was
and done
>> and like and here we are. It's the last.
I mean, you could argue that Puerto Rico
is a colony or or or Guam, but I mean,
this is the last settler colonialist
experiment. Puerto Rico is not a a
settler colonial experiment. It's the
locals who live there. We just govern
them.
>> That's not saying it's right or wrong.
>> Yeah. Right. Right. And actually, even
even the Puerto Ricans are split. You
know, a third a third a third. Uh, a
third want to be a state, a third want
to be an independent country, and a
third want to leave things just the way
they are.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I did, and I'm glad Lulu
brought this up because I was about to
mention it also, which is that Israel,
the last country to support apartheid
era South Africa.
>> Yes,
>> man. They, you know, they know how to
pick them. It's like apartheid era South
Africa and we're going to be their last
friends. I mean, yeah, we are going to
be their last friends. It's going to be
sooner rather than later. Um, it's going
to be really hard uh to for each
European country to domestically the the
the domestic unpopularity of the state
of Israel is just going to blow away.
John, I got to ask you about these
horrific photos that have surfaced in
the last 48 hours of of tiny children
>> um who have become tinier due to famine
who have been reduced to skeletons. It
reminded me of the famous footage from
Ethiopia during the famine half a
century ago when I was a kid. Um,
Somalia, places like that. Um, you know,
I mean, so in those situ I mean, you
could argue that all famines are
man-made. Irish potato famine, um, etc.
But this is the most man-made famine
outside of the of the Warsaw ghetto that
we've seen in a long time. I mean, five
miles away from all where this these
people are where surgeons are are
collapsing because they themselves are
starving to death and BBC journalists
are starving to death and dying. Um, now
people are, you know, eating couscous
and and hummus and
>> Yeah.
>> and drinking, you know, sweet red wine.
>> That's right.
>> This is I mean, there's plenty of food.
There's no shortage of food.
>> I said that earlier today in an
interview. There's there's plenty of
food. We see these pictures of children
starving to death. We're seeing reports
of surgeons in the middle of performing
surgery, passing out and fainting from a
lack of food. There's plenty of food.
>> The Israelis just won't allow the food
in. And when they do allow the food in
and people mob the distribution centers,
the Israelis then just open fire on the
crowds, which they've done at least
three times in the last two or three
weeks.
>> Oh, more more. It's almost every day,
John. Sickening
>> and and it's like and so I mean, so you
know,
>> well, let me interrupt you for a second.
Here's a good here's a good point. I was
talking about this for with a friend of
mine, Brillard Definit, sorry, I don't
speak French. What about the Egyptians?
The Egyptians are under real pressure
today to open the border. They have said
that they're not opening the border
under any circumstances. they open the
border, they will be complicit with the
ethnic cleansing.
>> Exactly.
>> Iraq in a hard place.
>> They are. Do you just let people starve
or do you jump in on the side of the
Israelis and cleansing Gaza?
>> [__] Israelis. That's what they that
they did this on purpose.
>> Yeah, they did.
>> And and the and the and the Egyptians
aren't stupid. That's why they built
that burm over a year ago.
>> That's right.
something like they're worried that the
Israelis will throw open the border and
then you know they won't be able to to
resist their troops aren't going to
aren't are not going to want to and will
not shoot two million people.
>> For the last couple of years I've
donated money to a Palestinian medical
relief organization. Not a not a lot of
money. If I have an extra 50 bucks, I
send it in. And um and I got a an
automated email from them um telling
people to stop donating because there
are no hospitals in Gaza now,
>> right? There's nothing to donate to.
>> There's nothing to donate to.
>> Yeah. This reminds me a lot of um so
like from 1996 to 2001 when the Taliban
were running Afghanistan the first time
they um there were there were Clinton
administration trade sanctions against
the Taliban in Afghanistan. But they
always said no no no no it's not medical
supplies or food. We don't prohibit that
at all. And when I was there the first
time in 2000 and I visited a hospital um
and the doctors and I found this to be
true at other hospitals too. They were
like, "We haven't seen a band-aid since
the early 90s." Um, and it's like
nothing. Nothing at all. It's like it's
field medicine. They It's basically like
you're outside
>> a mash unit,
>> but you're inside. Yeah. That's That's
it. You have a roof that may or may not
leak. That's That's what you've got.
It's a It's a nice tent, basically. Um
>> Oh my god.
>> So So, but John, about these pictures,
um, you know, I think you and I are
about, you know, we're experienced.
We've seen a lot of [__] We have many
of us here who are watching and reading
have too. But these these pictures
landed hard with me in a surprising way
and you know pictures thousand words all
that. It could really I mean I I get the
impression this is going to
>> things
>> it makes a difference. I think Macron
saw those photos and was like this is it
done. He was already on the way and I
think that's and I think that's it. I
mean, it's just like no one wants, no
one cares anymore but October 7th, you
know, but the Holocaust. No one cares
anymore. It's like you're out of you
guys are out of excuses. You have to
stop.
>> Ted, um,
I have a friend,
we've been friends for 20 years, and he
posted on Facebook, he he's not just
Zionist, he's a dual USIsraeli national.
and uh he posted on Facebook yesterday,
this happened in the last 24 hours.
Roads, Greece, Israelis blocked from
from uh coming off a cruise ship, Cedos,
Greece, Israelis targeted by angry
Greeks, Cyprus, Israelis had tomatoes
thrown at them. And it was like 10
things.
>> Gossins would love to have some tomatoes
thrown.
I took a picture of a child starving to
death in her mother's arms, nothing but
skin and and bone, and he blocked me.
That's what we're up against here. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> yeah. They don't care if children are
starving to death. They don't care.
>> They don't. And you know what's funny?
Getting back that I'm still haunted by
that Brett Stevens column from a couple
of days.
>> Yeah. Day before yesterday. And and you
know in there he talked about like well
you know yes there some people who say
it's a genocide point to the genocidal
comments that were made by his
high-ranking Israeli officials in the
days after October 7th. But they were
just being inmperate. They were being
spicy. They were just angry about
October 7th. Okay. So, if that had if
that were true and that was not the
official policy of the Israeli
government, which we know it is because
all the journalists have reported that
it is, but let's just say that, you
know, we're going to pretend here that
Brett Stevens is telling the truth.
>> Yeah.
>> Those people would have been fired.
>> Yes.
>> You know, if President Kuryaku of Israel
doesn't let those people stay on like,
what are you doing? That's not what
that's not who we are. Please leave your
ID at the door. That's just not I mean
that's I mean left them in there.
>> And remember we're talking at uh we're
talking about Smootrich and uh Ben
Gavir.
>> They were successfully prosecuted for
felony hate crimes against Palestinians
years before ever becoming
>> ministers in the Netanyahu government.
These are very bad people.
>> They are very bad people and they should
really be. I mean honestly um people
went to prison at Nuremberg for less.
>> Yes, without a doubt.
>> I mean Yes. I mean hell one guy just he
went to I think he killed him, right?
Julius Striker. He just published
newspaper.
>> Yes.
>> You know granted it was a nasty piece of
work but it was just a newspaper.
>> That's absolutely right.
So
>> yeah, I'm I'm worried about where this
uh is going in that I think a whole lot
of people are going to starve to death.
Women, children, the elderly, all
civilians, they're going to starve to
death.
>> No question. They are.
>> Yeah. The US is not going to put
pressure on Netanyahu. It's just not. We
know what our government is like. And
I'm not saying this is specific to
Donald Trump. The Democrats are exactly
the same way.
>> Absolutely.
>> Um, so it's not it's not going to get
better in the near term. It's just not.
>> No, I mean, look, we're in a world where
even AOC can't beed on accounted upon to
uh resist sending war funding to Israel.
I mean,
>> yeah,
>> even even just from a fiscal
conservative standpoint, you should be
able to say, you know, little birds,
we've been feeding you since 1948.
>> Time to fly the nest.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> that's right.
>> Yeah, without a doubt.
>> Um, is there anything else we want to
say about this?
>> I mean, Trump says that this is
interfering with his peace efforts.
There are no peace efforts, right? I
mean, there's I mean, basically, it's
very strange. Um, there's been the two
delegations in Qatar or Qatar, whatever.
>> Yeah, we should we should add that. We
should talk about that. The US walked
out
>> yesterday. The US walked out saying that
that Hamas is not serious about hostage
releases. It's like, seriously, that's
that's what the talks are about, hostage
releases.
And and why is it that we call Israelis
held by Hamas hostages and Palestinians
held by Israel prisoners?
>> That's a good question.
>> When they haven't been charged with any
crime, they were just scooped up only
because they happen to be Palestinian,
>> right? Because Israel is a nation state
and we love them. It's sort of like why
if it's Iran, it's the regime. If it's
France, it's the government.
>> It's, you know, all this loaded
language.
>> That's right. So there there are no
peace talks right now. We walked out.
They're on hiatus and they weren't
accomplishing anything anyway.
>> No. And you know, there was a piece in
today's times and we weren't and this is
not really on the agenda, but whatever.
Like we care. Um Russia Ukraine and it's
brought up a good point. Yeah. that
really peace negotiations haven't really
begun in earnest. No. And that's true
about Israel and Palestine. I mean, and
basically talked about shuttle diplomacy
back during the Henry Kissinger era and
whatever whatever many bad things you
want to say about Henry Kissinger. He
was uh never you know he certainly was a
hardworking dude. Sure. And he went back
and forth all the time.
>> Sure. Philip Habib in the 80s. Same
thing. It was a very like it was an
arduous prolonged long process to end a
complicated war between nation states.
Um you know I mean look Hamas was really
a government a real government.
>> Yes.
>> Um you know and
>> in fact the Israelis the Israelis use
the the Hamas Ministry of Health uh
numbers.
>> Yes. They accept the the Hamas numbers
on people killed or wounded or whatever.
>> Yeah. It's only the Zionists in the
United States who pretend like they're
not true. You can't trust them. They're
they're right. They're an undercount. Um
>> yeah.
>> I don't either.
>> Um Wow. Uh yeah. No. So for sure. Um the
Israelis are sitting on top of thousands
and thousands of uncharged political
they're political prisoners is what they
are and subjected to all sorts of
humiliating treatment. Um so yeah peace
talks um
you know I mean we're not gonna there's
no chance because you know the Israelis
the Israelis aren't serious and people
will say well what about Hamas? Well,
any in any kind I say in any kind of
lopsided military conflict, most of the
burden of making peace falls on the
superior military force. Um, they're
going to have the advantage. Um, you
know, I mean, they're going to have to
make most of the concessions. Um, you
know, in terms of getting close if you
want to have a ceasefire anyway. Um, I
know people will say end of World War II
or whatever, unconditional surrender.
That war went on. I I never, you know,
never I wasn't there, but I would have
never agreed with the policy of
unconditional surrender. I think it
dragged World War II on much longer than
it needed to.
>> I think you're right.
>> And th those days are gone.
>> That's just not how how conflicts end
anymore.
>> No. Now that now you like like Saddam
Hussein, you go hide in your spider
hole. You leave weapons behind and then
an insurgency pops up and you know,
nobody ever admits that they were
defeated. Hell, right. Trump did admit
he was defeated.
>> Yeah, that's true.
>> So,
>> Tom Ford
How in the world did Robin Hood know
that these were Tom Ford glasses?
>> That's
>> I never even heard of Tom Ford till I
bought these glasses.
>> I never heard of Tom Ford
>> and they were like, "Oh, this is the Tom
Ford." I was like, "Okay,
>> what's the big deal about Tom Ford?"
>> I don't know, but I like them.
>> Are they pricey?
>> Uh, yeah, they kind of were. Yeah.
>> Glasses glasses cost ridiculous. These
were like $1,200. They don't look like
much, but
>> Yeah. Well, these were only seven 700
>> only,
>> but still, I mean, to me, that's a lot.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> It's absurd.
>> Um All right. Well, so I guess we should
talk about the ICE thing. So, um,
Robert, so Democratic, uh, House
Representatives Robert Garcia and Summer
Lee
>> are, um, demanding, they wrote a letter
to Christine, the Department of Homeland
Security to demand that she provide all
the information, internal DHS memos and
policies, uh, that concern how ISIS is
supposed to comport themselves, um, how
they're supposed to dress. Uh, I don't
know if there's a, you know, certain
color of mask that they're supposed to
wear. You know, white in the winter, I
don't know. Pink for the gay ice
members. I don't know. Whatever. Um, but
they're they're trying to get all that
info. Are does does DHS have to reply?
>> No. Um, it's a that's an executive order
function. They don't have to reply. And
I'll tell you, one of the things I
learned when I was uh on Capitol Hill at
the Senate Foreign Relations Committee
is most of the time
cabinet members uh just ignore us. We
would write letters to secretary of
whatever
or assistant secretary or the FBI
director or the CI dire. They would just
ignore us.
>> And what are you gonna do? Is it worth
going to the mat over the fact that they
ignored the letter from your staff
member? No. So, yeah, I don't think
they're going to get any satisfaction
here. I'm still laughing, though, Ted,
at the uh at the reporting in the LA
Times that that tow truck operators are
are following these ICE officers and
towing their cars because they always
park illegally because they think they
can do whatever they want because
they're ICE. And then as soon as they
get out to do their raids, the tow
trucks tow their cars and impound them.
And after all, it's not like they can
extend any professional courtesy to
these random unidentified people
>> unidentified.
>> How are we supposed to know that they're
federal law enforcement officers?
Although I mean, are I officers really
law enforcement officers?
>> Well, you know what? That's a good
question.
>> Agents,
>> they're they're not really law
enforcement officers. Just like Bureau
of Prisons, prison guards are not really
law enforcement officers,
>> right? They're not. I mean, they're
they're either what's called a series
1810 or 1811. In this case, they're both
1810s, which means they're allowed to be
armed, but that doesn't necessarily mean
that,
you know, like they're not going to pull
somebody over for speeding. They're not
going to they're not going to likely not
going to disrupt, you know, the the the
a shoplifter at the Walmart if that they
happen to be in.
>> Could they? I'm not even sure.
>> I remember there was some strange
experience that the university, this was
analogous, maybe a University of
Cincinnati campus policeman
>> pulled over someone on a city street for
running a stop sign and it led to a
violent um you know incident where there
was a you know that the dude shot the
motorist. Um, it was it's like one of
those like shootings of black motorists
by a white cop. And I was like, can a
University of Cincinnati, you know, rent
a cop really play real cop? I mean,
aren't you like Paul Mart cop Paul Mall
cop? I mean, to me, an ice person, I
mean, look, if they want to be treated
like real law enforcement officers, they
ought to wear uniforms and they ought to
show their faces and they should show
ID. I mean, as far as I'm concerned,
they're just random thugs.
>> That's it. I I have to agree. Um, you
know, somebody makes a Where did I just
see it? They went to Fletzie. Uh,
Houdini. Uh, they've gone through Flexi,
which is the Federal Law Enforcement
Training Center. I went through Flexie
before my CIA days. I was a But I was in
1810. So, we did the handgun training,
but I was 100% not considered law
enforcement.
>> Oh, so you don't necessar So, going to
Fletsy does not necessarily What does Do
you know what Fletsy stands for?
>> Yeah. Federal law enforcement training
center. I I had a beautiful shiny gold
badge that I kept in this beautiful
leather case. I really regretted having
to turn it in when I went to the agency.
Um, and it got me out of a couple of
speeding tickets.
>> Mhm.
>> But, uh, I I was not considered law
enforcement. I didn't consider myself
law enforcement. And, um, and I would
not have tried to stop a shoplifter at
Walmart.
>> I would have said, "Well, it's not my
job. Let the next guy do it."
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it's like I mean, I
think it's funny how uh ICE people, they
want our sympathy, too.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't care
at all.
>> I mean,
>> I told you I I told you on on the
morning of January 6th.
>> I think I said this like a week ago. I I
had to go up to Capitol Hill to meet
with Bruce Fine. And we knew all hell
was going to break loose later in the
day. So, I wanted to, you know, get into
Bruce's office, sign this document, and
get the hell out. And so, um, when I
parked my car, there were all these guys
taking off their Bureau of Prisons logo
polos and putting on black shirts. And I
was like, shame, shame, shame. You
clowns aren't law enforcement.
>> No, not as soon as you do that.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. No, it's gross. All right. So, uh,
I guess
>> can I interrupt you,
>> please?
In all seriousness, what do you think
about this Candace Owens situation?
Candace Owens has been on this rant for
the last three years
where she has been saying that Emanuel
Mcronone's wife was born male and um
she's just she even did a documentary
about it. There she has no childhood
history. No documents exist, no photos
exist. Of course, none of that's true.
>> That can't be true.
>> No, it's just not true.
>> I I literally just spent like my son
doesn't know I realized was filling out
forms and doesn't even know like where I
was born. I'm like, you don't know [__]
about your family. So, I decided as a
gift I'm gonna create a giant I did a a
family tree, right? I put all this
information that I've been meaning to
put together. I started putting it
together. I got it. I went down a rabbit
hole through the French and German
government uh genealogy sites. Very
cool.
>> Go back four or 500 years, right? We
know like if if you you know in this
country, in France, in Germany, in most
countries, like uh you know, we know
where you were born, when you were born,
when you got married, which church you
got married at, you know, who you got
married to,
>> who who baptized you, where and when you
were baptized.
>> It happened in 1611. And so like Yeah.
in and in France. I guarantee you that
uh you know Emmanuel Mrs. Macron is she
was a it's not a dude looks like a lady
situation.
>> No, she looks like a woman and she's
obviously clearly born a woman. So
anyway, it turns out
>> not to mention she was very cute when
she was younger.
>> She was cute and has a son
>> meeting up her her husband,
>> right? And has a son. So, so
the Mcron, it turned out, through their
attorneys, approached Candace Owens a
year ago and said, "Stop doing this.
It's not true, and we're going to sue
you."
>> But she doubled down.
Nobody knew this until a couple of days
ago that she had been warned to back
off. And she doubled down. And she said
that in part she doubled down because
she became she converted to Catholicism
and her Catholic faith
demands of her that she out you know
this man who is masquerading as the
first lady of France.
And so the Mcron filed the defamation
suit. Now
>> where?
>> Yeah, that's a good question. I'm not
sure
>> where would be better for them.
England.
>> Yeah, that would be the best.
>> I really wish I'd sued the LA Times in
England. I could have because of the
internet and so um and I should have
>> even though you know would have required
me to go to England quite a bit.
>> Um wow, thank you. Uh we have a couple
of paid donations here.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> So we should answer right question. So
uh we'll we'll go in reverse order here.
>> Um obscuro
obscure orca. Yeah,
>> John NATO bombing of Yugoslavia.
>> Yeah. You know what? I was
>> about
>> I was stationed in Athens at the time
and it was absolutely miserable not just
to be an American diplomat in Greece,
but to be an Orthodox Christian American
diplomat while the United States
government was bombing an Orthodox
Christian country that the Greeks
considered to be brothers.
Um, it was absolutely miserable to the
point where
even one of my uncles attacked me
verbally at a u at a dinner
and I could barely respond to him. He
was like, "Why the [__] did you blow up
the Yugo factory? What the [__] were you
thinking you blew up the Yugo factory?"
>> That wasn't me.
>> And I said I said Theo. And I almost
didn't want to answer him. I said they
converted it to manufactured tanks,
which was true, but the bombing of
Yugoslavia was wrong, wrong, wrong in
the first place. And we created this
this fake rump country called Kosovo
that has never otherwise existed through
the course of of, you know, human
history. And it just so happens to be
holy ground for the Serbian Orthodox
Church. and it's where most of the
Serbian Orthodox uh monasteries are
located. And we're like, "Yeah, tough
luck. We're going to we're going to take
this land away from you. We're going to
give it to these Muslims that you've
been feuding with for the last 1500
years. And there's nothing you can do
about it. Oh, and by the way, we're
going to bomb you, too, just for the
hell of it."
>> Of course. I mean obviously I have to I
agree with you but you know what about
the argument that this was to try to
stop the genoci this the genocide uh you
know in Kosovo.
>> Yeah that that is what it was for. Yeah.
Well less so the genocide in Kosovo than
what was happening well no it was it was
Kosovo by then. Yeah. Yeah. You know
what we should have done? It was
supposed to create like an a safety
zone, right?
>> Yeah. On but nobody ever said anything
about it being an independent country
five minutes later.
>> And I don't know and I I had access to
the information at the time, but it just
there was no information. Why did we not
work with Boris Yelton to figure this
out? Why were we at odds with the
Russians over this is the the the nater
of our of our relationship with the
Russians? Why didn't we do something to
to make it better?
>> Yeah. I mean, yeah. I mean, we installed
Yeltson basically.
>> We did. We did. We installed Yeltson.
>> Yeah. I mean, the Russians will never
forgive us.
>> No. And Ted, coming back to, you know,
serving in Athens in in 99 while we're
bombing uh Yugoslavia.
Every year we have to vacate the embassy
on the 17th of November because it's the
it's the date of the uprising against
the military hunda that we installed and
there's a massive demonstration
that marches from the polytenic
university where where the uprising
began to the American embassy.
So we just shut the whole place down at
12 and everybody goes home. You just get
a half a day off.
We evacuated the American embassy at
least a dozen times that year because
these demonstrations were absolutely
gigantic. And at the time, this is right
before the Greeks converted to the euro.
So they had these 100 drama coins that
are about the that were about the size
of a of an Eisenhower silver dollar.
>> And so you could fling them and they had
some heft to them. So they would take
these 100 Dramma coins which were worth
about a quarter 27 cents and they would
smash all the windows on the front of
the embassy and then they would fill
balloons with red paint and with
slingshots launch the red balloons at at
so the the next day the embassy is just
peppered with
>> red paint splotches and the windows are
all broken from 100 drama coins. It was
awful. It was miserable.
>> I bet. Hey, John. Uh, we got to answer
USC Arad 21 who donated five bucks.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, USC.
>> Uh, I don't want to put your pardon in
jeopardy,
>> John. Uh, but what are your guys take on
South Park going after Trump?
>> I I DVR it. It was freaking hilarious.
>> I haven't seen it yet.
>> Oh, you got to watch.
>> You got to see it. You got to see it,
Ted. Um, I I won't spoil it for you, but
you know, they the the creators of South
Park just a couple of days ago signed a
$1.5
billion
streaming agreement.
God bless them.
>> It's obviously for the high quality
animation.
>> You know, I still watch South Park. I I
will admit to you, I watch Family Guy,
Simpsons, South Park, and Bob's Burgers.
I love all the animated shows.
>> Thank you, Caleb. Also,
>> South Park. Thank you, Caleb. South Park
is by far the most cutting edge. Like
when I watch when I watch um uh Family
Guy with with one of my housemates, I
always say, "Oh my god, how can they get
away with a joke like that?" But South
Park, it's like, "Oh my god." Like, it's
shocking to me that they're able to do
what they're what they're doing. Now,
it's all for a good laugh. It's all
comedy, but I I just love it. I think
it's great.
Yeah. Well, I'm I'm Yeah. My favorite um
the thing that those two guys did that I
love the best is still Team America
World Police. I can never get over how
how I've seen it more times than I could
count. It's one of the funniest seen in
my life.
>> Absolutely hilarious.
>> Yeah.
>> I wish I could be creative like that. I
don't think I can be creative like that.
>> See, I think I could. Uh and I think I
do.
>> Well, you could be I wish I was in the
writer room, you know.
>> Yeah. and and you deal in in very um
sharp comedy. I mean, you're a political
cartoonist. You have to have that kind
of biting sense of humor.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> yeah, they are geniuses.
>> You would totally think. Uh but so many
of my colleagues are just uh you know,
they're wussies. Um it's because they
worked at Daily Papers and they were
scared and they were you know, I'll
never forget I got a job interview at
the Aspbury Park Press. He's dead now,
so I'll name him. executive editor Ray
Olworthther brings me into his office
and you know it's like one of those
things where you really feel like it's
going well and see I'm there for a good
hour. I'm feeling like ah this I'm going
to get this. And it should be pointed
out that I've been drawing for them
local cartoons for central New Jersey
for a year. So it wasn't like I was just
blowing off blowing in off the street.
Yeah. Like we've been dating now are you
gonna put a ring on it or not? And so
everything's going great. And then Rey
goes, leans back, points out the window,
and says, "There's just one more thing.
Am I ever going to look outside that
window and see people protesting because
of one of the cartoons you drew?" And I
said, I was I was flumxed.
>> I hope so.
>> I said, I mean, I was honest. I said,
it's not my intent, you know, when I sit
down to to make that happen, but I don't
care if it does. And like and people are
going to do what they're going to do.
>> Legit answer.
>> And people get mad at stuff that I never
see coming and other stuff that I think
is going to blow up the world. There's
no reaction. I I don't know. It's like
don't you have security? I mean, I don't
know.
So I was like I
that look like wrong answer till and you
know never got the job. And I had one
interview like another like that after
that St. Louis Post Dispatch same thing.
Sacramento be I'll never forget the guy
who goes he goes uh
>> thank you Gav
>> Howard Weaver he goes um am I you know
what I have to figure out here is if
we're going to let the good burgers of
Sacramento wake up to grounds glass
every morning on their opinion page in
other words if he hires me I'm like I
hope so you know that's that's what it's
for. Uh, so yeah, I mean I this could go
we could do a whole whole show on that,
but that's Yeah,
>> I've actually purchased their
>> [__]
>> I I purchased years ago their uh Mormons
episode that people are talking about in
the chat and I also purchased the um the
lice episode. You remember the lice
episode?
>> Yes.
>> Oh my god, so funny. I still laugh out
loud every time I watch it.
>> Oh my heavens. You know, I mean, it's
like one of my I mean, I have to say if
the animation were better, I would have
seen every episode. The animation's a
little rough.
>> It's terrible.
>> Yeah.
>> But that I think that's part of the
charm.
>> Oh, well, obviously. What's their 27th
season? I think they've kind of got it
figured out. Yeah.
>> It's just crazy.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh my god.
>> No. Not complaining about them. Um, but
I have every right, but I just don't
feel like it because I don't think it
would be true. All right, so let's see
what else we got to talk about here. Um,
yes, I did stuff to hit. Oh, yeah.
Gizlane, how do we pronounce her name?
>> Yeah, Gal. Galain.
>> Galain. I can never pronounce Gain. Me
Gain Maxwell. She um she's still her
prison photos. She's still hot.
>> Oh, she looks good. So anyway, so she's
so she So John, I'm I'm a little bit
confused by this. Like, so I don't
understand. I mean, I know that
obviously the heat is on uh on the Trump
administration over Epstein. I get it.
And but now is this just window
dressing? Are they just pretending to
look into it? I mean, it looks like she
requested the interview with the DOJ and
Dave complied and went in, had a wide
ranging conversation with her about
anything and everything. According to
>> She answered everything.
>> She answered everything. She seems like
some she could be per if she committed
perjury, she would be um she would have
exposure to the prosecution. Yes. And
could extend her.
>> It it was very risky to to answer these
questions.
>> To me, that indicates someone who's
probably telling the truth. Yes.
>> When you take a risk, it's uh sort of
like when you sue for defamation, then
that's right. Subject yourself to
discovery and everything. Um
>> so what so what is this about? Like why
did this interview take place? And what
was the desired outcome from both sides
and what's what's the actual outcome?
>> Well, we we this has to be speculation
because we really don't know.
>> Totally.
>> Thank you, Houdini, very much. And I I
I'm thinking that do you remember last
week, Ted, when we were talking about
the comment that that um the attorney
general made about the the videos being
just child porn and they will never see
the light of day. Pam Bondi said, "We
will never release." And I said, "We
don't want to see the child porn. We
want to know the names of the men
committing crimes against children.
That's what we want to know."
Um,
so
it could be that it could be that that
she's naming people who would be on uh
those hard drives.
>> Apparently that happened.
>> Yeah. Um
>> reportedly according to her council
>> much of the uh
much of the uh reporting has been on you
know these allegations and they're not a
stretch by any means that she wants a
some sort of a commutation even a pardon
and Trump being Trump um wouldn't rule
it out.
>> Well why would he give it to her right?
Doesn't he want her to shut up?
I can't I my brain can't wrap itself
around
what in the world would possess Donald
Trump to to throw her a bone.
>> Yeah. I mean, wouldn't he get wouldn't
he wouldn't he pardon her for being
quiet,
>> right?
>> You know, I mean,
>> not blabbing everything. And it turns
out that, you know, remember we were
joking the other day about it depends on
what your definition of a list is.
>> Well, apparently we were right about
that. And it turns out that some of the
names that are popping up are Bill
Clinton and John Kerry and a handful of
other people who are well known to every
single American. But the question
remains, who were the guys committing
crimes against children,
>> right? Like I mean, yeah. So this remind
So in the Mayflower Madam, you know,
>> oh yeah, I remember that case.
>> Oh, you're going back now.
>> Very old ' 80s. there was a very famous
little black book that belonged to her
that that made its way unlike the
Epstein files into the public eye. And
um and the thing is what was notable is
of course yeah she had her John's in
there and she had her girls in there but
she had a dry cleaner in there and she
had her Chinese food in there. I mean,
the point is that's what people do,
right? And and anyway, there so there's
we it's not I guess if like
>> you're looking for a spreadsheet that
says
>> my child sex client
XLS, it's not in there. Okay.
>> But that's not really the issue. I mean,
it's kind of like as usual, the Trump
administration is playing Well, like all
administrations, they're being they're
playing it too cute.
>> Yeah. Yeah, they are. That's right.
So, was Maxwell railroaded?
>> Oh, I don't think so. I think she was
she was guilty. I think that there were
a whole bunch of people who were guilty.
They shouldn't have gone after just her
and Epstein,
but uh but yeah, I think she got what
she deserved.
>> Okay, so she got what she deserved. I
mean, okay, she got what she deserved.
She procured for Epstein. We know that.
Now the question is basically what this
looks like to me is they partied a lot.
Um they they probably they had lots of
young girls around.
>> They passed them around,
>> right? It's not about necessarily a
honeypot operation. It's not about msad
necessarily or probably
>> it's probably just like gross dudes
drinking and doing drugs and having a
good time. Yep.
>> And doing [__] that's illegal and
immoral sometimes. Not all. Some of
them. It's sort of like you're at a
party and there's something going on in
another room and maybe you don't go into
that other room and maybe you do go into
that other room. I think that's what it
was like.
>> I think that's I think you've hit it on
the head. You know, there's another
thing too and this is a minor point, but
it's something that I've often wondered
about. I've spoken publicly a lot about
how pedophiles are almost always locked
up in low security prisons. They're not
eligible for minimums because they're
pedophiles, which means they're dangers
to society, but they don't go to mediums
or maximums because they'll be attacked
or killed or beaten or tortured or
whatever
>> people who are already there.
>> That's right. She's at a minimum
security work camp. How the heck did
that happen?
Why were the rules waved for her? Why is
she getting special treatment?
>> And what's your answer to that question,
John?
>> I don't know. I I don't have an answer.
>> It doesn't make any sense to me.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's the whole thing,
right? Like there may not be a
conspiracy, but when things don't make
sense, people fill in the blanks. And I
mean, and it look in all fairness,
there's weird [__] that happens in the
real world. I mean,
>> yeah,
>> you know, I mean, how the Concord
crashed is very strange. Um, right,
>> not a conspiracy, just a piece of metal
fell off a plane that was in front of it
and went to the engine and blew it up
and now we can't fly supersonic
transport anymore.
>> Michael Gardner says, "Rich get
different rules, even in prison."
Absolutely true. Listen to this.
There was a guy in the next row of cells
over from me. Oh, I can't remember his
name, but he was a quarterback for the
New York Giants in the early 1970s.
And he was a uh he was in for like 25
years for running this major massive
Ponzi scheme.
And you know, let's say he made a
hundred million and they made him pay 50
million in restitution. He still had 50
million left over. So what this guy did,
he was a real scumbag, too. What this
guy did was he paid off all the the
Mexican and black gangs to ensure his
safety, right? So he he, you know, paid
like $500 a month, I think, is what he
told me. Like $500 a month to the MS-13
shot collar, 500 to the Crips, 500 to
the Bloods, 500 to the Mexican Mafia.
And then he he hated the food in the
cafeteria. Everybody did.
>> But but he hired one of the Hispanics to
be his personal chef.
And so other guys, their their side
hustle in prison is they steal food out
of the cafeteria and they're allowed to
steal food. The the guards look the
other way. So he would spend his 500 a
month in the commissary that he was
allowed to spend and then he would buy
the rest of it on the on the black
market stolen from the cafeteria. and he
had this personal chef make him three
meals a day. So, you're right, Michael
Gardner. Rich people,
>> it's good to be king.
>> Yeah, it's good to be king. Rich people
are different. There are different rules
even in prison.
>> Wonder how it was for Martha Stewart.
>> Oh, everybody loved Martha Stewart.
Yeah,
>> she taught them how to make soap and she
taught them how to make little handy
crafts and
you know I I think Martha Stewart's
experience in prison was kind of like
mine where I'm still in touch with a lot
of the Italians. I I spoke to two of
them last night. We did a little Zoom
call to say hi. Um
there was a there was a crooked
congressman from Ohio who went to prison
a couple years before I did. He was in
my prison.
>> Oh, I remember that guy. remember him?
>> Trafficant.
>> No, no, this was after this was actually
the the district immediately south of
Jim Travocant.
>> Okay. All right.
>> I forget his name now. But anyway, he
said when he got out, he was in for like
two years or two and a half years. It
was a corruption charge. And he said,
"Oh my god, Clyde Hall." Yes, it was
Clyde Hall.
How in the world did you pull that up?
>> Must be an Ohio.
>> Wow. Wow. I'm Listen, man. RS, I'm
impressed. Yes, it was Clyde Hall. I
have not thought of that name in a
decade.
So, um, he got out of prison and he
said, you know, they say that, um, you
don't go to prison to make friends. And
he says,
>> I I came out of prison having made some
of the best friends of my life. And I
remember thinking at the time, this is
before I was ever in trouble, thinking
that he was nuts.
>> But he's not nuts. And I understand it
now.
>> Is it trauma bonding?
>> In part it could be, but but the the
people that you trauma bond with, you
tend to walk away from.
These guys were genuinely good guys. I
mean, some of them did some very bad
things. Like I remember one of them
saying, I said, "So, what are you in
here for?" And he goes like this. He
goes, "The cops
found a body in a barrel in my storage
unit.
I don't know how that body got in there.
I said, "No, no." I said, "I'm not
judging you.
>> Seriously,
>> happened to anybody."
>> He goes, "A hundred people had access to
that storage unit." I said, "I'm not
judging you. Don't worry, but uh yeah,
we're still in we're still in touch."
And um it's a strange place. Um how do
people get so jacked like bodybuilders?
That's a good question. And
I saw there are three three guys that
pop into my head immediately as like the
most perfect human specimens I've ever
seen in my life because there is
literally nothing to do but work out.
Nothing.
>> What about you?
>> I I walked I made sure to walk five
miles a day around the track. And when
it snows they close the track and you're
only allowed to walk around the
basketball court. So you walk around 500
times, you know, when I first arrived,
um, I was walking around with with a
captain from the Banano family. So this
is a very senior guy. And it was the
first really great advice anybody had
given me in prison. I had been there
about two or three weeks. And we're walk
it's it's pouring down snow. It's like
10° and we're walking around the outside
basketball court. And he he said to me,
"How much time did you get?" I said 30
months feels like 30 years. And he said,
"Let me give you some advice."
He said, "If somebody asks you how much
time you have, you say five years." I
said, "Why?"
>> He said, "There are guys in here with
20, 25, 30 years. If they hear that you
have 30 months and you're pissed off
about it, they're going to kick your
ass.
So tell them five years." Does anybody
ever ask to see your paperwork?
>> Only when
>> to find out if you're a child molester
or what?
>> Only when you first arrive to see if
you're a child molester.
So, I had to give my paperwork to the to
the shot caller for the Aryans. And um
and he he read the paperwork and he
goes, "Intelligence Identities
Protection Act." He goes, "What the [__]
is that?"
And I said, 'It's like it's like
a conspiracy charge.
And he goes, "Okay."
So I sat with the Aryans for a while
till the Italians took me.
>> Yeah.
>> At at meals.
>> Yeah. There are some guys who like will
just sit with the Aryans and then the
shot caller will go up and say, "Who the
[__] are you?" and give me your
paperwork. And then the smart ones will
just go sit with the pedophiles without
saying anything.
>> Some will just claim that they can't
find their paperwork or they'll have
their lawyer write a letter. It's like,
no, no, no. If you have any idea what's
good for you, you're going to get up and
move to the pedophile table right now.
And they always do.
>> Wow. Uh I mean, I think this is I have
have to put this question up. How bad
are the showers? We've all seen the
movies.
>> Yes. You know what? That was one of the
very few questions I asked my attorneys.
One of the things that my attorneys did
for me was they scheduled a lunch a
couple of weeks before I left for prison
with a former professor from George
Washington University who played fast
and loose with the National Science
Foundation credit card and got two
years. So the very first question I
asked him was, "What's the situation
with the showers?"
And he said, "Oh no, it don't worry
about that." He said, "It's nothing like
what you see on TV. You're going to go
to a low or a minimum, and they're all
individual showers, completely enclosed
with shower curtains. Same with the
toilets. They're all individual toilets
with shower curtains. Don't worry about
it at all." And he was exactly right.
And and I'll say, you know, one thing,
um, I never saw a guy naked in prison.
Well, that's not true. We we did have
one strip search once. Um, but you do
not walk around exposing yourself unless
you want to have like every bone in your
face broken.
There was a there was a an Afghan child
molester who uh came into my cell just
before I I left. I have an entire
chapter about him in my second book. And
um he went out to play soccer one day
and then he came back and we we had
these huge fans like a a 4ft tall fan
because there's no air conditioning in
prisons. And so the fan was on like for
months at a time in the summer. So this
guy went out to play soccer and he came
back and he takes off all of his
clothes. His his his clothes are
literally dripping sweat. It was
disgusting. And he goes up to the fan
and he's airing out his balls.
And I walked past him and I said,
"Sheir, you're going to get your ass
kicked. You can't." I said, "This isn't
a [__] country club. You're in
prison."
>> And he's like, "Fuck you. I don't answer
to you." Four guys were on him like
white on rice. They
>> left him in a bloody pulp on the floor.
>> At all.
>> Told you. [__]
>> And he's like lifting up his balls and
airing them out. We're like, "What are
you doing? Are you out of your mind?
>> People I mean it's always weird to me
when people are in situations like this
and they just don't know how to act. Um
I have I like this question where
criminals actually respected if child
molesters chomos are at the bottom
>> who's on top or does it work that way?
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. It very much works that
way. The chumos are at the very very
bottom. The rats are very barely above
the chumos. The Italians were at the
very top. very very top and you know it
was funny because of all the gangs and
they're considered a gang
>> mafiosos or Italians or is there a
differentiation?
>> Oh there there's a there's a difference
you have to be connected in some way
>> like they'll it they'll
the Italian network is very strong and
so they'll know weeks in advance that
you're coming to the prison.
>> Um
so
>> this is also an important
>> that's a good question. Okay that's a
good question.
change during and after your
imprisonment.
>> I assume your prison was like the
California system that I've read about
where everything is racially segregated.
>> Absolutely everything. You in fact at
higher levels you cannot
have any contact with other races
because you're then branded a race
trader and then you
>> you're not friends with say a Latino
just to be like
>> absolutely not can't play cards. I I
made a conscious decision when I first
arrived and I say that in my in my book.
I made a conscious decision to ignore
those racial divisions. And at the end
of my my sentence, the black shot
caller, a guy named Ali from Newark, he
was at the tail end of a 25-year
uh drug charge. He came over to hug me
and to tell me how much he respected me.
I helped him. I I wrote his resume for
him. I helped.
>> How did that happen if you weren't
allowed to?
>> Because I refused to respect those
racial divisions.
>> So you were Did you Did you get any any
[__] for that from whites?
>> No, I got [__] from the Hispanics.
And I was like, you guys all hate each
other. like the Mexicans hate the the
the Puerto Ricans and the Puerto Ricans
hate the the Dominicans and the
Dominicans hate the Costa Ricans. It's
ridiculous. I like you guys all look
exactly the same to me and you all hate
each other. I just never understood it.
Um, so the Italians were by far the most
respected and that was the point I was
going to make of the gangs, right? If
you're if you're in an organized gang,
MS-13, Bloods, Crips, Mexican Mafia,
Burachos, Nortenos, all these guys, your
prisoner number ends with the number
-47.
47 means organized gang. Well, the
Italians were also 47s.
Um, so of all the gangs, the Italians
were by far the smallest and by far the
most highly respected.
>> And what? And was there a charge that
was most respected like
like you know like in the hierarchy of
robbery, murder?
>> Rico Rico.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. Rico and Rico usually had murder
attached to it. Usually it was
conspiracy to commit murder because you
know a guy will murder somebody and then
20 people will get charged for it
because they're all part of the
conspiracy.
>> I'll tell you who who they didn't like.
They didn't like these these big rich
white collar criminals.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. Yeah. They didn't like those guys.
The only ones who, you know,
>> were they just viewed as soft and uh
>> Yeah. soft. Oh, you thought you're going
to get away with it. No, poor you. You
got caught and now it's like, "Oh, I'm
in prison. Oh my god."
>> So So it's a class thing. It's a class
thing.
>> It's a class thing. The only The only
guys who were in where nobody gave a
[__] was like arson. I knew three
arsonists and people people were like,
"Eh, arson. Did you kill anybody?" No.
Okay. Nobody cares. Like insurance
fraud, mortgage fraud. Uh, one guy was
property fraud, which I had never heard
of before.
>> Funny. He he just forged papers. Um,
transferring ownership of a golf course
to himself
and then he tried to charge people rent.
>> He's like one of those squatters with
the that write up the fake deed.
Exactly. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> It's kind of a big deal, right? It's
sort of like how car theft is uh you
know is is is a direct error to horse
theft and it's cons and you're basically
stealing a man's livelihood. So it's
considered
>> yeah not cool really serious. And
stealing a man's home is the same way.
Um this question from Nick. Um what are
our thoughts about all the recent trade
deals? the tra, you know, I I told my
sister this the other day. I can't
believe Trump is actually getting away
with it.
>> I know.
>> People were saying, "Oh my god, he's
nuts and the tariffs 100% and 50%. Oh my
god, he's coming to deals with all these
countries
and they're deals that favor the United
States." I can't believe I'm saying it.
>> So, yeah. No, I I I I don't have
anything to add to that. That's that's
very very very true. Um, all right. So,
finally, um, but maybe not least, um,
Donald Trump issued an executive order,
uh, stating that he's, uh, very upset
about the the the explosion of
homelessness.
>> Yeah.
>> The executive order actually understates
the problem. It says that there's
250,000 homeless people in the United
States. They're actually 770,000.
>> I was going to say, by a factor of three
or four. Yeah.
>> And and it's gone up a lot. That number
was 550 for years and then it shot up um
over really over the last four years
since since COVID and prices shot up and
uh people got priced out of housing.
That's not counting the millions who are
couch surfing
hidden hidden homeless. But he's he
doesn't care about that. He he said it's
a bad look in DC for foreign dignitaries
to see tent cities as they drive in from
Reagan airport. He's right. Um he he
says that it's uh you know it's it's
it's disturbing and dangerous for
law-abiding citizens to see people
pissing and [__] outside.
>> Yeah. Nobody wants to see that. But
you know
>> that's capitalism for you.
>> That's capitalism and you can't keep
cutting the budget and starting with
with services,
>> right? So, so, so here's what he So,
Donald Trump, I think, is really good at
diagnosing problems like, hey, factories
in the Midwest have closed and we
haven't retrained anyone and everybody's
just depressed and and poor and uh
addicted to opiates.
>> Yeah,
>> that sucks.
>> for me, but he's and he's right and and
honestly, that is not a small thing.
Being able to diagnose the problem is
very, very important. Like, I didn't see
Joe Biden doing that. I didn't see Kla
Harris doing that. Okay, good for you.
But Trump's very bad at coming up with
the um with the cure and the treatment,
right? And so here he want he's
basically the thesis here is that the
vast majority of public homeless people
are mentally ill, uh emotionally
disturbed, uh drug addicts, or some
combination thereof. That's probably
true. If they aren't before they get on
the street, they rapidly deteriorate.
I've seen that happen in my neighborhood
here in New York.
So what do we So the question is what do
we do about it? His answer seems to be
forcible commitment. Now I'm not the
kind of liberal who's going to say that
someone should has their has a moral and
legal right to sleep outside in
Manhattan when it's five below zero,
>> right?
>> No. No. I want them picked up,
>> dragged off and and taken somewhere, but
I want them taken somewhere safe
>> and nice and warm. I don't want them to
be abused, treated like [__]
humiliated, um attacked, raped,
whatever. So, the problem is that
there's no facilities here. So, it's a
two-part thing, right? We've got drug
addicts and we've got um mentally ill
people. And he's like basically reopen
the insane asylums like the old
Creedmore, you know, scandal from the
70s.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Where people were chained to, you know,
to their beds and stuff. Yes.
>> Well, the point is,
>> Mr. present. There are no facilities,
right? Where are you going to put them?
This reminds me of the mass
deportations. There's no facilities to
handle the mass deportations. There's no
facilities to handle the mass removal of
the homeless from American city streets.
I mean, where are you going to put them?
And and that goes double for drug
addiction. There's no treatment really
available. There's no services
available. If you want to create a
massive infrastructure, a massive safety
net to deal with these people, God bless
you and I will help you and I will
support you and I will scream it to the
heavens. What a great president you are.
But I don't see that happening.
>> No, I don't see it happening either. Um,
our our viewers are making a lot of
really good points here. First of all,
the the tent uh right behind the
executive office building. Uh there's
also another one now up at uh Union
Station. Same idea.
My guess is he'll find some pretext to
to move them out. Uh you know, Reagan,
well, it started really under Carter
where the Supreme Court ruled that
people could not be held against their
will if they were not a danger to
themselves or to others. But a lot of
them are a danger to themselves or to
others. And they're deserving of mental
health care.
>> Yes.
>> So what what do we do? Do we
>> do we make it easier to force people
into mental health care? And then on the
other side,
>> lots of abuse, right? I mean,
>> lots of abuse. I had when I was a little
kid, my neighbor, he decided that it was
like a lot easier and cheaper than
paying alimony to have this wife who was
perfectly wonderful and lovely and sane
forcibly committed. And she spent six
months at the local asylum in Dayton
before she managed to get out. Um, that
kind of [__] used to happen all the
time.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I mean, you don't want to make it
too easy,
>> but you don't want to make it too hard
either.
>> California suffered with that for many
years. many many years. And it was in
the 1970s that they finally changed the
law so that the police couldn't forcibly
commit you. Can you imagine the cops
just ring your doorbell and then by
force take you and put you in a mental
institution and there's literally
nothing you can do about it?
>> Well, I mean in in a sense in a sense
that does happen now. I don't know if
you've seen the Netflix I think it's
Netflix the movie we care a lot but it's
>> Oh, I have. Oh my god.
>> A real phenomenon, right?
>> Yes, it is. Like so basically um these
nursing homes they they they they
conspire to have power of attorney.
>> Yeah. And and and it's for people often
who've done ab who are perfectly fine,
nothing's wrong, but they target them
because they're rich and they're going
to take their money
>> and they do they take their money. Uh
but you know we we really we we spend
scandalously little money on mental
health and in fact
>> even though it's even though mental
health parity is in the Affordable Care
Act completely uninforced
>> completely uninforced and in most
counties I I read this I think at the
Rutherford Institute website um in most
counties in in America
>> forcing into mental healthare shall be
done after mental health care is vastly
improved if at all. If at all. Exactly.
That's right.
>> So, in most counties in America, there
are more mentally ill people in the
county jail than there are in mental
hospitals.
>> Yeah. Well, there just aren't enough
mental hospitals. And the mental
hospitals that are there suck ass.
>> Yeah.
>> So, um Yeah. I had a I had a friend her
um she discovered her ex-husband had
committed suicide. She walked in on him
>> and um and uh and found him. The guy had
almost took a butcher knife and nearly
hacked his own head off in his kitchen.
>> Oh my god.
>> Unsurprisingly, she freaks out, runs
into the streets of Brooklyn screaming
and screaming, you know, I want to die.
NYPD shows up understandably. They think
they have a mentally distraught woman on
their hand, which they did. And uh they
so they dragged her off to uh Belleview
um and and put her in like the padded
room. She saw her phone, so she called
her sister. Her sister came to visit and
her sister was like, "Honey, I know
you're really upset." She said in a
really low voice, "But listen, they're
going to keep you here unless you can
pretend like you're okay." Like, do you
understand what I'm saying? They're
going to keep you here like
indefinitely, maybe forever. You have to
get it together. Stop crying. Stop
sobbing. And just be like, "I'm good
now. I can go home and just keep it
together and so that they'll let you go
and she did. Um, and then she fell apart
later. But I mean, it's like that's
that's how it works.
>> There was even an episode of Lou Grant
about this. Um, I happened to see on
Hulu years ago where uh this
investigative journalist who was working
at the LA whatever it was called,
Dispatch,
um,
uh, got himself committed to a mental
hospital so he could write an article
from the inside. And
>> that's what that's what happens with the
Queen document.
>> Yeah, that's right. But he couldn't get
out.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Couldn't get out.
>> And they drug you. Yes.
>> So, yeah. I mean, they drug they drugged
the seniors and old folks home, too, to
make them compliant.
>> Yes.
>> And there's
so they weren't great before they showed
up and they're definitely not great
after that.
>> Um, they did it to my mom. I watched
them do it. I knew they were doing it.
And there's it was, you know, basically
when they say you need an advocate when
you're in there, they're not wrong. You
need you need to be there like all the
time. Um, I wanted to Yeah, this is a
good question actually. So there's a
border.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Border conflict, right? Thailand and
Cambodia going on right now. It's not
like war in the Southeast Asia has ever
been a problem for the United States. So
maybe we don't need to talk about it.
>> Uh but in all seriousness, um Thailand
deployed an F-16 across the border into
Cambodia and uh it took out artillery
positions. They claimed that they were
retaliating. This all boils down to a
goes back to a treaty from 1907.
>> Yeah. by the French colonial power that
set that border as usual. The text so
this is fascinating as a graphic artist,
right? So the text of the treaty says
that basically the the the border
follows the natural flow of the river,
but the drawing that went with it that
some Frenchman in 1907 drew doesn't
really do that. and it puts this temple
that's uh on the Cambodian side of the
border and the Cambodians are like thank
you and everybody went with everybody
went with the with the drawing and as
graphic artists I agree with that 100%.
But you know I think actually under
under most treaties you look at the
words and um and the ties are like well
we're looking at the words [__] the
drawing and so that's what this is all
about. It's like art versus text.
>> Crazy.
>> And um and it's about this this temple.
>> Um this this seems like maybe not a big
deal, but it's not not a big deal
either.
>> Tell you the truth, I didn't even
realize that the Cambodians had a
military.
>> Oh, really?
>> Seriously? Yeah.
>> Well, it got really over Well, the Cime
Rouge got overrun by the Vietnamese.
>> Yeah,
>> that was a long time ago.
>> Yeah, sure. Sure.
>> It must not It must not be much of a
military. It it can't be. And they still
have all those minds all over the place.
Yeah. When I when I first saw this, I
was like, "Wait, what?" And then I had
to I had to reread it like, "Okay." And
they're they're firing at each other
across the border, too.
>> Yeah.
>> This happens between India and China
every few years.
>> That's true. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Kind of major war over it in 192.
>> Um and then there's uh Yeah. Yeah. That
like a few years ago, right? drunken
border guards.
>> They drink a lot up there. Nothing to
do.
>> Things get out of control.
>> That's what I always say is like that's
why that's why Putin never wanted a NATO
country on his border. He knows about
drunken border guards.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> And then the next thing you know, you've
got like French nukes headed your way.
>> Crazy.
>> With Article Five of NATO. Uh we were
asked, and I'm sorry, I apologize to
whoever it was who asked this earlier in
the chat, but I'm going to do a call
back. I hope you're still here. Um, what
do we think about Trump's reversal on
NATO? He used to hate it. Now he loves
it. Well, you know, Trump's always
flip-flopping like a fish on his dock.
>> Um, what do you think?
>> I think he really believed that Vladimir
Putin would do what he told him to do.
And I think he's just so angry that
Putin won't just go to the negotiating
table and settle this thing with Ukraine
that now he's got to embrace
NATO. He's got to otherwise he's going
to be out there all alone.
>> Well, this is like this is what we were
talking about earlier, right? I mean,
it's like diplomacy takes [__] work.
>> Exactly.
>> I mean, Bill Clinton, I know neither of
us supports supported his actions in
against Serbia, but I do have to hand it
to him. You know, the date I love the
story about how the Dayton Peace Accord
came to be, right? So, he cleverly
brought the three leaders of uh Serbia,
Croatia, and uh um who am I forgetting
here? Um Kosovo.
>> Yeah.
>> To uh to date
>> uh to the Air Force base, right?
Patterson Air Force Base. And you know,
having grown up there, I I'm pretty sure
uh Bill Clinton was aware of the fact
that it was one of the most boring
places in the United States. So he's
like, "You got you got you guys work on
this, you work it all out, then you get
to go home." And anyway, so he left them
there. And they were kind of kept
prisoner.
>> Yeah. And
>> but he but he did give them soccer
balls. I remember that.
>> But he but they were getting really
desperate. And finally he was like, I
tell you what, there is a French
restaurant called Low Bears. It's just
south of D South Dayton. It's the only
French restaurant in Dayton.
You guys, you fellas can all go down
there and you can have a good meal, but
you got to sign you got to sign the
agreement.
>> And uh so Slaban Malloic and the rest,
they were like, "Man, I gotta have me a
good meal. Dayton sucks." So they so
they all signed and um and and like so
they I grew up like you know I don't
know quarter of a mile from Lil Bear um
and they so I used to walk by it on my
way on my way from my house my mom's
house to uh to my school every single
day and anyway so they they went to
Loberish and and and had a nice kind of
old-fashioned too much sweet sauce you
know old style French place it's gone
now at Town and Country Shopping Center
and And they had they used to have a
seating chart like with, you know, they
showed like where all of the diplomats
sat.
>> That's cool.
>> Where Clinton was and all that, what
what type of wine they had. But I always
always like I laughed at that. I was
like, "This is like French food
diplomacy. We're hungry. We can't eat
this shitty base food anymore."
>> No. No. It gets to be too much.
>> Yeah. And by the way, uh, totally true.
Uh, two toes.
>> Yeah. That's a surprisingly excellent
museum.
>> That is big. It's not like a, oh, pop in
for 30 minutes and you'll see
everything. That's a half day event and
it's good. I mean, it's also got a
strong uh aeronautics aspect to it also.
Um, and also uh and also all the the
space stuff is amazing, too.
>> Um,
>> yeah.
>> So, someone I lived in Dayton then. The
story back then is that Mallik insisted
something needed to be signed.
I think it was Clinton, but I don't
know.
Who knows? Who knows? All we know is
that people were hungry. They ended up
at Loberge.
>> Indeed.
>> But um yeah, and it was a boring place.
Um but anyway, yeah, I love that story.
So um so let's talk a little bit before
we should wrap it up. The um the the the
the homeless executive order.
>> Yeah. Um,
this could be an opportunity for
Democrats to say, "You know what, Mr.
President, you're right. Homelessness is
a is a national shame for the world's
richest country. Um, we shouldn't have
anybody sleeping outside. Let's let's
work together on this. Um, that's that
can't happen, right?"
>> No. Yeah. There was a piece in the post
today saying that, you know, it's all
fine and good to sign an executive
order, but the the truth of the matter
is that this is a a state issue and he
might be able to to fiddle with what
little federal funding there is, but
there's nothing he could do to force,
you know, tent cities to be removed or
to force people into mental institutions
or whatever. He can't do anything. Now,
if he wants to make a proposal to take
abandoned or mothballled military bases
and turn them into housing for the
homeless where maybe they can undergo
some job training, get mental health uh
care,
whatever, and then be reintroduced into
society. I guess that's something else.
But I think this is mostly talk.
>> I agree. Yeah. I mean, I don't think
it's one of those things that can get
done this way. Very I think we could
maybe ask answer this last question. I
think we need to and then we should be
on our way and start our weekends. So
what do you think what do we think about
Trump saying Obama could be arrested
over the Russia election scandal?
>> Well, thanks thanks to Donald Trump
going to the Supreme Court. A president
can't be arrested for anything.
>> Correct.
>> Issues done closed.
>> If it was ex Yeah. All that Obama would
have to argue is that he did it in the
exercise of his functions as president
of the United States.
>> Yes. Now, John Brennan is another issue.
Just before we started this show, I
interviewed um Matt Taibbe for for my
other podcast, Deep Focus, and Matt says
I I I sort of lamented the fact that
that what the Justice Department um has
had referred to it is um misdemeanor
charges against Brennan and Comey. um
related to allegedly lying to Congress.
And he said, "Yeah, that's true." But he
said what he's hearing now is that they
are actively pursuing felony conspiracy
charges against at least Brennan and
maybe Brennan and Comey.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. And I'll tell you what, I
mentioned to you offline the other day,
I will go to Brennan's trial every
single day.
I mean it
>> with a big fat grin on your face.
>> Karma is real and she's an evil [__]
>> And I think that's a perfect place to
start our weekend.
John Kuryaku, thank you so much as
always. It's a pleasure to be here with
you.
>> Yeah, it's always fun. Uh we're we're
we're deeprogram. We're going to be here
again next week. Monday, Wednesday,
Friday 5:00 pm Eastern. Maybe we should
try for the week the the whole every day
the week after maybe. But
>> sure, we could try that.
>> Okay. All right. So, Monday, Wednesday,
Friday, Eastern 5 o'clock. Um, please
like, follow, and share the show.
Seriously, please share it. Like, you
know, just find the link and pass it
around. Massive thing for us. We're
trying to get it. I mean, the numbers
are definitely go in the right
direction, but um, anything you can can
do to make them go there even faster
would be much appreciated. Um, as
always, thanks for your questions. It
was always fun to answer them. We have
the best fe the best viewers. Love you
guys. Take care.
>> Thanks everybody.
>> Hey there.
>> I'm Ted R and I'm here for a D program
along with John Kuryaku. Uh, he's the
CIA whistleblower. I'm the editorial
cartoonist. Uh, thank you so much for
joining us. It's Wednesday, July 30th,
2025. It's 5:00 pm on the East Coast.
Thanks for joining us on the Rumble
feed, on the YouTube feed, and
everywhere else you're listening also to
uh people just listening to the audio.
We appreciate you, too. Please like,
follow, and share the show. Lots to talk
about today, as always. Um, we talked
about that this might happen, John. I I
didn't think it would happen this fast.
>> No way.
>> The UK is almost certainly going to
recognize Palestine at the UN General
Assembly this September. Well, that's
our lead. Uh we're going to be talking
about interesting news out of Iran where
Iran's leading the way in abandoning US
tech, namely GPS. And uh you know, we
could see a lot more of this kind of
thing coming in the very near future
from all over the world. Um super
interesting uh look into the future. Um
is Israel losing the American right? The
evangelicals who've been their loyal
supporters. Marjorie Taylor Green is
criticizing the Gaza war as genocide.
She's right, of course, but it's amazing
to hear her and people like her saying
anything like that. Um, two CIA related
stories that there's no way I'm going to
let you off the hook, John, from talking
about. Tom Sylvester is out at the CIA
and uh Sandy Grimes, the lady who caught
Aldrich Ames, died at the age of 80.
We'll talk about her legacy and we'll
talk about breaking news and anything
else that comes up. And of course, if
you have questions, please put them into
uh the feeds and we always pick up on
them and post them and talk about them.
But uh we've got lots of stuff to talk
about. So Kirsty um he kind of like gave
it kind of give some people are
interpreting this as a wussy move but he
basically said he'll recognize Palestine
uh in September unless uh Israel comes
to its senses and agrees to a ceasefire.
They've been the ones who've been
breaking all the ceasefires up until
now. And um so you know obviously
Israel's not going to do that. So, by
definition, the UK will will join
France. And there's a whole pel of other
countries who are interested in doing
it, too. So, let's get to it.
>> Yeah. Let's let's start, if you don't
mind, with Tom Sylvester.
>> Oh, thank you very much, Marble.
>> Let's do Tom Sylvester.
>> I just want to get this out of the way
because we have so much to talk about
related to uh to Gaza. Tom Sylvester is
the uh the CIA's deputy director for
operations. And in that position, he's
you can argue the number three or number
four U official in the CIA. He's in
charge of all CIA operations around the
world. This is a job that every CIA case
officer aspires to. Um and by all
accounts he's been very um popular uh
among the rank and file. Well, if you've
been the deputy director for operations,
your final pre-retirement job is
normally that you're named station chief
in London. That is the one job that
everybody in the CIA aspires to.
Everybody wants to be the station chief
in London. So he was named station chief
in London um several months ago,
but over the course of those several
months, he gave an interview to Tim uh
Weiner, who uh is the the Pulitzer
Prizewinning author of several books on
the CIA. Uh there's one coming out soon
called the mission that um thank you
Eric
that um several outlets are excerpting
and
apparently
CIA director John Radcliffe didn't like
the fact that he spoke with Tim Weiner.
Now, normally the director of the CIA
will instruct his officers to to work
with with authors, especially with Tim
Weiner. But whatever it is that Tom
Sylvester said, it apparently pissed
people off. And so the job was
unceremonious unceremoniously yanked
from under him. He will not be the CIA
station chief in chief in London. Uh,
Director Ratcliffe informed MI6
apparently yesterday that Sylvester will
not be the CIA station chief in London.
And so today, Sylvester announced his
retirement effective immediately. He's
just going to take his pension and go
home. Now,
most of the time,
senior officers, even if they're
disgruntled,
will keep their mouths shut. The fact
that he's already spoken to Tim Weiner
makes me think the story's not over.
We're going to hear more. Uh so that's
that.
>> So my fathering
>> my father worked in government
specifically in the US Air Force for for
years at at the upper echelons and he
told me and John tell me if this is
correct that um usually when you know
you're about to retire that's your one
chance to vent and blow up. you know,
you're going to retire anyway and you've
had stuff that you wanted to say. You've
got one big thing you want to do,
someone you want to blow up, some boss
who was an [__]
>> and then this is when you do it and then
you you retire and they can't get you.
Is that basically what what happened
here?
>> 100%. 100%. And I I'll tell you my own
experience. My last tour
uh when I resigned from the agency was
at the United Nations in New York. And
um my station chief, Mary Margaret
Graham, and I did not like each other,
even not a little bit.
And so
a couple of days before I I left, she
threatened me. threatened me with with
putting out what's called a burn notice
against me.
>> Oh,
>> I saw that TV show.
>> Yeah, she she threatened me with a burn
notice and
I laughed at her. I was in her office
and of course she had her little witness
there, the chief of operations who was a
just a little dwarf. So, um
I said uh
I said I'm not afraid of your threats.
burn notice. I said, "Come on. You
forget that when I made this recent
recruitment,
you congratulated be me by telling me to
take petty cash and go get myself a
blowjob."
I said, "What do you think the
Washington Post would say about that
>> or the New York Times? Because as God is
my witness, I'm gonna call them and tell
them."
>> And she immediately backed off.
>> Wow. So, uh,
>> by the way, I do want to answer, uh,
maybe you can answer this question. Um,
Marble is asking, "Why is London a
desirable post?" It's like the top post,
right? It's the post
>> because you get a gigantic mansion to
live in. You get a chauffeer driven um,
uh, Jaguar limo that that they drive you
around in. You have the largest
entertainment budget of any station
chief in the world. Nobody's trying to
kill you there.
>> And MI6 is the closest um alliance,
right? Intelligence ally that we have
>> without any question. MI6 CIA is the
closest friendship in the world.
>> So it's like it's analogous to in the
State Department, right? Ambassador to
the Court of St. James. It's the same
kind of thing. It's the job.
>> Yes. Exactly right. It is the job. I
mean,
>> it's like for an editorial cartoonist
like New York Times, you know, like
that,
>> right? And and so Hans, I absolutely
positively did not. I've never paid for
it in my life and I'm proud to say that.
So, although we all pay for it in
different ways, that's
>> nothing's free as my working girlfriends
used to tell me. But even at lower
levels in London, like I I did I I've
spoken about this operation I did with
Christopher Steel back in 2000 and my my
I was in Athens at the time, but I would
travel to London every week. And then my
counterparts in the station um who were,
you know, just whatever GS12, GS13,
GS14,
uh they were living high on the hog,
too. you're living in Nightsbridge or
you're living in in Paddington and this
beautiful uh muse house and life is good
and like I say people aren't trying to
kill you on the way to work.
>> Gota love that
>> refreshing.
>> Um how by the way what do you what do
you think of uh Tom Sylvester and what
do you think of Tim Winer? Tim Weiner
Winer Weiner.
>> Um you know honestly I like them both.
Uh Tom Chilester was a was an inspired
choice to be the deputy director for
operations. The guy's been he was a
station chief I don't know six times,
seven times all around the world. He was
a specialist in Soviet and then Russian
um operations and um and really
quite the good uh ops guy, careerlong
ops guy. Spent almost his entire adult
life overseas.
Uh Tim Weiner I actually have a great
deal of respect for. I gave him an
interview uh for his his previous book
about the CIA and he treated me with
great respect. So um I you know
>> I read that book. Yeah. It's a it's a
solid read for sure.
>> It's it's a solid read and and read and
it won the National Book Award which is
a very big deal.
>> Yeah.
>> Very big deal. I mean, it's it's
definitely not a fun read,
unfortunately. And I and that's my kind
of idea of a fun read, but
>> yeah, it doesn't, you know, I mean, I
love I mean, that's all I read is that
kind of thing, but
>> I love it.
>> Yeah. But I mean, the pros doesn't sing,
but I would say it's worth it's worth
>> a little bit on the dense side, but he
footnotes the daylights out of his
books.
>> I appreciate that.
>> He backs up everything he writes. It's
It's quite impressive.
>> And then his books are like 800 pages
long.
>> Yeah. I mean, I'm a sucker for those
long books. Uh I've been hearing that
like uh word counts are dropping at
books. Like uh 100,000 120,000 words
used to be a standard like fiction book.
Now 60 or 80,000 is like closer to a
novella because people's attention span
is so short. But the biographies and and
political non-fiction still is the
outlier. They're getting longer and
longer all the time. Um,
>> can I ask can I answer Eric um who real
quickly?
>> Um, Eric, the um the rule on the Peace
Corp was written in granite. There could
be no contact whatsoever
between the CIA and the Peace Corp for
several reasons. First of all, everybody
already accuses the Peace Corp of being
CIA, right? So, it's dangerous enough.
Secondly,
the Peace Corps has no protection.
They're out there in the sticks. You're
you you are out there in the sticks
doing God's work and there's nobody to
protect you. So, we were not permitted
to even like say hello if we ran into
somebody from the
>> good. I mean honestly that is a good
rule that you guys had because I mean
you know it's to me the analogy is the
uh journalism the journalist embedding
programs
>> without a doubt
>> violently opposed to um and you know
it's like the the as soon as that
started in Afghan in well in Iraq um
anytime you went anywhere you know the
the locals would say like well you're
just uh you know you're with the US
soldiers you're you know you're a
propagandist you're I can't trust you
why shouldn't I kill you and it's like I
mean It's so dangerous. And then, you
know, with a as a journalist, the only
weapon you have is your your camera or
your or your your laptop. I mean,
>> that's it. You're on your own.
>> You're really like your your dick is
waving out in the wind. I mean, it's
bad.
>> It's bad.
>> Um Oh. So, uh do you want to talk do you
want to talk about do the others? Do you
want to do Sandy Grimes or should we
save her later?
>> Let's do Sandy Grimes. You know, Sandy
Grimes, Sandy Grimes is another kind of
legendary figure and she never really
set out to be. Um, Sandy started off as
a secretary uh in the days when I think
she started back in ' 67 is what I read,
but those were the days when women were
not permitted to have leadership roles.
Not just leadership roles, they were not
permitted to really do anything of
import. They were only secretaries and
clerks, file clerks. So, she started off
as a secretary
and then rose up to be one of the the
greatest mole hunters in CIA's history.
And she's the one who caught Aldrich
Ames, one of the most despicable
traitors in modern American history. So,
u and she she was totally unsung. She
didn't. Even inside the building,
if you would say to somebody, "Hey, so
which one of these people over here is
Sandy Grimes?" Nobody would know because
she wasn't about the fanfare. Her job
was to find the mole. And by God, she
found him and he got life without
parole. I remember George Tennant saying
one time in a meeting that Sandy had
gone to him. George, of course, was the
director at the time. And Sandy said,
"I've identified him. It's Aldrich
Ames." And it just so happened that
George had to attend a White House
briefing at which Ames was a
participant.
And um
and George said that he just couldn't
look Ames in the eye. He knew he was a
traitor and he knew that he was going to
be arrested in just a couple of days.
And so he was determined only to look at
Ames's shoes so as not to give himself
away. And he said he couldn't help but
to see that the shoes were um
oh the shoes that that OJ Simpson wore
those like $500 shoes. Do you remember
what those were?
>> Oh god. Um I don't remember what those
were. I had never heard of them at the
time. I had neither. But they're like
Prada Prada shoes.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And then a couple of days
later, uh
>> that's always the thing, right? I mean,
these guys, these these moles
>> Yeah.
>> they have too much money. Um they're
living too high. That That's what it's
like the mob, right? That's what
attracts the wrong kind of attention.
>> Absolutely. I'm gonna I'm gonna Google
it real quickly. OJ Simpson's
shoes. And while you're doing that, let
me just bring in Robbie uh to talk about
>> Bruno Mali.
>> Bruno Mali. That's it. Well,
>> shoes.
>> Let me bring in producer Robbie. Uh
guys, we just have to ask you a quick
little favor and we're going to explain
this to you. Okay. Robbie's our
producer, Robbie West, who I'm going to
see next week in Montana. Um, so, uh, we
basically are trying to to get some
money here. And with the existing
audience that we have, if we can get
people to go over to Rumble and watch us
on Rumble, same exact experience.
There's a there's a live feed, it's
exactly the same thing. Um, instead of
YouTube, which pays not nearly as well,
uh, John and I will have a little easier
time paying our bills every month.
>> You want to explain it?
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, for sure. Thank you all
for popping for popping me on. All
right, so just real quick, I'm going to
try and make this as precise and not
boring as possible. So, YouTube pays you
based off of ads. And basically,
whenever you click on a video, whenever
an ad pops up, they will literally throw
a few pennies to uh Ted and John here
onto the channel. What I'm working on
doing is getting deprogrammed into the
Rumble content creator program. And I
want that for a couple of different
reasons. One, Rumble is a free speech
platform. So what does that mean? It
means that Rumble will not one day
decide that John and Ted are being too
controversial and pull the plug. So if
you like John and Ted, go to Rumble and
listen to them and they'll be
uncensored. Second, Rumble pays you
based off of your watch hours. On
YouTube, watch hours mean nothing. So
it's kind of like TV or radio. So the
more people that watch, what happens is
that they get paid literally hundreds of
dollars per hour watched as opposed to
maybe six or seven dollars over on
YouTube. And like Ted was saying, the
experience is exactly the same with one
big exception. When you're on Rumble, if
once you're in the creator program, they
have to do five hours of Rumble only
premium content. So what does that mean?
If there's a topic that's particularly
controversial that you're all interested
in hearing,
then you can see it live on Rumble and
be able to continue supporting them and
be able to help them pay some bills. I
mean, y'all know what's going on with
them. Y'all know that that they lost
their income. So, while we ask y'all to
go over to Rumble, drop some follows. We
have thousands of people here watching
on YouTube. If only it
I'm I do not kid y'all. If 20% of y'all
do what we're asking, it would make a
radical change financially
for Ted and for John. That's all I got
for you. Now, drop the link in the chat.
>> Okay. Uh the chat that it's it's in
here. It's rumble rumble.comc
inexplicably
dprogramshow, but you can just go to
rumble and just search for dprogram and
Ted Roller or John Kuryaku and you will
find it. Robbie, thank you so much for
that. Um, okay. Sorry for the ad guys. I
mean, it's like we're getting to be like
NPR John. Anyway, you were saying about
Sarah about Sandy Grimes.
Yeah. So, here she catches one of the
most prolific uh moles in modern
American history. And then the next day,
she came into work and just went about
her normal job looking for the next
mole. So, I felt bad when I saw she
died. I didn't realize that she was 80
years old, but God bless her. She was
really one of those unknown heroes,
those unsung heroes at the CIA. You
know, every once in a while the CIA will
give out something called a trailblazer
award. I never understood these things.
And most of them will be, you know,
white men who were station chief like,
you know, in Havana when the when
Batista was overthrown or station chief
when the last guy was pulled out of
South Vietnam on the helicopter. And
then they'll they'll toss one to
somebody like Bonnie Hersburg. I worked
for Bonnie uh in the office of
leadership analysis. Bonnie was a
terrific analyst. She was an okay
manager.
What she what trail she blazed, I will
never ever ever understand because she
was just kind of a typical
run-of-the-mill manager. But then you
have people like like this who um you
know are unsung.
But anyway, that's the CIA today. Lot of
news coming in CIA today. What what is
what is before we move on from from her
I mean what is the what are the
personality traits that are required to
catch a mole like what skill set is
required I mean it's not you have to
navigate also you're you're in the case
of an Aldridge Ames you're you're
bringing down someone who's uh you know
got title uh position above your own
a lot of institutional resistance no one
wants to hear it right
>> no one wants to hear it and I'll tell
you But there are no bigger secrets than
the counter intelligence center at the
CIA.
Um,
that's a very important question you've
asked, Ted. The the mole hunter at the
CIA has to be somebody who is obsessed
with secrecy
to the point where you don't even talk
to yourself like in your own head. Like
for me, I'd be I'd go to the credit
union and say, "I'm taking you down,
Ames. you bastard. You know, I would
never fit in in a position like that.
>> Um,
>> and you have to and you and you have to
not really care about like people
telling you, "Shut up, Kiriaku." Like,
you're you're you just don't like that
you don't like games because you don't
like his politics. You don't like the
cut of his jib. This is personal. You're
going after a good patriot, someone
who's doing God's work for America, and
you're being an [__]
>> That's right. That's right. Um and and
listen, somebody in counter intelligence
is akin to somebody in internal affairs
in a police department.
>> I'll give you another
>> No one likes you.
>> I I'll give you an example. On my uh on
my first at the end of my first full
week at the agency, my boss walked me
around both the new headquarters
building and the old headquarters
building just to point out where
everything was. Right. Here's the
cafeteria. Here's the credit union.
There's medical services. This in the
lobby of the new building is it's it's
all glass like a glass atrium and they
have windows and one window says health
insurance and one window says life
insurance and one window says sports
tickets, right? And then there were a
couple of other windows. He said this is
where you go if you want to buy baseball
tickets, basketball, hockey, football
tickets, right? And then there was
another one that said,
well, I shouldn't say what it said, but
it was the window that you go to if
maybe you have a little bit of a
drinking problem
>> or you've got a problem with your credit
or maybe you're taking care of your
elderly parents and it's too much of a
burden. He told me, "Don't ever go to
that window." I said, "Why? It's nice
that they do things like that."
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And he said, "Because
the people at that window work for
counter intelligence
and they don't give a [__] about your
elderly parents. They want to know if
you're in a bad enough spot that you're
going to turn mole."
So this is so this is a little bit like
uh in the cultural revolution let a
thousand flowers bloom
>> where the Chinese communist party and
said oh we're opening up to ourselves to
criticism you know all you academics all
you people who might be accused of being
counterrevolutionaries
step forward the party's a big tent we
want to hear from all of you guys then
you step forward
>> off to a May 4th farm
>> nobody ever Easy again.
>> Yeah,
>> that's right.
>> Wow. That is I mean that's some dark
cynical [__]
>> That was my first week. I'm like, "Holy
shit." I never even went in there to to
buy a a ticket to the ball game. I was
just afraid of somebody just seeing me
going in there.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You can That Ticketron is for um
or Ticket M or whatever the [__] it's
called now.
>> That's exactly right.
>> Oh, man. That is that is so so dark. Um
>> All right. Should we uh should we talk
about um Palestine? I mean uh we have
>> you were right, Ted. You were right
about Kier Armor. And frankly, I didn't
think he had the guts to do it. But then
he kind of made a half step, if you
don't mind my, you know, taking over the
conversation,
>> please.
>> He said, "We're going to we're going to
recognize Palestine in September unless
the Israelis let food in and and are
nicer people about it."
>> It's a decision to sign by committee,
right? You can tell that and um you know
and but I think it's probably very easy
to agree to. I mean it's it's kind of
like well okay fine. I mean the Israelis
are not going to do this. I mean it does
have kind of I mean I don't like it
either because I feel one of the
commenters uh deep down in the thread
pointed out that really uh this
recognition should just be based on uh
not as a reward a punishment for Israel
but it should just be a statement of
self-determination for the Palestinian
people. Couldn't agree more.
>> In the original documents that led to
the creation of Israel, and there's even
a YouTube video of of Harry Truman
talking about this, it says that Israel
is going to be created, you know, today,
whatever 1948,
and Palestine will be created as an
independent state pending further
discussion.
Okay, that was 1948
and we're still talking about it. Now
that said, we are there's 153 nations. I
guess it's going to be 155 soon. Um,
Australia is apparently uh cir is uh
getting ready to go to shoot to to pull
the trigger. Um, Luxembourg is getting
ready to pull the trigger.
>> I didn't see that one.
>> And uh and and there's there's a whole
pel of other European countries that are
Croatia.
>> Yes. Croatia. Spain.
>> Yeah. Spain's already in.
>> Well, they're already in.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I mean, I think
basically, uh, it's like you said, it's
going to be just the Axis powers of
Germany and and and Japan and Italy who
are going to be out with the US. What a
what a what a mly crew. And, um, you
know, but but so, yeah. No, it's it's a
big deal. I mean, I think the the
pressure built so fast on Starmer.
That's what I I mean, I knew it was
going to happen. I just didn't think it
would happen this quickly. And you know
what started it was these pictures that
ran in the BBC of starving children that
just opened the floodgates.
I I really believe that.
>> Yeah. Well, let's talk about that.
Someone brought it up and I apologize
because this was further down, but I'm
glad that someone uh asked about this
question. So, um, there was this very
one particular photo of this one kid who
was really, really, really sick and with
these haunting eyes. And you can see why
the why this particular photo went
viral. And um, the New York Times and
other corporate media organizations have
walked that back obviously in response
to Zionists who've complained that the
kid aside from suffering from starvation
also had other diseases at the same
time. Right? So therefore, but those
other So the implication being maybe
that these other diseases are wasting
diseases, but they're not. Um but the
kids was really really sick and he's
starving. So um and he's that's which is
why he was at the hospital. But um you
know, look to me it's kind of like well
what do you you know what do we make of
that? My answer to that is I think it's
the you know it's the last gasp of a
dying regime. I mean, I think Israel is
in real trouble now.
>> I I agree. I agree. And I don't think
that they really realize just how deep
they are. I saw an interview. Well,
maybe you saw it, too. It's it's Tucker
Carlson's latest interview. Uh it just
dropped and it's with John Mirshimer who
is absolutely freaking brilliant. And
Mirshimer
essentially said that. He said that the
Israelis just don't realize how how deep
they're in. And and on the contrary,
they're talking about
this concept of a greater Israel, which
is like includes the bottom third of
Lebanon, the southern third of Lebanon.
It includes, you know, another 50 miles
inside of uh of Syria. It includes the
entire West Bank. and it includes the
Gaza, I'm sorry, the uh the Sinai
Peninsula. It's like, wait a minute, you
guys should be thinking about your
survival here and about your country
falling apart because you're carrying
out a genocide
and you've got people who are in
government talking about greater Israel.
Mir Shimemer made another important
point
and this is how unhinged the American
evangelical Christian community is where
you've got the likes of Ambassador
Huckabe or Speaker of the House Mike
Johnson
>> saying that Jesus wants us to support
Israel and Israel's policy. Well, last
week Israel's policy was to utterly and
completely destroy one of the last
surviving Christian villages in the West
Bank, drive out all the Christians and
steal their land. So, you're saying
Jesus wants wants the Jews to drive out
the Christians,
>> and that's what we're going with.
>> It makes absolutely no sense at all. And
so many Americans don't know how many
Christians there are in Palestine. A lot
of them. Um the by the way though%
>> I do want to say and one of the things
you wanted to talk about was uh the you
know the the the split now the growing
split on the American right over Israel.
And I do want to be fair to Ambassador
Huckabe. He's the US ambassador to
Israel. He went to the West Bank and
visited that town that's been repeatedly
attacked by violent fascist settlers.
Probably most of whom are from like my
neighbors from Brooklyn.
>> They're from New Jersey and New York.
>> Yeah. and those and those those those
scumbags who've been uh you know mur
murder murdering, raping and pillaging
over there. Uh but at least he went
there and he was he expressed concern
and he was I think turned off by what
the the settlers were doing. They showed
up. Um Joe Rogan, who I think is
unfairly characterized as a
right-winger, but he's boycotting
apparently he's not allowing BB
Netanyahu to come on a show he who BB
wants to come on. Um, you know, I mean,
I I think they're losing the thread, the
Israelis. Um, I mean, I mean, we're
talking about a country that is
uniquely, right, it's unique, right?
It's the only country that's currently
on the face of the planet that owes its
existence to the United Nations. It's
the only complete welfare state that
owes its entire ex economy to the United
States of America. It's ignoring the UN
and its resolutions. It's ignoring
public opinion in the US, the tax among
the taxpayers who are paying that bill
to the Israelis. I mean, these people
are biting, chomping, stabbing, and
hacking at the hand that feeds them.
>> And, you know, I mean, they're a rabid
dog. And, you know, I mean, I I I wrote
a column this week that's called that
Israel no longer has the right to exist.
And
>> yeah, I read that
>> and thank you. the the argument that you
know I'm trying to make here is in the
community of nations there are some
things you just that people can't
tolerate like you know when Napoleon
disrupted Europe um all these disperate
powers who had competing interests got
together to defeat him even though they
hated each other you know World War II
uh you know the US and the USSR were not
buds but they had to come together to
fight Nazi Germany not to stop the
Holocaust because I mean the US
certainly didn't care about it. I mean,
certainly the Russians cared more about
it because it happened on their ter in
their territory. But the, you know, they
came in and they got together because
Nazi Germany was so militarily
aggressive and violent and out of
control and disruptive, they just had to
be put down like a rabid dog. I mean,
same and imperial Japan the same way.
That's exactly the scenario that we have
now with Israel. They're such a
destabilizing force in the Middle East,
right? I mean, literally, even if you
count like Iran, you know, and the Axis
of resistance and all the shenanigans
they had going on with the Houthis and
all that.
>> Yeah.
>> It's nothing compared to Israel, right?
I mean, just in the last few months,
right? They bombed Iran. They did they
overthrew the government of Syria and
now they're bombing the new government
that they installed.
>> Yes.
>> I mean, these people are nuts.
>> They are nuts. And you know, I have to
say, uh, where did I just see it? It was
uh
well, thank you everybody first of all
for for going on to uh there it is. What
what nonsense says USA sex predators
flee to Israel. Oh boy are you right. So
listen to this. I was in prison with a a
pedophile. This disgusting horrible
pedophile.
He had graduated from Harvard and
Harvard Law School and he was an
attorney in Moscow. Um he
to make a very long story very short he
um was a an afficionado of the ballet
and so he offered to pay the tuition for
a 12-year-old Russian boy but he
insisted that the boy live with him. The
parents were like, "I don't know about
that." But they were poor and this kid
was like a once in a generation gifted
ballet guy. And so they allowed their
12-year-old to move in with a guy, um,
Ken
Kenneth. So, uh,
12 hours later, Ken was raping this kid.
And this went on for five years.
Finally,
um, the kid told the FBI what was
happening. They issued an arrest
warrant. By then, Ken was back in
Philadelphia where his parents were
exceedingly wealthy, big humanitarians.
They, you know, donate to the museum,
whatever. He ran immediately to Israel
and the Israelis would not extradite him
>> because they
>> would not the Israelis don't extradite
Jews. It's a it's a it's a law in
Israel. They don't care what he's
accused of. They're not extraditing any
Jew.
So, we asked for the extradition. They
said no.
Um
and then
Interpol came up with an idea that was
absolutely genius. I love when I hear
about these these brilliant operational
ideas that people come up with. This was
my favorite thing to do at the CIA was
just to sit around thickening up ideas
with with my colleagues.
They decided
to
they decided to sponsor a ballet show in
Cyprus
and they used a dummy email account to
email him an announcement of the ballet
>> to lure him
>> and they lured him to Cyprus and they
grabbed him at the airport and the
criates extradited him
>> and he got 20 years. He's still in that
bastard.
>> But the Israelis will not extradite
Jews. Period.
>> That's pretty gross. I mean, I just
Yeah. I mean, I I think look, I think
the I think we're we're done here. So,
look, what's what do you think is going
to happen? I mean, by the Okay, so
September now feels really far away.
>> It does. I agree. And it's not it's four
and a half, five weeks,
>> right? So the so the UN so it's going to
be Labor Day. The UN's going to come
here to New York and [__] up all the
traffic and no one's going to be able to
move. And in that traffic, it's going to
be a lot of new allies of or at least
friends of Palestine.
>> Um how many countries do you think it's
going to be? It's going to be like the m
our migration over to Rumble. Everyone's
subscribing over there. Um yeah,
Palestine's signing them up. Um
>> Oh. Oh, and by the way, I I did want to
ask you a little bit about this
statement that broke. I don't know if
you had a chance to hear it because it
just happened right before we went on
the air, but uh Arab and Muslim states u
a member of the Arab League, the EU, and
17 more countries have supported a
declaration signed at a UN conference
that was hosted by Saudi Arabia and
France that basically uh is calling,
this is also includes this cutter, Saudi
and Saud Saudis and Egypt. They're
calling for Hamas to disarm and give up
power and basically turn over all
authority to the Palestinian Authority,
which of course is Makuda Abbas, who's
what, 92 or something like that.
>> Yeah. I always say he's he's 16 years
into a four-year term.
>> Nice. He and he and Zalinsky have a nice
democracy they they're working on.
That's right. And and anyway, so they
Yeah, he's over there. Um so Makmoud
Abbas, the sort of the the head of the
I I guess it's like the Vichy kind of
government of the West Bank kind of
>> corrupt.
>> Yeah, they're corrupt and they don't
really do anything. But basically,
that's what all these countries are
calling for. Like they don't want to
recognize Hamas.
>> I mean
I mean that's not it's not going to
happen, right? I mean because first of
all that's fat and they can't rule in
Gaza. The Gazins don't want them.
>> No. No. The Gzins have made it clear by
voting Hamas in and the PA out. The PA
is not the answer to this problem. you
know, Harets two or three weeks ago ran
this article saying that one of the
things that's being discussed, and I
think it isn't actually being discussed,
I think they just put it out there to
see what the reaction was going to be,
um, was to have Hamas disarm and then to
have Saudi Arabia administer Gaza while
Israel continues to actually own Gaza.
And then after a day, nobody really
commented on it. And can I say something
too about Cypress? This this thing that
that the uh Israelis said about northern
Cypress being an Israel problem. Um they
they mean something actually
contemporary on that. The Greeks, I am
utterly ashamed to say that the Greeks
and the Criates are 1,000% pro-Israel.
And the reason that they're pro- Israel
is severalfold. Number one, it's because
um it's because the
Israelis and the Turks hate each other.
So if the Turks hate Israel, then the
Greeks have to love Israel because the
Greeks hate
>> the enemy of my enemy is my friend.
>> There it is. The other reason is because
the Criates are sitting on an ocean of
natural gas and it stretches into
Israeli waters. And so the Greeks, the
Cri and into Palestinian waters, right?
>> Gazin waters.
>> Gazin waters. Yes. And just like one
little vein into Lebanese waters.
>> So the Greeks and Criates don't have the
money to uh to lift this gas, but the
Israelis certainly do. And so the three
countries have entered into this joint
venture that's already well underway to
lift this gas and it's going to make
Cypress one of the wealthiest countries
in the in the in the world over the
course of years. So
we just I'm not going to say celebrated,
I'm going to say commemorated
the 51st anniversary of the Turkish
invasion of Cypress.
>> Oh wow. Um the the Turks invaded
Cypress, killed thousands of Criates. 17
American citizens are still missing from
the Turkish invasion 51 years ago.
>> Yeah. This was in the 70s. Yeah.
>> 1974.
>> Yeah.
>> And um
>> I never understood what was the what was
the
>> what was Turkey after? I mean besides
just territory,
>> there were a lot of moving parts in this
thing. So these were were literally the
final days of the Greek military
dictatorship.
>> And as it was in its death throws, it
overthrew the democratically elected
government of Cyprus and installed a
strong man by the name of Nikos Samson,
who had been an assassin
in sort of his previous life. So Samson
announced a military dictatorship in
Cyprus. The Turks saw that as the green
light to invade and overthrow Samson,
which they did in a matter of days.
So the the democratically elected
president returns to Cypress. He'd only
been in exile a week and the Turks never
left and they've just kept onethird of
Cypress, the northern third of Cypress.
So, what we're seeing here, um, what
we're seeing here with the Israelis
saying, "We have a problem with northern
Cypress." There is no such thing as
northern Cypress with a capital N. Um,
the Turks call it the the trunk, the
Turkish Republic of Northern Cypress.
It's not recognized by any country in
the world except Turkey,
>> right? It's Turkey. It's Turkish
annexed. It's Turkish annexed or Turkish
occupied Cypress is what it
>> is. just occupied Cyprus. Yeah. And so
because the Israelis and the Greeks and
the Criates are all in business
together, the the Greeks and the Criates
went to the Israelis and says, "Hey,"
they say, "Hey, we we need your help on
on Cyprus. You need to say the right
thing about the Turks." And so the
Israelis hate the Turks like the Turks
hate the Israelis. So they jump in on
the side of the Greeks and the Criates.
It's awful.
>> Let's ask Let's I do want to answer this
question uh by God.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Why would anyone Sorry, not
that too. Um, I'm Okay, we'll answer
this one. Why would anyone trust Saudi
Arabia to administer Gaza? Um, they
wouldn't
>> is the short answer.
>> They wouldn't. I wouldn't.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, they're not.
>> And then and then also um Yeah, that the
scroll is moving so fast I'm having a
hard Oh, here we go. Um, can you find
your can you can we explain what what
what happens as uh you know with
countries recognizing Palestine?
>> It's really I mean it's so it is
symbolic. it doesn't change the facts on
the ground and there is the concern that
um you know in the case of of the
republic of pal the future republic of
Palestine or the present republic of
Palestine depending on how you want to
look at it it's divided right I mean
it's literally um there's two
governments there's the Hamas government
and there's the Palestinian Authority um
that's kind of an issue because you're
supposed to know who you'd be able to
talk to u but you know I guess like
that's not being but I mean it what
happens is it's legitimate right So the
big thing is if you're a country that
has a deal with Israel or is thinking of
making a deal with Israel, once you
recognize Palestine, you have to go
through all of your trading agreements
and everything that you have with Israel
to see if anything in there is wrong or
illegal or challenging to Palestine. So
a good example of that would be let's
say so Israel produces wine. They
produce it in uh occupied territories
for example in the
Heights, which Yeah. Which is, by the
way, I have to admit, I've had uh this
treason wine. It's it's really good.
>> Yeah, it's really good. So, the Golan
the Golan wine is um you know, for
example, you would not if you've
recognized Syria as an independent
country, which most of the world does.
Well, you can't import that wine into
your country. And it's just a million
little things like that and they add up.
I mean, and there's more to it than
that, too, right? If there's a genocide
taking place um in your country, uh in
in you're recognized by another country,
you can call their ambassador and say,
"Listen, I need your help. Um you know,
there's stuff that we we need we need
your cooperation. Can you help help us
with intel? Can you you know, there's
can you can you stop drecognize Israel?"
There's lots of stuff like suddenly the
doors are open. You're not isolated. Um,
it reminds me a little bit of a strange
uh meeting I had with the Afghan
ambassador to uh Usuzbekistan during the
Taliban period in and this was like in
2000 it was in 2000. So it was the first
>> was healed.
>> So he was a he was a northern alliance
guy.
So I'm So he had the embassy in Tashkant
and um and so I so I asked him like well
you know technically you're supposed to
be getting support from the US and he
said oh yeah he goes um we're supposed
to be and I said what kind of support do
you get and he opens up his desk drawer
pulls out a yellow envelope and he's
like here you go. I open it up and
inside there's a map of Afghanistan
and I'm like it's just and he goes
that's the only support I have ever
gotten from the US government. Like
that's it. And I go well it's a it's a
pretty good map. He goes it's out of
date. He said the Soviet ones are
better.
>> He's like and uh and I was like so how
do you pay for all this? And he was like
hemming and hawing. And I was like you
guys mine rubies. And he's like, "Yeah,
in Badakshan."
So that's, you know, that's how they
were subsisting. But yeah, but I mean,
so I don't know. I mean, what do you
think is I mean, what does it what's the
practical meaning of of recognition for
the Palestinians?
>> I think um it opens the door for
Palestine to be a member state in a lot
of different international
organizations, which gives them a voice
on the international stage that they
otherwise wouldn't have had. uh it makes
them eligible for uh for financial aid
both from international organizations
and from uh individual countries.
And uh you know
we used to have a Palestine liaison
office here in in Washington. Uh Donald
Trump closed it in his first term and
expelled the Palestinian diplomats. Uh,
I would love to see Palestinian
diplomats on the circuit again in
Washington or in London or Madrid or,
you know, Canbor or anywhere else where
they're recognized
>> and they could be and they could
eventually have like one of those
rotating seats at the Security Council
um at the UN.
>> Exactly right. Exactly right. So they
would be they would be the
representative of the Asia group on the
UN Security Council. Oh my god. Could
you imagine?
>> Huge.
>> Huge. Absolutely huge. When I was at the
CIA, it was Libya's turn. And we went
apeshit over the notion that Muamar
Gaddafi would be represented on the
United Nations uh security council. And
so we started this international
lobbying effort and we got the Asia
group to to deny
seeding Libya on the security council
and Egypt got it two terms in a row.
>> Ridiculous.
>> There were no other countries in all of
Asia,
>> you know, that should have been
represented on the UN Security Council.
>> Right. Right. By the way, uh really uh I
think good point here from Sky. Uh after
September, the US will be the only
permanent member of the security council
not to recognize Palestinian statehood.
>> That is a very good point.
>> That's a very thing is Israel is going
to be a pariah. The question for
President Trump and for the United
States and really frankly Trump we
shouldn't pick on him on this because
Democrats are equally guilty for how he
supported Israel.
>> Absolutely. And this whole genocide
started under Biden and he encouraged it
and he funded it and he armed it. So,
uh, you know, Trump just happens to be
holding the bag right now. But the
question for the US is going to be, do
we want to be at the pariah table with
little Israel or do we want to be with
everyone else?
>> Well, you know, in these in these votes
in the UN General Assembly, it's it's
not just us in Israel. It's also Naru
and occasionally Costa Rica and uh you
know one of those little countries in
the Pacific that I can't pronounce. So
we're not always standing alone, right?
>> Like Vanuatu.
>> Vanuatu.
Where would we be without Vanuatu?
>> Well, Vanuatu, I think Vanuatu is the uh
closest to the international dine. So on
New Year's Eve, they always are like,
"Well, Vanuatu celebrated 23 and a half
hours ago.
You've seen that?
>> Unbelievable. Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's It's I'll answer I'll answer
Yellow Banana's question. I'll be in New
York City Labor Day weekend. How bad
will traffic be for the UN?
>> Horrible. Espec if you're staying on the
up on the east side.
>> East side.
>> The east side is in Manhattan is is
terrible. If you're like somewhere else,
honestly, if you're up like I'm on the
upper west.
>> I had a I had a UN badge and I had
trouble getting to the office.
even with a UN badge and and I was
walking so it's going to be bad on the
east side. Stay away from the east side.
>> Yeah. And it's always it's it's kind of
like in general that's that's good
advice anyway. Um Labor Day but all the
rich people will be gone. So in other
neighborhoods it'll kind of help. It's
kind of like a great time to visit town.
Um
>> uh and the weather should be a little
bit better. Um oh my god. So all right.
What do we think of Kaddafi? I love that
question. And I I I I think Gaddafi was
super I mean no one got screwed more
than Gaddafi, right? I mean and and what
happened to him is so is so important as
a you know lesson for other rulers,
right? I mean George W. Bush said,
"Listen, you know, if you drop your
nuclear program uh and you know, we'll
cut a deal with you, we'll bring you in
um legitimize you. We'll forget all
about Locker B." The whole nine yards.
And then he did as asked and the next
thing you know uh Hillary Clinton comes
in as Secretary of State. There's this
uh radical jihadi movement out in
eastern Libya in in Benghazi and the the
US finances it, runs interference for
it, provides air support with NATO and
we helped kill Gaddafi and get him
sodomized on on live. my my boss Steve
Kappus,
deputy director, the associate deputy
director for operations and and a mentor
of mine, flew out to Libya to meet with
Gaddafi and uh Gaddafi's intelligence
chief, who actually graduated from the
University of Michigan um and uh and
convinced him to give up his weapons of
mass destruction programs, saying, "You
don't want to end up like Saddam
Hussein. We're going to kill Saddam
Hussein." He told Gaddafi in two in
2002, "We're gonna kill him.
>> You don't want anything like that.
>> Just give up your weapons of mass
destruction and everybody's going to
live happily ever after." And Gaddafi
gave up all his weapons programs.
>> Arube
>> and we allowed him to be killed anyway.
>> And he got played.
>> Yeah, he got played. We just lied to
him. And then, you know, the way he was
killed was so horrific. It was so
grotesque. And people think that's just
the local they think that's the locals
who did it, but that's not true. I mean,
it was a US uh drone that fired a
missile at his motorcade and maybe at
his car specifically, but his car was
driven off the road. He and his
entourage forced to flee. They hid in a
in a drainage pipe culvert kind of
thing. Yes. And then then the uh the
Giadis found him and and killed him.
>> Yeah. Uh, so yeah, let's talk a little
bit about Do we want to talk about this?
I do. I mean, it's what's so remarkable
about the mass shooting that took place
at 345 Park Avenue here and 51st Street
>> is that it's not remarkable. Um, you
know, this guy came in, he claimed in
reminded me of the um the the shooter at
the University of Texas in Austin in
1966, the Texas Watchtower shooter. Yes,
he suspected there was something wrong
with him, that he was hearing voices and
having violent urges. And in his suicide
note, he he asked he requested that his
brain be examined for uh signs of
trouble. And in fact, they did find a
tumor that was pressing up against his
amydala. And uh that's so and so this
guy yesterday um he his suicide note
said that he believed he had CTE. I
don't know if he had ever been diagnosed
formally or not. He was a high school
football player. He went to the NFL
building HQ uh and basically went to the
wrong floor, killed four people,
including an offduty New York City
police officer who was working security
at the desk. And um you know, the thing
is though, it's one of those things
where if you say, well, what could you
possibly do about it? I mean, I think
nothing. I mean, you know, it's like
people guns are legal, AR-15s are legal,
there's they're we're washing them.
They're all over the place. um you know,
he drove here from Nevada. Uh he parked
in front of the building in his BMW and
walked in. I mean, this can and will
happen over and over again. And it's
almost like all you can do is just
shrug. And I think that's the part
that's what's so remarkable about it is
how unremarkable it is.
>> And you know, he he apologized in the
note that he left, which just to me made
it that much more sad. Yeah,
>> mental illness, whether it's caused by
CTE or or something else, is is a
horrible existence.
>> And he really believed that he had CTE
and he really believed that it was
because he uh played football in high
school.
>> Yeah. So he was
>> Yeah. So it seems to be like kind of
it's a political act basically.
>> Yeah. Right. It is. Yes, it is. It's a
political act.
>> John, should we talk about Yeah. Should
we talk about this uh story out of Iran?
So, obviously, the Iranians are still
smarting from the uh their 12-day,
14-day war with uh I guess 12-day war
with uh Israel, and um they're licking
their wounds, but their their whatever
their nuclear program was appears to be
largely intact. But the Iranians took
note and they're starting to think and
they obviously are investigating what
happened. And part of their
investigation finds that um their GPS
was manipulated by the US or Israel
andor Israel andor other some kind of
other bad actor uh to screw up their
targeting abilities. This might help
explain why they were so uh caught with
their pants down and unable to defend
themselves uh and fire back against the
uh Israelis who had complete uh you know
command of the skies over Iran which to
me blew my blew me away.
>> This has been a rumor really since since
the 12-day war that something was wrong
with the GPS's. You're not allowed to
use ways in Iran because ways is owned
by an Israeli company. But any GPS the
Iranians,
>> right? Ways was purchased by Google.
It's now part of Alphabet. Yeah,
>> correct. Um, it was founded by an
Israeli company.
>> That's right.
>> So, uh,
>> I always hated it. I never understood
it. I didn't understand like how it like
the interface makes no sense to me.
Maybe, maybe you have to read from right
to left or something.
maybe.
But I think it's they're worried about
GPS's in general now just because
>> they believe probably rightly that the
US and Israel have the technology to be
able to um interface with the satellites
>> and target Iran.
>> Well, there are satellites, right? I
mean,
>> Bill Clinton, right? This was this was
military and covert technology, right?
Until Bill Clinton decided to publicize
it. Um, I think wisely he was convinced
that this was going to open up all sorts
of technological innovation and it it
has. I mean, if you think about
something like, you know, you look at
real estate listings and, you know, you
can see a map of where the house is or
whatever. It's it's amazing. But that
technology, it's American and it can be
it can and was weaponized against the
Iranians. So now they're looking for a
Chinese or other alternative. Um, right.
This story is not about Iran. This story
is about the US having technological
dominance.
>> That's right.
>> And and then that dominance being
undermined by the US's willingness to
weaponize that dominance um for
short-term gain, losing sight of the
long-term impact, which is that if you
come off as a non-neutral arbiter, uh
you know, you're not the rest of the
world isn't going to want to trust you
anymore, and then you're going to lose
your advantage. I mean, you know, we
invented the phone. That's why our area,
that's why our country code is one. Um,
you know, we we we have I mean, this is
exact it's analogous to the dollar,
right? We weaponized the US dollar. So
now Russia, everyone else who's
thinking, well, one day I could fall a
foul of I mean, Belgium, you could fall
a foul of the United States. You don't
know. And then, you know, they could
just decide to turn off the spigot and
screw us and steal our for our reserve
currency. Like, we can't have that. So
you know get you know swift or all these
bank all these systems that if you want
to control them and and take a little
piece you can't like put your thumb on
the I mean the example I'm thinking of
is like you know how did Constantinople
become rich right well it's like right
on the Bosphorus and they just collected
tolls right from the Silk Road and just
waited for ships to go through and
everybody had to pay and what made it
work was they let everyone through and
they charge to everyone. If they had
started to say like ah you know the the
[__] those Sagdians let's nail them. Um
then like that wouldn't have worked.
Other people would have been like well
we have to overthrow the the
Constantinople or we have to do an end
route. We have to figure another way.
>> Yeah. The US just doesn't I don't know.
It seems really really shortsighted.
>> Very very shortsighted. And we had the
same conversation last week about
sanctions.
Countries have gotten to the point where
sanctions just simply don't hurt them
anymore because we are so heavy in the
way we we levy sanctions against
countries that they're forced to come up
with the way around them. And let me
interrupt our conversation for one
second. Uh just as we were going on the
air, exactly 60 60 minutes ago, Prime
Minister um Mark Carney, the Canadian
Prime Minister, announced that Canada
would recognize Palestine.
>> Holy [__]
That's amazing.
I just had a little tingle there in my
in my upper back. That's so great.
>> It's It's happening. You're right. It's
There's a hole in the dyke.
>> The flood.
>> It's It's coming. It's it's you know to
take a story from uh from the from from
from northeastern Russia it's it's a
seismic shift.
>> It's a tsunami.
I mean but it is I mean no
>> and Canada is also I mean diplomatically
a very important country. I mean, you
know, Canada is the country that when
you're a backpacker and you want to
travel to like you're an American
backpacker and you want to go to like
Afghanistan and not be thought of as an
[__] you wear the you put that
Canadian flag on your backpack, right?
Canada is considered neutral.
>> I did that. I sewed a Canadian flag on
my backpack in the summer of 85.
>> Everyone thinks Canada is is chill. Um
I'm wondering what can cander strike
means here. Canada is following orders
from whom, I wonder.
>> No, that that doesn't make sense to me.
>> Yeah. Well, you can pipe in uh we'll
we'll put that up whatever you if you
reply to us. Um but yeah, so yeah,
exactly. Houdini is like always say
you're Canadian overseas like oh like
yeah I like hockey. Um
but yeah, so we'll we'll see what
happens here. Um
Oh, so yeah. So, there's so much cynical
cynicism here, right? I'm not buying it.
These elites that back to genocide
already can't do good.
>> Um, look, it's not because they're good
people. It's because they read polls
>> and like they know that basically the
world isn't this. I mean, if they were
good people, they would have come out
against this [__] on October 8th, 2023.
I mean, you know, this is like because
it was already obvious what the what the
Israelis were going to do from within
hours. I mean, they were they were
having a great time, you know, they were
looking forward to it.
>> Yeah.
>> So, um
>> you know, I wonder if some of this is a
swipe at Donald Trump, too, from from
the Canadians.
>> I wonder.
>> It could be. It could be. Well, they
have reason to be pissed.
>> Right.
Right.
>> Um I think Yeah. I mean, I don't know.
I'm not ruling out that Donald Trump is
going to distance himself from Israel. I
don't It's not like he's going to like
recognize Palestine, but he's right.
>> I think the weapons flow has to come to
an end.
>> It does. Alyssa Slotkin, some a couple
people have mentioned Alyssa Slotkin in
the uh in the uh chat. She's the senator
from uh Michigan, former CIA colleague
of mine. Uh she,
you know, Alyssa's complicated. She's
Jewish. She was not endorsed by any of
the Jewish groups in America uh in her
campaign. Uh but she won. She won
relatively easily in a in a year when
Donald Trump carried her state. Um but
she said that she would be willing to
vote for a cut off of offensive weapons
uh to to Israel. That's not going to
happen.
We saw a week ago there was a vote to
cut off offensive weapons to Israel and
it got like six votes in the House. So,
it's just not going to it's not going to
happen.
>> Well, I I don't think it's going to
happen quickly, but I think I think by
by Christmas time, I think we're going
to see we're going to see some movement
or it's gonna it's going to slow down or
something. Do you do you think do you
think that if it keeps happening if if
country after country you know not
including of course Hungary, Italy,
Germany, the United States, but if these
other countries continue to recognize
Palestine,
do you think that this could threaten
the Netanyahu government?
>> Yeah. Um
>> because somebody's going to have to take
the blame for losing the international
community,
>> right? And that has to be that has to be
BB, right? I mean, um, I I did a deep
dive into Israeli opinion polling, as
you know, because you read my column.
Um, yeah. And 76.5%
of Israelis as of June um, totally have
no problem with the genocide. They're
like a okay with it. And they don't
think that Palestinian uh, that the the
needs of the Palestinians and their
misery should even be taken into
consideration in military planning.
Right. So, this is um you know, let's
let's be clear here. Even what passes
for the Israeli left, they're not
demonstrating against the genocide.
They're demonstrating because the
hostages haven't come home. Yeah. And
and also they don't like Netanyahu um
and and his corruption. But that's what
this is about, right? Um, so we looking
at it from the, it's hard for me to see
this from the point standpoint of the
Israelis who basically have their heads
up their asses while the whole rest of
the world is appalled and disgusted with
them and they don't see it. But I do
think if from their point of view, if
they're involved in an existential
battle to expand Israel, drive and get
Gaza for themselves, um, which obviously
all is Israelis aren't stupid. They know
that's what this is about.
and that that project is going to be
deeply hampered by losing US and
international support. Yeah. Yeah. Who
else are you going to blame? I mean, you
can't alard it, say, "Well, this is Ben
Gvere, but not, you know, but not
Netanyahu." It's like, it's all of them.
The government's got to go.
>> I mean, it's not like we're gonna
they're not going to be replaced with
liberals, but
>> No. No. There aren't any anymore in
Israel.
>> No.
>> No. If there's a ceasefire, does BB go
to prison? Well, if BB if BB is out of
government
>> if he's out of government,
>> BB goes to trial.
>> Yes.
>> And then probably he goes to prison, I
think.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. And this is a good point. Oh,
thank you, Candace Strike. Thank you
very much. Um,
uh, where did I just see it? It we're
we're getting so many comments I can't
keep up. Yeah. Um, hug droid mix. don't
think they can admit wrongdoing on
anything. It's a mountain of war crimes.
That's exactly right.
>> No. Well, that's for sure.
>> And and and that's why that's why
Netanyahu can't risk not being prime
minister.
>> Here's a big question for you. You know,
back in the old days, people like Edamin
would go into exile in places like Saudi
Arabia.
>> That's right. I saw him in Jedha in the
in the vegetable market.
>> What?
>> I was like, "Oh my god, that's Idiam."
and he was there with his wife like
>> shopping for ears.
>> Seriously, right? What a monster.
>> You know, there's a there's a famous
story uh I forget if it was Time or
Newsweek, but one of them interviewed
him and uh at and on the back porch of
his presidential palace and uh at and he
um at one point uh was presented with a
plate of human ears with tomato garnish
and said like, "This is a delicacy in
our country. Would you like one?"
>> Oh my god. I remember reading an article
once saying that in a conversation with
a reporter, he he was talking about the
saltiness of bush meat and he said,
"Monkeys are salty. Leopards are very
salty, but nothing is as salty as a
human being."
>> Yeah. He was a famous cannibal. Um did
you ever see the that movie with the f
by the French brothers? Um the it's in
the criterion collection. It's just
called me dada.
It's one of the It's one of the most
amazing film. It's a documentary. So,
this is amazing film, right? So,
basically
>> for six months, these two French
brothers were given unfettered access to
Ediamin. They followed him everywhere.
Um they and this was right after uh the
antbi uh mission by the Israelis and
>> odd's brother was killed
>> and and and it changed him apparently
Ediamin um like for the filmmakers had
his army recreate the antbi mission from
and they brings out helicopters and
[__] You got to watch it. It's like
it's the and and also he swims. Is it
the Zambzi? Um he he's swimming
>> like next to crocodiles and like every
morning and he like pushes them out of
the way like get out of the way you
[__] rascals and but the most to me
the it's it's completely you can't take
your eyes off it but the best moment for
me is there's a cabinet meeting and you
can hear the air conditioner like
rolling. He's going around the the room
and it's kind of like got that sort of
East German kind of decor like you know
sort of that uh lives of others kind of
vibe and he's like okay so secretary of
transport minister of transportation um
sorry minister of education you're doing
good job keep it up uh defense
everything's looking good and he's going
around and he's like
transportation
and the guy starts quivering like a leaf
and he's
you know the service in the still
getting complaints about the bus service
in the capital just
you have my number right my four-digit
number and he tells it like 3224
you you I tell you you have a problem
you call me morning do and night you get
it have you ever called me even one time
you never call and nothing ever gets
better and then the scene cuts and
there's the guy's body floating in the
river it says the next day
transportation minister So and so was
found floating in the Zambesi.
>> I mean,
>> it's unbelievable. But anyway,
>> oh my god,
>> it's crazy. So, okay. Well, so does BB
Netanyahu can he fly to would the Saudis
take him in as a as the as could they as
the uh you know prime minister of a
Jewish state?
>> Never.
>> Okay.
>> No. Never.
>> So there's some decency. There are
limits. There are rules.
>> I You know what? I think that the reason
why they wouldn't ever do it is because
their own people would overthrow them.
>> Well, yeah.
>> They did something like that.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. No, he's more likely to end up,
you know, in in the US. I I was I was in
Oldtown Alexandria, Virginia one time.
Now, this is this is 20 years ago.
And I saw Perves Musharf and his wife
just window shopping up and down King
Street.
Like, so this is where you ended up, you
war criminal.
>> Oh, he's a Yeah, he's a he's a Yeah, I
could go on about him. Um, you know,
because uh I've you know, I'm a
commentator. I don't really break news.
Um, the news that I broke ever was the
was the Perves Masharf coup. Um, so I
was down the street in Islamabad uh at a
cafe just eating and um there was I just
gotten down the Kakorum Highway. It
taken like three or four weeks with my
friend. Um and so we're like hanging
out. We finally arrived in Islamabad
and there's gunfire down the street and
uh you know small arms fire. And so I
asked the waiter, the waiters always
know everything. I said, "What's going
on?" And he goes, "Oh, they are
overthrowing the the government." I'm
like, "What?" He goes, "Yeah, Omar
Sharif, he is finished." Like he's it's
like he will be killed. I'm like,
"What?" It's like I'm like, "Right now?"
It's like, "Yeah, that's them now." So
So I got up with my camera and went and
took a bunch of photos and talked to
some soldiers. that indeed like Omar
Sharif's in the van like like while I'm
talking outside I'm like outside the van
they're taking him off to be tortured
right they did torture him and um so
Perves Mashar uh you know and I knew
because when we came down the the uh
Kakorum highway we saw Taliban soldiers
all over the place in and you know we
were stopped at a checkpoint and uh
we're like and they're like oh you're
you're in Afghanistan I'm like this is a
KKH we're not in Afghanist we're in
Pakistan and the guy starts joking and
he goes sometimes Afghanistan comes to
you and um because Perves Bashar came to
power by by with as an alliance with the
P with with the Taliban and he allowed
the Taliban to enter northern Afghan
northern Pakistan to go as proxies to go
fight the Indians and basically say we
didn't attack you guys we don't know
anything about it was called the third
Kashmir war with the Cargill conflict
you all this but this is for the this is
for the audience.
>> Um
>> oh my god
>> and it's like yeah [__] Perves
Mashara I mean after 911 right Pakistan
was so responsible for what we they what
happened to us more than any other
country. Did they get justice? No. They
got a raise.
>> Nope. That was it. They got a raise.
>> Yep. And like every exiled Pakistani
leader,
>> he's now in Dubai, which is exactly
where um
uh what was her name uh went? Um Prime
Minister uh
Oh, come on. We were just talking about
her last week. Why am I having a
>> Which country?
>> Pakistan.
>> Oh, BH.
>> Prime Minister BH and her husband.
>> Yeah. back and forth between Pakistan
and Dubai, presidency and exile, you
know, crimes against humanity and all
that stuff.
>> Lovely fellows all around and ladies.
>> Yeah, she's dead. Musharv's dead.
They're all dead now.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's true.
>> She took a a bullet to the brain is what
did her in.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, that it is a I mean,
Pakistanis are spicy.
>> Oh, yeah. It's a tough It's a tough gig.
>> You don't want to cross them.
>> No, it's a tough gig. I mean it's like I
mean I I every moment I was in Pakistan
I had the feeling that a riot could
break out any second any second. Someone
who just could just walk down the street
and start screaming something in Erdo
and the next thing you know people are
out there with sticks and [__] and you
had guns out there like it's on and you
don't even know what's going on.
Um all right so all right where's Hamid
Carzi? Hamid Carzi is still in Kbble
living happily next to the Taliban. M's
got balls of steel, but
>> his brother's got a restaurant in uh
Baltimore if anyone wants to go check it
out. It's actually pretty good.
>> I do like Afghan food quite a bit. Um
but well, not not the Afghan food there
for the most part, just because
>> the Afghan food in America is head and
shoulders better than any Afghan food.
>> It's like Cuban food. Cuban food sucks
in Cuba.
>> It's terrible in Cuba.
>> Yeah.
>> Like how much zucchini can you eat?
>> Or boiled chicken. Yeah, tell me.
>> And and Bad Yellow Rice. Um,
all right. So,
>> what's your take on Immran Khan? I
actually like Imran Khan. I liked and
respected him. His problem is that
anytime he has a problem, whether it's
riots in the streets or an ingrown
toenail, he blames the United States.
>> I think we're gonna we're gonna leave
that that there for the deprogramming
for today. Um, just a reminder to
everybody in case you missed it. Um, it
would mean a lot to uh John and I and in
the most important way, which is to say
financially, if you guys were to watch
this same exact show, the same exact way
over on Rumble instead of YouTube. Um,
you know, obviously if you can't for
whatever reason, we love you on YouTube,
too. But, um, we get paid a zillion
times more over on Rumble than we do its
pennies on YouTube. There's no
comparison. So, um, you know, if you go
over to Rumble and just watch this
exactly the same way, it'd be much
appreciated. You don't have to remember
this weird URL. Just go to Rumble and
search for John or Eisen my name or the
show andor the show and it'll come right
up. And so, thank you very much. We're
here Monday, Wednesday, Friday, five
o'clock Eastern time. We're going to be
going in two weeks to a Monday through
Friday schedule, uh, 5:00 pm. So
hopefully uh you guys will stick around
for that. We love this show and we love
you guys. We have the best fans and the
best watchers and viewers. So, and we're
fans of you guys, too. So, it's a mutual
admiration society. Um anyway, John,
always a pleasure. Hang in there. And
>> fun as it always is.
>> It It flies. Time flies.
>> It does.
>> All right. And
>> thanks everybody.
>> By the way, O Canada,
>> that's right. Kudos to the Canadians.
>> Hello. Well, good afternoon depending on
where you live. We're assuming you're
living somewhere in the afternoon, but
if it's morning where you are, good
morning.
>> I'm
John Kuryaku is here too. Uh we're the
deeprogram show. Michelle Woody's out
this week. She'll be back next week, we
hope and trust, although these days no
one can trust or hope really in
anything. Um anyway, it's uh Thursday,
April 10th, 2025. Thanks for joining us
here as we try to deprogram you from all
the propaganda and assorted BS that
we're all subject to these days
increasingly. Um it's uh it it there was
breaking news even like three minutes
ago right before we came on uh
concerning Columbia University uh which
is just a stones throw from where I'm
speaking to you John. Um I can you know
walk on my hands and knees and get
there. Uh and it's where I graduated
from. Uh the federal government, I mean,
appears to be uh entertaining the
possibility of subjecting it to
oversight, federal oversight,
effectively seizing Columbia University
at an Ivy League school. Um and uh yeah,
I mean, the details are are not quite
known yet, but the Wall Street Journal
is reporting it. It's uh obviously
something the administration is at least
toying with. Um so
>> I'm gonna I'm gonna look at that piece
right now. this there there are very few
things that sound crazier to me than
seizing
>> agreed
>> a university because you don't like some
of the political positions that some of
the students have taken. I mean that's
really what it comes down to here. It is
exclusive Trump administration wants to
install federal oversight of Columbia
University in an unusual move. The
government is aiming to legally bind the
school to changes as they negotiate over
federal funding. So what the Trump
administration apparently is proposing
is if you still want the what was it,
Ted? $400 million in federal funding or
some some amount like that.
>> That's right. That's exactly right.
>> Then there will be no freedom of speech
whether it's among students or or
faculty. That's what it that's what this
is coming down to. Stunning. I can't
believe it.
I can't believe it either. I mean, you
know, it's uh another story we're going
to talk about this lawyer who was um uh
inter uh interdicted at the uh at the uh
the Detroit airport.
>> At the Detroit airport.
>> Yes.
>> I mean, to me, I you know, I think of
like, you know, America, you know, we
think we're a democracy, but you know,
all societies have a cast system.
>> Yes. And uh and you know you know the
homeless are at the you know the
untouchables at the bottom of the cast
system but you know attorneys are of are
usually a protected class. Um multi-
trillion well multi-billion dollar
endowed Ivy League universities are at
the absolute apex of the protected
classes. Um and you know let's talk
about Colombia. I mean, to me, the
grotesque irony here is, I mean, aside
from the fact that there's still yet to
be proven one single anti-semitic
incident that happened at that school,
which is actually kind of shocking. You
would just think considering that it's
about the Israel Palestine conflict that
there probably would have been some
[__] kid who would have said
something anti-semitic. It may have
happened, but it's sort of like the
returning veterans from the Vietnam War
having been spit upon by by by uh by
hippies. Maybe it happened, but there's
zero evidence that it ever happened,
right? And there's no evidence. Um so
maybe I'm not saying it didn't, but it's
kind of like, you know, there's no
evidence that this that the Easter Bunny
doesn't exist either. But the irony here
is that the university has been so
one-sided on the uh Israel pro-Israel
side and so mean to the pro Palestinian
side that it's like that's what's so
weird. It's like so the university had
these protests. It the it was definitely
ground zero for the pro Gaza protests
and it inspired the rest. There were
this big encampment in the in the
central quad.
>> Um by all accounts mostly peaceful. Um
the university asserted that there was
some damage to Hamilton Hall when some
of the students broke in. That's a proud
tradition at Colombia. Breaking into
Hamilton Hall goes back to the
divevestature protest that I was part of
in the 80s um and also back to 1968.
It's just sort of like what what you do.
And um it's not that big a deal. $30,000
of damage. Basically, it came down to
some broken doors and uh some chairs and
some few windows got broken. They
shouldn't have done that. grant
>> and punishment. I think probably you
know maybe some some but anyway the
university came down like a ton of
bricks on the on the Palestinian
protesters. Jewish voice for peace and
other think about it Jewish voice for
peace and other pro Palestinian voices
the these these groups were banned by
the university administration. Students
were expelled. They were suspended. uh
gra graduated students had their their
had their diplomas freshly printed
revoked by the dozens. Um the there were
some a lot of incidents of violence on
the part of pro-Israeli
students who attack who attacked these
no there were there was no sanction
whatsoever against them. Um the
university president at the time
Claudine Gay uh was that no that was
Harvard I keep forgetting uh this was um
uh Mino Minous Minute that's right Min
>> that's right yes I remember
>> she went up there to Capitol Hill went
to the McCarthyite hearing where and she
was asked to fire a specific professor
for being pro too pro Palestinian she
said okay and she did nevertheless that
wasn't enough for them. She she they
ultimately she got pushed out. Um but
what's so baffling is what do they want
this university to do? Shoot these
students? They called in the police not
once but twice on them to brutalize them
and drag them out. They they they've
expelled them. They fired professors not
just once, several have been pushed out.
Free speech has been obliterated.
basically, you can't speak about you,
you know, the Palestinian cause on the
Columbia campus or you're going to be in
deep [__] Um, they they've even hired a
new 30 person goon squad to supplement
the normal campus security guards to
crack down on pro Palestinian
protesters. This was one of the
conditions of the Trump administration.
It's kind of like, why are you punishing
the university? The university is doing
your bidding. I don't that's the part
that's so mysterious to me.
>> Ted, last night I went to um
uh this annual uh banquet banquet party
um hosted by the ArabAmerican uh
foundation,
>> American Arab ArabAmerican Heritage
Foundation. It's uh in celebration of
ArabAmerican Heritage Month, which is
the month of April. And every year they
have they have this beautiful dinner and
speakers and then music and and folk
dancing. It's it's a wonderful event. So
this year it was scheduled to be held in
the auditorium at um Amazon
headquarters. Amazon 2 it's called here
in Arlington, Virginia.
>> Yeah. Isn't that where that that was
originally supposed to be located in
Queens and then AOC said no thank you.
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. And dog on AOC I wish it had
stayed in Queens. So um 48 hours before
the event
uh Amazon sent a letter to the uh
ArabAmerican Heritage Foundation
cancelling the event. You can't come
here. So when they called and said,
"What's up? We we booked this a year
ago. We paid for it. They said, "Nope.
No discussion, no explanation. You can't
come here."
So, in 48 hours, they had to find
another venue for 600 people and then
get all the word out that it's been
moved. They ended up moving it to the
banquet hall at the St. Peter and Paul
Antiochan Orthodox Cathedral in PTOAC,
Maryland, which was a magnificent venue.
But it's nowhere near a subway station
>> and so about a hundred students from DC
area universities who had bought tickets
could not go.
>> Um we had Rashidita TB um she came and
gave a talk and um Andy Shal who's this
beloved um uh restaurant tour here in in
the Washington area. He's got eight uh
restaurants called Bus Boys and Poets
which are progressive combination
bookstores. Yeah, it's a a wonderful
venue and Andy's just a wonderful human
being. He spoke and a couple of other
people spoke and there was a tribute to
Um Kum and then there was Syrian folk
dancing which was wonderful.
But the point is they were they were
cancelled and they were censored only
because they're Arab, not for any other
reason. Now this organization has been
around for 40 years
and it's made up of doctors and lawyers
and engineers and bankers and all
professional people all wearing suits.
They're all like, you know, from 40
upward in terms of age, and they were
just cancelled only because they're
Arabs.
There were a couple of brief mentions of
Gaza, but really the the event, the
night was about, you know, the
contributions to American culture that
that ArabAmericans have made. And, you
know, that that we've got to stick
together and work together. And I I'm I
say we I'm not an Arab, but I'm
certainly a supporter. And uh you know,
it was like any other black tie or
semi-lack Thai event that you might go
to. There was nothing controversial
about it in any way,
but they were cancelled just because
they're Arabs. Now, that was last night.
today, Columbia University. We're going
to see a lot more of this in the coming
weeks and months as the Trump
administration gains more solid footing
and comes to realize that there's no
significant push back.
>> That last part is the part that I wanted
to focus on, right? I mean,
this is a story we've seen before. I
mean, you know, like you, I I love
history and I'm a I'm a student of World
War II. My mother grew up in Nazi
occupied France and
>> wow
>> cowardice is the you know it's we saw
that back then although not nearly as
much as here um you know I think about
like you know when Hitler came to power
um he still had to contend with the
socialist and and communist parties
>> that's right
>> they had armed wings um they they they
marched in they were militant they had
street battles with the Nazis in the
streets um you know people would die um
you know obviously American politics
doesn't do that. Um I I'd say I would
argue for the better except maybe at
times like this. Um but we don't you
know we don't do that where it's like
I was also reading about another law
firm that just coughed up another
hundred million in free le, you know, uh
in proono work that Trump could pretty
much cash in like a like a coupon for
any of his him or any of his friends who
needs free legal work done. I mean, you
know, I mean, they basically just become
wholly owned subsidiaries of the Trump
administration.
What I mean,
was were was this like built is this
structural a structural problem in
American politics that we're not built
for resistance? I mean, is is that sort
of we just don't have
>> I think it is, Ted.
>> I think it is. And then, you know, when
when you've got, for example, uh
protesters exercising their rights to
free speech at Cop City outside of
Atlanta, being charged with, you know,
RICO charges, and facing sentences of of
life without parole, you've got a
problem. when you've got a couple of of
um uh eco activists in in Oklahoma City
going up to the um to the balcony of an
oil company's headquarters and throwing
glitter uh to protest uh you know shale
uh oil exploration and then being
charged with terrorism which carries a
life sentence. Yeah, we've got a serious
structural problem in this country. I
mean, so, so yeah. Well, that's the
oppressive side. That's the oppression
side, which is way over the top. And
then, but then, you know, okay, so last
Saturday there were
>> there were some beautiful rallies uh
organized by some Democrats.
>> The most beautiful rallies that have
ever been seen.
>> Gorgeous rallies. I mean, honestly, you
know, it's it's good for people to
protest. It's good for people to get to
know each other. Get get some fresh air.
get some, you know, get out there and
walk around, you know, maybe get your
10,000 steps in.
>> Yeah.
>> But, but really,
>> what good is it? I mean, there's, you
know, those same people today that, you
know, people are just like, oh man, they
even people who well informed, they're
going to hear this story and they're
going to be like, "Oh, that's weird."
And then it'll be like sort of like 1936
with the Nermberg laws. Wow, Jews aren't
allowed to go to the park anymore.
That's weird.
You just can't own radios anymore.
>> Yeah. And and then they say, "Well, it
doesn't it doesn't affect me, so that's
that's a they problem, not a me
problem."
>> And next thing you know,
>> society. That's right.
>> It's an everybody problem. I mean,
>> that's right.
I mean, you know, I used to I used to
fantasize about these scenarios and I
think maybe and I always thought the
only power that could ultimately bring a
US a fascist US to heal would be the EU
through armed intervention.
>> That's probably it.
>> But then you've got these elements of
fascism within the EU as well. Look at
Hungary and Poland and is it Slovenia?
France has an enormous far-right. Uh
>> the problem is in France in France the
the center left under Macron is acting
like fascists by not allowing free elect
the free election of a possible fascist.
>> That's right.
>> So
>> that's right.
>> You know you look back too at the at the
1930s and 40s United States. We had
farright elements that were involved in
politics. We had Huie Long for example
or Father Cochland and you and I have
talked about Father Cochland in the past
and they were allowed to just sort of
you know go on the air and hang
themselves with their own words.
>> There was no there was no move by the
Roosevelt White House or by the Supreme
Court or or the Justice Department to
try to silence these people. Why now?
Why do we try to silence alternative
voices now? Whether from the left or
from the right? Well, that's obviously
that shows the insecurity of the of the
powers of the ruling elites. They don't
think that they're worried, right? I
mean, they weren't I mean, they weren't
scared about I was the most reprinted
cartoonist in the LA in the New York
Times all throughout the 90s. I know
this because my editor, uh, John
Landman, he told me. And I said, "Oh,
how do you know that?" He said, "Oh,
well, we we we had we had we did an
internal audit and we counted all the
paychecks in an Excel spreadsheet and
you had the most of them, one paycheck
per per cartoon." I was like, "Oh,
that's nice." You know, like now there's
no way I can get into the New York
Times. I mean, maybe maybe if I'm
arrested, I'll make it into the New York
Times.
>> Um,
>> exactly right.
>> But I mean, it's it the the spaces have
shrunk. So, you know, I mean, if I'm the
if I'm a trustee of Columbia University,
I mean, a lot of those trustees are I
mean, it's they've had a conservative
pro. I mean, people think Columbia
University is like hot bed of
radicalism,
>> right? It's not.
>> The students are sort of some of them a
quarter, but like the but the
administration, they're they're
right-wing corporate corporatist conser
very a lot of them very Zionist. um and
they've been pressuring people. But if
you're a trustee of this university, if
you have the smallest IQ, you've got to
see that this is an existential threat
to your un to your university. I mean,
to the brand, like if you consent to
federal oversight already, college
recruiters are saying that people who
were accepted to Columbia University are
choosing to go to like smaller name
schools because they don't want to be
attached to the brand. Not because
they're worried about being viewed as
anti-Semitic, but because they just
think the place is falling apart. It's
becoming chaotic. I mean, you know,
normally when the Department of
Education subjects a school, like
typically it's an inner city school
that's in deep crisis, typically a high
school or a junior high school.
>> Yeah.
>> People graduate and they can't read,
they can't do basic math. That's right.
>> Right. Yeah. It's a it's a as Trump
would say, it's a [__] hole school. Yes.
>> So, CL Okay, so granted I haven't set I
haven't set foot in a classroom there
since 1991,
but Columbia University is not a [__]
hole school. Um, you know, it's it's one
of the premier educational institutions
in the world, a major research
university that just added a whole new
brand new science campus very recently.
Um they've got they've they they have to
resist. Yeah. But they won't they'll
probably say like, "Well, we want to
cooperate. We we we don't like
anti-semitism." I mean, it it's
literally like they're they declared war
on on like the on like the tooth fairy
or something. There's no anti-semitism
at these protests and these protests are
no more. There are no protests for there
to be anti-semitism that wasn't there.
And now you're now you're gonna go. So
why are what are you subjecting them
over to oversight for? Why?
>> Do you think that that's a question that
a federal judge is going to ask in the
coming days?
>> It has to be.
>> Well, I mean, assuming that there's a a
plaintiff in the form of Columbia
University's trustees, they have to they
have to fight this, right? Yes. And they
they may not. I'm not sure that they
will.
>> Oh my god. Can you imagine the precedent
that would set set if they didn't fight
it?
>> Well, that's
>> federal takeover.
>> That's one advantage of the Ivy League,
right? Because the the purpose of the
Ivy League is they all they do talk,
right? They have a I mean, it's not just
a it's not not just a it's a it's an
actual organization.
>> Interesting.
>> Interesting. I didn't know that.
>> Oh, yeah. It's not like just sort of
like a term like if it was like a term
for like you know elite schools then say
you know um Stanford would be in it but
it's not um so
>> Right. Right. That's a good point.
>> So like yeah know it's it's a it's an
organization they cooperate on things
like they try not to admit too many of
the same kids like oh here at Cornell
we're going to admit John but uh you
know maybe you pen you you don't admit
him like that. So, so they they they
they collude and um so they've got to be
on the phone. They've you know these
these presidents have to be the
presidents don't have any power though
as we've discovered recently. They used
to but um it's all the trustees and the
donors who are running everything. So
there's got to be a deep division there
between sort of the money people and the
uh and the former and the academic
oriented people. That's a that's a you
know what Mark's called like a division
in the ruling class. That's that's the
crisis that we're seeing and I I don't
know how it plays out
>> because I don't know what
>> worried
>> what I'm very worried. I could see them
not resisting. I could definitely see
them resisting lamely
>> like sort of filing you know a request
for an emergency injunction. But then I
could see the judge saying you know it's
the Department of Education they have
the right to do this.
But I mean, this is so shortsighted.
Don't you think that that that would
then open the door for a president, you
know, Pete Buddha Judge or whomever, to
to try to federalize Liberty University,
let's say.
>> Absolutely,
>> man. This is dangerous, dangerous
territory.
>> It's not good. And so I have to know, I
mean, I would go the, you know, like in
Star Trek when it's like when Kirk is
like, "Okay, you want to take over the
ship?
>> [__] off. I'm I'm self-destructing the
ship."
>> Yeah.
>> What if Columbus University did the
same? You want to take us over? Fine.
We'll shut down.
>> We'll just close the doors. We're out of
business.
>> Come and anyone want to buy some desks?
We're out. And I mean, I think it would
be so shocking it couldn't be ignored.
I think that's I think that's actually
the only proper answer.
>> Wow.
>> I mean it's like I mean I mean we don't
have federal control of universities in
this country.
>> No, we don't.
>> Ted, is this is this all about federal
funds?
>> Well, I mean it's about like you know
they Columbia University didn't even get
the $400 million back no matter even
though they sucked up to the
administration so badly. Um they they
just uh they just they they all they're
getting is a seat at the table which
apparently is not a good seat the way it
looks. From here it's looking like a
seat with like bird droppings on it way
up high behind the jumbotron with no
view at all. It's a seat you probably
don't even want. But yeah, it's about
the $400 million. And that's confusing
to me. Okay. So, as an alum, you know, I
know a lot of alums and a lot of them,
like my ex-girlfriend when I was in
college, she's rich as [__] She's the
head of aviation finance at one of the
three biggest mega banks in the world.
>> She she and her she and her husband
donate tens of millions of dollars to
>> Oh my god.
>> Barard. Now, I know that if she got a
call and and and and they and they and
they said, you know, the the Trump the
Trumpies have [__] us. We're out $400
million. Are you good for $20 million?
She and her husband would just write a
check. There's and she's one of tens of
thousands like that. What I'm trying to
get at is they probably could get the
500 the $400 million and more back just
by playing the victim. I mean, even I
I've never donated to Colombia. I I have
my issues with them. I'm much more
likely to donate money to my uh to my
son's college because they've been very
generous to to him and like I'm I'm an
only I'm an only I'm a single father.
I've struggled. They were really
understanding and cool, generous
financial aid package. But still, if
Colombia called me and said that, I'd be
like as undermployed as I am right now,
I'll cut you a check. I mean, so I think
there's they would have so much
sympathy. So the fact that they're and
and do they need it really? I mean,
right,
>> they have a 15 trillion dollar sorry 15
billion dollar um I'm I'm trying to make
sure I I get this right. Yeah, 15
billion dollar endowment. Now, they
can't spend that like a piggy bank.
Granted,
>> they have it. They can borrow against
it. There's all sorts of things they can
do. They get a revolving line of credit.
that $400 million wasn't going to all
come in at once, right?
>> So, you know what I mean? They're not
like that. They could hike tuition a
little bit. Um, there's things they
could do. They could they could cut the
budget, lay off some lay off some
adjunks, whatever. They could they could
cut the fat. There is fat there. So, why
are they not they're choosing not to
you? They're choosing to roll here. This
is because there's some of the trustees
really believe this anti-semitism
garbage.
>> That's sad actually.
That's sad.
>> You know, people and so many people
>> coming from inside the house. That's the
problem.
>> So many supporters of Israel in this
country have been successful at publicly
equating support for Palestinian human
rights as support for Hamas. It's
stunning to me.
>> I wrote a piece for the Wall Street
Journal, which they killed um but
whatever. I syndicated it. Um about
this, you know, the ADL um which is
basically in the hands of this maniac uh
uh pro-Israel, you know, the ADL was a
very respectable organization.
>> Oh yeah, it was.
>> And then this guy Jonathan Greenblat
took over. He's the CEO. And he and even
within the ADL, there's been a lot of of
anger. He he redefined all criticism of
Israel as anti-semitism. So if you look
at the stat he there's this stat that he
put out after October 7th 2023 where he
said like maybe about six months later
there's been a 700% increase in
anti-semit
anti-semitic incidents in the US over
the last year. Okay, that's, you know,
obviously that's catnip for editors and
it's a big story and it's shocking if
true. The problem is that starting in
Octo on October 7th, he redefined all
anytime someone called in and said, "Oh,
I saw a sign that said from the river to
the sea,
>> right?
>> That's an anti-semitic incident." All of
those have been counted that way.
There's no discreet and they were not
counted like that previously. Well, so
obviously there were there were so
obviously you're going to get that
spike. You know, if I start if I start
counting Blue Jays as terrorists in
spring,
>> well, you know, there's going to be a
spike in the spring because there's more
Blue Jays in the spring. Um, I mean,
that was just they just it was on
purpose. They and and you know, every
media organization stretched thin but
always lazy to begin with, they they're
just like they dutifully cut and pasted,
oh, the ADL, they're legit. And it's
like, but it's not like these numbers
are not real. I don't know if there's
been an increase in anti-semitism
overall. I would suspect probably, but
but it's not been 700%. And um you know,
we don't know what it is because
nobody's keeping reliable statistics.
The FBI's um hate crimes numbers take a
few years to come out, so we don't
really know.
>> So um that's much more reliable, but
that's only about violence. That's not
about like someone feeling sad because
they seem they don't like. So,
>> you know, it reminds me of when you're a
little kid and and you're like, "Mom, he
looked at me." That's what this is.
>> He hurt me.
>> Yeah.
>> It is like that. And like, so I mean,
and look, I think I've read the
arguments for why, you know, anti-semit
anti-ionism is anti-semitism. And look,
we can we we can and should have that
debate, but they don't want that debate.
What they want is to the Zionist side
wants to bully and get their side. They
don't want to can get buy in. They don't
want to convince anyone. They just want
to I mean, there's a there's an argument
to be made and they should probably make
it, but they're not. Uh or maybe they
feel like they made it and they lost,
but whatever. They're resorting to
bullying. And oddly, Trump with his
personal history of, you know, racism
and housing and everything is like
trying to present himself as the hero of
the Jewish people. It's all so bizarre.
>> It is. It's bizarre.
>> It's bizarre. And uh you know, I I'd
like to transition just a little bit if
we could. Yeah,
>> you know, you can't criticize Israel for
anything or you're labeled as being
anti-Semitic. But then the Israelis
attack these ambulance uh workers, EMTs,
they have lied about this attack at
literally every step of the way. The And
there's video of the attack,
>> right?
>> And it's the Israeli press that has been
breaking the story. and the story's
developments
>> Israeli the Israeli press does yman's
work um ha aretsz is it does
>> amazing
>> great work in a very insular society
very brave
>> um you know yeah
>> so there are these ambulances
>> driving down the road lights are on
they're marked with big red crosses on
the
>> there's video
>> yeah there's video and the Israelis stop
the ambulances is pull everybody out. It
was 14 or 15 people. Line them up and
execute them just like the Germans used
to do.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, as an aside,
>> one of my closest friends in the world
is also my my cousin Mark Kiryaku. Shout
out to Mark. And Mark's dad died
recently. He was in his early 90s, but
he was a he was shot by the Nazis and
and had a terrible scar on his on his
gut from when the a Nazi soldier shot
him.
Um
Mark is in the process right now of
translating letters that his dad wrote
during the period. And and just to read
about the Nazi occupation of Greece,
it's it's sickening. It's sickening to
me. Anyway, much of what
>> Yeah. Yeah, the brutality.
>> These letters describe the brutality.
>> It's what's happening in Gaza today.
You can't line ambulance workers up on
the side of the road and execute them.
That's what the Nazis did. And then not
only did they execute them, but they
then dug holes,
put the bodies in the holes.
>> That's what Nazis
>> and buried the ambulances so nobody
would know.
>> Yeah.
>> And word got out.
>> They were in a hurry. And um I mean it's
kind of I mean it's really sad but also
kind of awesome that uh they didn't
search the bodies because that's how we
have the video. One of the uh cell
phones belonging to one of the workers
was on the body and I guess it was night
and they were probably in a hurry uh to
cover things up.
>> Cover up their genocidal war crime.
>> Yes. And so but that's where we know we
have the where the the the Israelis
claimed there were the the vehicles
weren't marked that they had no
emergency lights on but the this person
the victim he was he was um you know
taping he he was videoing his the the
the convoy moving through Gaza and you
can very clearly see everything is not
the way the Israelis said and um and
that yeah and that's the evidence that
has proven I What do you think the
Israelis were? Why' they do it? I mean I
mean you mentioned the Nazis and I I I I
don't like to give credit to them, but I
don't really and I've read a lot of I
mean I've read if I had a if I had to
carry all the books about Nazism I've
read I couldn't. Um it's like I don't
remember them really targeting you know
health workers that kind of that's not
really their
thing.
>> That was not a thing for the Nazis. No,
you're right. So why what what's what
are the Israelis what are they trying to
accomplish here? They they just didn't
want them to respond. They could have
just blocked the road and detained them
and said get the [__] out of here or
shot you know.
>> Yeah what what what was this about?
>> And to murder them in cold blood like
that. And I'd like to know who who
sanctioned this. How how high up does
this go?
>> Um
>> right.
>> You know was this a governmental
decision? Was this a a a rogue military
unit,
>> right? Was this like a like what was his
name? Uh in uh Cali in
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's right.
>> The MI
massacre. Yeah. I don't know. It It's
clearly a war crime
>> and clearly don't want to account. They
don't want to hold anyone accountable
for it. I mean, so I I the conversation
one would hope that would be occurring
at inside the IDF would be sort of like
like an argument, right? Like where
there would at least be someone at the
table, some general hopefully who would
say, "Yeah, I know these are our guys
and you know they're fighting this these
horrible Arabs whom we hate, but still I
mean this is like we can't have this.
we've got a court marshal and it's like
no no everyone that'll discredit someone
else is saying that'll discredit the
entire war the world will hate us even
more um the Americans will get pissed
they'll be bad in the media you know I
mean but I don't even know if they're
having that kind of debate I mean you
you got to judge people by their actions
and their actions are that they're not
no they're not even throwing
>> even the little fish who usually get
court marshal in situations like this
nothing's
No, even the fall guy that you would
expect. That's right.
>> The stupid grunt.
>> That's right. I I just don't get this at
all. But there's also no outrage from
the American government. I I'm not aware
of any statement that has come from the
government. You know, we're seeing we're
seeing coverage in the Washington Post,
the New York Times, and elsewhere. Uh
but we're not we haven't heard Donald
Trump, for example, condemn uh this this
war crime. Not a word.
I don't get it.
I don't get it at all.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> I don't get it either. Um Well, what
about the I mean, and also I'm not
really seeing the American media hold
like, you know, during the Nixon years
whenever, you know, the like Ron Ziggler
was the press secretary for the
administration. He was so famous for
stonewalling that to Ziegler became a
verb in the American Heritage
dictionary. That's right. Um I think
it's been retired. But to Ziggler,
someone was just basically to keep
dodging and you know and not and just
not answering the question. But you know
the the the reporters used to like let's
say we were both in the White House
press corps and you asked a question
that like Ziegler refused to answer then
I would ask the same question even if I
had a different question because just we
to we'd all watch each other's back and
then if like they didn't answer it when
I asked it then it would go to Michelle
and Michelle would ask it and it would
just keep going like that right that
doesn't seem to have that same there's
no one really holding the feet the you
know the the the White House feet to the
fire they could go in there and every
single briefing just ask about this.
>> Yes.
>> But they don't. They don't.
>> Nobody will do that. Nobody.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Just awful. Shocking.
>> So,
>> and not shocking at the same time.
>> Well, yes. It's shocking that it's not
shocking. What are we gonna I mean,
what's
is there help? I mean, we have the ICC.
Um, we have the UN,
but basically the nothing will happen,
right?
>> No, nothing will happen. Nothing will
happen.
>> The the By the way, the audio is
absolutely chilling. Uh, where you can
the the cell phone, you can hear him at
one point saying, "Dad, please help me.
The Israelis have targeted us."
>> Oh my god.
>> And you know, and then you hear the the
the hail of bullets. They go on for five
minutes on the audio tape and then uh
and finally the phone goes dead.
>> Oh my god.
>> So So in other words, the the the phone
was probably in his pocket.
>> Yeah.
>> He hit record or he just left it
recording
>> and then while the whole thing unfolded
>> these really Yeah. I mean, what can I
even say? I mean,
>> there's nothing
>> there's there's got to be some kind of
justice and there likely won't be.
>> I know. I also it's I I and I can't even
imagine that this is being widely
reported in Israel because liberal
Israelis they read hets and they're
already against the war. Um and and but
there aren't and you know I mean that's
probably nowadays it used to be half and
half. Nowadays it's maybe one out of
four Israelis is liberal I would say. Um
the other three out of four they're
they're militant. They're so hardened
they just don't care. No, they don't
they don't care. You know, I the last
time I was in Israel, I asked an Israeli
reporter that I was visiting about that
and he attributed that to the gigantic
influx of um of migrants from Russia and
Ukraine that they were so conservative
to the point of irrationality
when they moved to Israel and they moved
in such numbers that they were
essentially able to take over the
electorate. and then by extension take
over the government.
That's amazing to me.
>> That's actually
in part. That's why there's no viable um
labor party anymore. There's socialism
is dead in in Israel. You know, when I
was in college,
so many of my my Jewish friends had
spent a summer at a kabutz, for example.
It was like this right of passage that
so many people did.
>> Yeah.
Nobody even talks about kabutzas
anymore.
>> It's all done. All done.
>> It's it's it's it's crazy. Um that's an
interesting theory. Demographics is
destiny. I think um we should talk a
little bit about this attorney uh in
Detroit.
>> Yeah. This is bad.
>> It's bad. Yeah. So, this guy, his name
is Amir Mak. He was uh traveling. He
went to the Dominican Republic uh for a
vac spring vacation with his wife and
two daughters.
>> Um seven years old. Um you know, family
man comes back from the DR. Um he's a
local attorney there in Detroit. He has
a one somewhat high-profile case. It's
this white college girl at University of
Michigan at Ann Arbor who was part of
the Gaza protests and he's defending her
against presumably whatever charges
she's facing um related to her role in
the protests. Um she he's pulled out of
he presents his passport. He's then
told, "Oh, you're going to have to go
with this special anti-terrorist task
squad." They pull him into uh a into a
detent into an interrogation room and
they inform they hand him a piece of
paper that says oh you know we well they
first they say we know you're a whole a
high-profile attorney. He's like no I'm
not I'm a local attorney. It's like well
we need to see your phone. We need we
need to go into your phone and get
everything. So So at first he says he he
refuses. He says there's privileged
information in there. Uh I'm not giving
you the the phone. And then they hand
him a piece of paper that says, "Oh, we
have the right to take your phone."
Which I I know that's well they say that
>> unfortunately.
>> Yeah, I think they basically do have
that right. Um but um he and you know
and it's important for people who are
watching this and wondering what they
should do to know that if your phone is
like password protected and like let's
say an iPhone fairly recent vintage
pretty much they're not going to be able
to get in there. So they can take it
>> but they can't get into it
>> and they can keep it. They can keep
Well, I guess they have to return it
eventually.
>> Eventually they But it I saw I saw a
report recently that they kept one guy's
phone. He refused to to open it up like
biometrically and they kept it for six
weeks.
>> Yeah. I'd be like, "Bye-bye phone."
>> Yep.
>> I mean, you know, I mean, these days
with the tariffs, the new one's going to
be three grand,
>> right?
>> But okay, fine. Maybe I'll get a flip
phone. Probably be good for me. Um, but
it probably be the best thing that ever
happened to me. Thank you, ICE, or in
this case, BCE order.
>> I'm gonna get one of these unplugged
phones that I mentioned in the last
podcast. They're a thousand bucks or 900
bucks. They're being marketed by Eric
Prince, who I loathe, whom I loathe. But
that's okay because they've got this
feature where if if the the feds demand
that you turn over your phone, you could
hit a button and it just zaps
everything.
>> I love that.
>> I'm doing it. So, I guess the whole
thing is like if you get detained while
you're being marched to the detention
center, power down your phone.
>> Yep.
>> And then you have some power because
otherwise they can hold the phone up to
your face and force you.
>> That's right.
>> Although you can always deactivate that.
You can you don't have to have that on.
You know,
>> people don't realize that. You can redo
it later. It'll take your you know,
probably be more accurate in case
change.
>> Right. Right. Exactly. So anyway, um so
it's good to good to be fair. Anyway,
they take this guy in, they detain him
for a couple of hours. Um and then say
finally he negotiates and says, "Okay,
how about if you just look at my
contacts?" And they say, "Okay." But
then they disappear with his phone. He
signs on a legal p paper. Okay, you have
the right to look at my contact. I'm not
going to tell you who they are. But they
take off with the phone. You know, they
took everything. You know, they drained
it. Of course they did. Of course they
did because the courts allow them to.
>> This has not yet gone to the Supreme
Court, but there have been two separate
circuit courts of appeals who have said
they can take your phone
>> or your laptop or both.
>> So the the final word isn't in, but as
the law stands right now,
>> that could happen to you anywhere within
a 100 miles of a of a border with the
US. Right. That's right. That's like 80%
of the country lives within the that
range, right? Because people live on
coasts.
>> Um, so like yeah, you could be you could
be driving on Interstate 95 in the
Northeast pulled over in like New Haven
by at a and be like, "What? What the
[__] is this New Haven?" It's like, "Is
these are these Connecticut State
Troopers?" No, this this could be BC
Border and Customs Enforcement. That's
right. And they could do this to you.
They could do that any and there have
been some cases like that.
>> Yes. where they've done these
checkpoints. So, I felt like the I felt
like the the the undertone when I saw
the the lawyer being interviewed was he
kind of knew he'd been had, you know, he
he had that sheepish
>> I got the same I got the same impression
>> like ah [__]
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I mean, look,
>> I think he was so taken by surprise that
he didn't have a minute to get his
thoughts together.
>> That's right. they take advantage of
that and you know but I think it's kind
of like you have to be like all right
you know I'm just not gonna give it to
you you know you got to go you have to
go with the kuryaku rule
>> I'm protected by I'm I'm represented by
council and I don't talk to cops cops
>> yeah that is
>> exactly right
>> that's going to be my rule whenever I
encounter those [__]
>> they eventually give 90 90% of the time
they just like ah [__] you and then they
they walk away.
>> I'm sure.
>> Yeah.
>> And you don't you don't have to be a
dick about it. You just, you know, say,
"Look, with all due respect, I'm
represented by council and I don't talk
to cops." And you just repeat it. It
might make them a little bit angry or
they'll pretend to be confused like,
"What's this crazy position this
person's taking?" And then they just
walk away.
>> Yeah.
>> Because they all think they're the good
guys.
>> But yeah, that's what I do. And it
works.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, okay, so we're seeing
a very rapid escalation here. Um,
lawyers are a protected have always been
a protected class in this country. They,
the administration lied and said, "We
didn't target him." It was like random.
>> That's clearly not true based on what
they told him. Um, they told him that he
had been targeted. So, that's not true.
And so, um, but obviously this is send a
message. You know, my friends say, "Oh,
you don't have to worry. They're just
going. they're only interested in these
Gaza protests and like uh and the people
related to them. And I'm like, okay, for
now,
>> but you can see the escalation, right? I
mean, we're in the Martin Neoler poem. I
just don't know what verse we're at, but
the question which verse I'm at,
>> but I'm in I'm in the poem
>> and I'm not at the end of the poem. I'm
closer to the, you know, I'm between the
end of the poem and where the poem is
right now.
>> That's right. So, so where where do we
you know I mean the question is where
what happens next? What you know
basically the administration is is
dipping their toe in to see how cold the
water is. So far it's been bath water.
So they can keep doing this and and they
will. I mean they they I mean they've
already gotten major law firms to take
the knee.
>> So now what I mean yeah what do you
think their next targets are going to
be? Journalists
>> probably. Yeah. I I would say definitely
actually not even probably journalists.
Journalists and lawyers if you can cow
the lawyers then you can cow anybody.
>> And you know how much journalism is
corporate now? I mean so few Americans
read alternative media.
>> So they have nothing to lose.
>> Yeah. And and let's face it, the
corporate attorney, the corporate
journalists, you know, it's not Jimmy
Breeslin anymore, right?
These aren't hardbitten working class
>> Jack Anderson. Yeah.
>> [__] you. I don't give a [__] about you.
They're not those people.
>> Nixon talked about assassinating Jack
Anderson.
>> That's how much he hated Jack Anderson's
muck raking, but we don't have
journalists like that anymore.
>> I I should take pride. Uh what was his
name? The um Oh my god. Allan Keys. Alan
Keys.
>> Oh, I remember Alen Keys. Yeah, he was a
nut. And he said he said that I should
be executed by the US government.
>> Oh, Senator Kit Bond said that I should
be hanged from a tree when I blew the
whistle on the
>> Yeah, he's torture program. Yeah, I I
wear that as a badge of honor.
>> Well, it's all good times until the, you
know, until until it's dawn.
>> Yeah.
>> But I mean, yeah. So, I mean, they're
going to So, I guess the question is, do
they go after I mean, like going with
the universities, they didn't go after,
you know, [__] Reed College. They're
going after, you know,
>> Colombia,
>> the big boys, Harvard, Colombia, Yale.
Um, with these law firms, they didn't go
after, you know, um,
>> no, they went after.
>> Yeah. They went after the biggest law
firms in the world,
>> right? So, I mean, it seems to me like,
you know, if you if you kill the king,
you own the castle. It's probably their
philosophy here. So, it seems like maybe
you and I are in a little bit less
danger than if you're say uh, you know,
an op-ed writer at the New York Times.
>> I have to agree.
Yeah, I think that's right. Hey, we're
running a little bit short on time, but
we've got to talk about talks day after
tomorrow in Muscat, Oman between the
United States and Iran. Now, Donald
Trump said that the talks were going to
be direct face-to-face talks. The
Iranians said that is not true. They're
going to be indirect talks. The US
delegation will be in one room. The
Iranian delegation will be in another
room. And the Omanis are going to be
shuttling between the two rooms. I
mentioned a couple of days ago, I'm 100%
sure that that the Iranians are are
right on this. There there won't be
direct talks, but talks of any kind are
good. Here's the problem.
>> The problem is the Iranians have a
demand and the demand is that they be
treated with respect.
And Donald Trump doesn't
>> talk to anyone with respect.
>> I know, right? And Donald Trump doesn't
treat anybody with respect. He's going
to go in there.
>> You're asking for some You're asking for
a product I don't have to sell. We're
all out.
>> He's bombastic. He's threatening. He's
bullying. And he said that if there are
if there is progress, then all is good.
If there's not progress, we're going to
bomb the [__] out of the Iranians. Or we
may bomb the [__] out of the Yemenes,
the Houthis, because they're generally
viewed as an Iranian cutout.
Where do you think this is going? Well,
or why not bomb Hezbollah again? Just
>> Oh, yeah. For what that's worth, if
there even is a Hezbollah that still
exists for any for all intents and
purposes. The reason I ask what you
think is going to be accomplished is
because we've not seen any indication in
any media that there's an agenda,
>> right?
>> So, what are we going to just stare at
each other?
>> That's a good question, right? It's sort
of like uh you know, it's like a date
where there's no there's no agenda. It's
>> it's like we're we're doing six minute
dating. We'll see if we like each cut of
each other's jib. Maybe we'll go home
together. Maybe not. Who know? Whatever.
It's it maybe there is a secret agenda.
Maybe maybe it's maybe it's just or
maybe it's to meet in order to to feel
each other out and just sort of see. I
mean, look, I'm sure the Iranians are
serious.
>> They're serious people and they're
always and you know, they're all and
their government's always serious
>> and they don't agree to talk slightly.
you know, they they held off the Biden
administration seemingly forever because
because they were burned by Trump won in
that he immediately withdrew from the
JCPOA and the and the Biden people
weren't offering, you know, automatic
re-entry into the JCPOA. I mean, the
problem with, you know, Trump and his
ADD presidency is that even if he even
if his heart's in the right place and
he's like, I really want to normalize
relations with Iran,
>> I mean, you know, he's dealing with
Russia. He's dealing he's trying to take
over university. He's got so much on his
plate. How does he focus? And and you
know, this Iran thing, there's a lot of
components, a lot of moving parts. And
Iran is as you know um you know the
ultimate country with a Byzantine
governmental structure with overlapping
structure several like four to five
discrete overlapping sort of all of them
and it's kind of hard you can't just
make a handshake deal like with the
dictator of Turk Menistan like if he
says it it's done. It's not like that
with the Iranians. Um so you know it's
not a dictatorship at all.
>> It's not. Hillary Clinton once famously
called it not a theocracy but a military
dictatorship that the IRGC, the Iran
Revolutionary Guard Corps, controls
every aspect of the Iranian government
and economy. And that is not true.
>> Not even a little bit true.
>> Not even a little bit.
>> Right.
>> It's a democracy whether we like it or
not.
>> It's disturbing that she Yeah. But I I
always like to say there's more
political cartoonists working at
newspapers in Tehran in their very
vibrant press than in the entire United
States of America. So um you know my
personal canary in the coal mine. Um
yeah. So it disturbs me that she was
ever Secretary of State, but I can say
that about so many of them recently. Um
yeah. What do you I mean I'd like
something good to come out of it. I
mean, should we read anything into is is
it related the fact that Russia and the
United States were able to have a
prisoner swap um recently? I mean, and
that apparently the talk is that the US
State Department and their Russian
counterparts are, you know, in the
foreign ministry are trying to uh
normalize relations with Russia. I'm I'm
not really sure normalization is really
the right word because we don't we never
sever diplomatic relations. Um and
normally when you normalize you, you
decever them. But this would be like I
guess about getting rid of getting rid
of sanctions and um you know that kind
of Oh, let me I think I need
>> Hey, sorry my my
>> bizarre
>> my computer went down just on its own. I
don't know what the happened.
>> That can happen. Okay, let me uh So,
it's really funny. There's like you're
in the little square now. Uh let's see
if I can figure fix this. All right.
You're Well, that's because I think
you're on the phone.
>> Yeah, I'm on a phone.
>> All right. There's nothing much I can
do. So you're skinny. Um it's like
remember in TV when they used to show
the 70 millimeter movies and they were
squished and everyone was like really
>> I do.
>> So
>> So anyway, um all right. So, I guess you
probably didn't hear what I was saying,
but um should we read I mean is is there
reason for optimism for for the US Iran
talks in the fact that Russia and the US
are apparently trying to normalize
relations uh these talks that resulted
in the recent recent prisoner swaps uh
basically and normalize relations I
don't think is the right word because um
you know we'd never sever severed them
but um
>> the Iranians did though
>> but I'm talking about Russia Russians.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. You're right.
Improving. Yeah.
>> I literally biked by the US consulate
today uh before the show and it's
>> Yeah. Yeah. The the the Russian embassy
here in Washington is up and running
every single day.
>> Yeah. There's some weird protesters out
in front. I didn't even know what they
were I zipped by. Um but anyway, the you
know, my um I guess the question is if
they're uh you know, if the Trump
administration's posture is basically
like generally speaking, we're we're
open for business. Marco Rubio. We'll
send little Marco over to talk to you
guys or his people.
>> Um I mean that's that seems to be where
they're at, right?
>> Yeah.
>> For the time.
>> I think it is. And you know, I have to
>> talk to anyone but Colombia but Columbia
University.
>> Yeah, that's right.
And I have to think that
Steve Woff is not stupid. That that
these talks, USRussia talks and US Iran
uh Iran talks are not exclusive of one
another. That there has to be a bigger
idea behind it. And so
>> what is that idea?
um that we really can
normalize
normalize relations with countries that
have been deemed to be enemy countries
even if that normalization is solely
related to trade. You know, we can end
the war between Russia and Ukraine. we
can lower the temperature in in US Iran
relations and everybody ends up being
happy or semihappy and maybe making some
money. And remember I said this again I
said this day before yesterday but I'll
say it again
>> and and Donald Trump is obsessed with
winning the Nobel Peace Prize.
>> The North Korea thing didn't work out
for him. You notice we're not even
pretending to try to talk to the North
Koreans
u despite the love letters from six
years ago.
>> So I'm I'm wondering if this is about
Donald Trump's legacy.
>> Yeah. Because if it's just like with
North Korea, there'd be something for
him to win Nobel wise if there were if
there were a crisis, but there isn't.
>> There isn't. No. So yeah, it's not just
about like making things good again.
It's got to be about fixing a war. I
would think that the Russian thing would
be lowhanging fruit for him.
>> Yeah, that's an easy one. I agree. I
agree. You just beat up on Zalinski
until he finally agrees.
>> He finally agrees to give up territory
in exchange for peace
>> and that's it.
>> Yeah.
>> Peace.
>> Yeah, I think that's it. But Iran, I
mean, that this could this could turn
into something big if Donald Trump is
actually serious about about pursuing
some sort of normalization.
>> Yeah. No, I mean, the Iran thing is long
overdue. The whole thing is stupid.
There's a lot of money to be made with
uh I mean, but apparently at the same
time, our relationship with China is
China is obviously [__]
>> It's bad. Yeah, it's bad.
>> The Chinese are really pissed.
>> Yeah.
>> This isn't posturing for them anymore.
>> No. No, definitely not.
>> And um you know, I think they feel
picked on. I mean, you know, I think
from their point of view,
>> singled out.
>> They haven't been militarily
expansionist. They have been playing by
all the rules. They've converted over to
capitalism just the way we always said
we wanted them to. We're probably
regretting that now. Uh we outsourced.
We They did what we wanted. We're like,
"Please take our dirty industries." Uh
which we don't want anymore. We're
de-industrializing. You take them. We're
going to outsource them. They were like,
"Okay, we did everything that was out."
And it's like they did everything that
was asked of them. They made some money
in the process and now that their
economies of all weak were beating up on
them. Mhm. Yes. Exactly right.
>> We're kicking them when they're down and
they're not liking it. I I wouldn't
either.
>> No, I wouldn't either. I wouldn't
either. But, you know, I wonder too if
the Chinese have calculated that that
they can handle this kind of conflict
longer than we can.
>> And I I went to the Treasury Department.
>> They only need to wait three years.
>> Yeah. Right. They would have to wait. I
don't think I don't think President
Vance would continue this policy.
>> I I don't either. I don't either. I
don't think anybody would.
>> No.
>> 125%
140% tariffs. Come on, man.
>> Absolutely [__] our economy if they
wanted to. They're the They're the
second or third largest uh holder of
government bonds, treasury bonds.
>> Yeah. And let's face it, we have the
trifecta of financial misery right now.
Never have I seen um you know I used to
work on Wall Street. Never have I seen
stock market go down at the same time as
treasury bonds and not exactly right at
the same time as the dollar collapsed.
>> Yes.
>> Those last two are where you go when
you're when equities go tits up.
>> That's right. That's exactly right.
>> So like and what's that about? It's
because every everyone thinks that we're
run by a madman
>> and so they're they're running away
screaming, you know. Um the the euro is
is doing surprisingly well despite all
of their problems over there.
the uh the Greek prime minister made a
statement yesterday that Donald Trump
seized on um the prime minister Kiryakos
Mitagis. He's a conservative um he's
been prime minister for a long time
since 2019
and uh he's in his second term right
now. Uh but he said he told uh Gati
Medini which is the New York Times
partner newspaper in Athens that this
isn't this situation with the tariffs.
This is not the crisis that many people
think it is. This was Donald Trump's
demand that everybody sit down,
literally everybody in the world sit
down and negotiate better trade deals.
He said, "Look, Donald Trump is right.
There has been a trade imbalance. Um, if
I were the American president, I
wouldn't want these imbalances, you
know, in favor of China or in favor of
South Korea or in favor of of Japan, for
example, or Germany. I would want
something that was fairer to my people.
And um and Trump said, "Well, I know
him. He's a very wise man and he's he's
right."
And so the Greeks are kind of perplexed
like, well, what do we what do we make
of this? Donald Trump just complimented
the prime minister. We're not sure we
like that.
But but you know, I think he's probably
right.
>> Well, I mean, that's an interesting
thing, right? It's sort of like I I
don't know if you had this feeling when
you first took economics, probably like
me in high school the first time. Uh,
forcibly definitely one of my favorite
subjects. So boring. Um and I was and I
was a very avid student. Um but like uh
when it you know the idea of the trade
deficit I was like
>> what is it like why is it a concern? I
understand why
>> why are we worried about this?
>> I understand why a national debt is a
problem but why do you care? I mean it's
like it's like I have a trade deficit in
my favor with the New York Times. They
buy my things sometimes. I never you
know I don't pay that much for the
paper. you know, are they being screwed?
I don't really think so. That's not
really Or, you know, Lasso, whose name I
mispronouncing and I know you pronounced
correctly.
>> Oh, Lutu.
>> Lutu.
>> Only because I knew a woman from Lutu.
That's the only reason I know how to
say.
>> You knew the woman from Lasu.
>> Yeah. The one woman.
>> So, so Lasutu is like, okay. So, they
have a We have It's not like the US
suffered from the fact that we bought
probably handiccrafts primarily from
there. I heard it was raw raw textiles.
>> Textiles, right? Yeah. So,
>> so we're buying a lot of textiles, raw
material, but that's all. Yeah. I mean,
they don't have the money to buy stuff
from us, so we can't sell them Lexuses
or whatever. Not that ours. So, like I
mean, it how does that harm us? So, it's
sort of like I mean, a trade imbalance,
I guess, writ large. If you're always
have a trade, you don't produce
anything. Yeah. then your GDP ultimately
is going to drop and and then it'll be a
problem. But sort of country by country,
it doesn't really matter, right? Is that
basically right?
>> Right. Yeah. Right. It doesn't really
matter. It doesn't
>> I don't even know if they should have
ever talked about it. It's one of those
metrics that it's sort of like, you
know, it's sort of like the cholesterol
numbers that they made too much of. It's
like actually cholesterol is not for
most people really a big deal. You can
have just eat some eggs if you can
afford them.
>> Yeah.
matter.
>> Right. Right. Exactly.
>> So, probably we should have just been
told like, "Don't worry about it."
>> Yeah. No,
>> it's no big deal.
>> So, we're going to be watching these all
these stories. We'll see. Um this is our
last show for this week. We'll do we'll
do one. We'll be back next week with a
couple of shows, I'm sure. Um we're
going to be doing uh we're going to look
at see what happened in Muscat over the
weekend with the Iranians. Um, that's a
process that's gonna be
>> It sure is.
>> It's going to be Yeah, it'll take some
time. Um,
>> the Russians might be a little faster
maybe. Um,
>> I suspect they will be. Yes.
>> And I I mean, when can we start seeing I
guess the next step will be sanctions
coming down, right?
>> Fingers crossed. Trump has twice spoken
about um reducing or eliminating
sanctions, but he always ties it to
progress uh at least uh with regard to a
ceasefire.
>> So, yeah,
>> the proposal is out there. It's on the
table,
>> right? And um I guess I don't know if
anyone's telling Putin like, you know,
I'm sure he has smart adviserss um that
are, you know, but someone I think he
has smarter adviserss than Trump does.
uh you know telling him like you know
the the American president's getting
impatient
>> and you have an opportunity here with
him that you might not have in the
future. If I were if I were the Russians
I I I'd jump on this.
>> Yeah.
>> You know
>> agreed.
>> So and you know Trump is battling the
neocons in his own party.
>> So he's he is I do give him credit for
that. And then um and then we'll see
what happens with this uh the Columbia
University thing that just started at
the beginning of the show. Um, and I
mean I'm just I'm gonna I'm I'm so
ashamed, you know. I'm Class of 91.
Roar, Lion, Roar. [__] those guys.
>> Yeah. You know,
>> it's just crazy.
>> Wow. All right.
>> I hope they don't buckle.
>> I think the only way out is is the
poison pill.
>> Yeah.
>> Like we'll close.
>> Mhm.
>> It's like you can't do that. watch us. I
mean, and a school can close and reopen.
Antioch College in my uh hometown of
Dayton, Ohio, just Yellow Springs, just
east of Dayton, they closed and reopened
>> and that's and you know, you can
>> I mean, you know,
>> okay, good. That's a strategy. Then
>> there would be an outcry massive maybe
just like, well, you know, we're going
to graduate our kids May 15th. That's
graduation day. Um, you know, if you're
if you don't have your diploma yet, you
might want to transfer somewhere else.
We're we're closing our doors. I mean,
the the political I mean, can you
imagine Mayor Adams here in New York?
What he they would be like, "What?" I
mean, New York Columbia University is
the second largest land owner in New
York City. I mean, it's a massive
contributor to the economy. I mean, you
can't do that.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I don't know. All right.
>> Good luck to them
>> with that. Uh I guess we will we will
consider everyone to have been
sufficiently deprogrammed for now.
>> Thanks for joining us everybody.
>> So much that you have to be deprogrammed
for. You have to come back.
>> Thanks everyone for uh checking us out.
Uh follow us on the socials and all
that. Uh please subscribe, please share,
please promote it. We're trying we're
independent. We're trying to make this
work financially. Um, you know, maybe
we'll have a big backer in the future,
but in the f but in the time for the
time being, we really need your help or
you know, we can't do it forever. So,
>> thanks everyone.
>> Indeed.
>> Thank you.
>> Bye.